[音乐响起--字幕精校中--By Persisan]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVID MALAN：好的，这是CS50。
DAVID MALAN: All right, so this is CS50.
这是第二周，我们将更深入地探讨
And this is week 2, wherein we're going to dive in a little more deeply
来看看这种新语言。
to see this new language.
我们还将回顾一些
And we're also going to take a look back at some
上周我们研究的一些概念，以便您可以更好地了解一些
of the concepts we looked at last week so that you can better understand some
C的功能和一些步骤
of the features of C and some of the steps
您一直在努力使您的代码正常工作。
you've been taking to make your code work.
因此，我们将从上周剥离一些抽象层
So we'll peel back some of the layers of abstraction from last week
以便您更好地了解实际情况
so that you better understand really what's going
在计算机机壳下面。
on underneath the hood of the computer.
因此，当然，上周，我们开始了也许是最经典的程序
So, of course, last week, we began with perhaps the most canonical of programs
在C语言中，您可以使用的最规范的程序
in C, the most canonical of programs you can
几乎可以用任何一种语言写
write pretty much in any language, which is that which
简单地说，“您好，世界”。
says, quite simply, "hello, world."
但是请记住，在实际运行该程序之前，
But recall that before actually running this program,
我们必须将其转换为计算机本身所说的语言，
we have to convert it into the language that computers themselves speak,
我们上周将其定义为二进制，0和1，否则称为
which we defined last week as binary, 0's and 1's, otherwise known
在这种情况下作为机器语言。
as machine language in this context.
所以我们必须以某种方式从源代码转变为某种东西
So we have to go somehow from this source code to something
更像是这样的机器代码，计算机实际上是0和1
more like this machine code, the 0's and 1's that the computer actually
了解。
understands.
现在，您可能还记得我们为此引入了一个命令。
Now, you may recall too that we introduced a command for this.
该命令称为make。
And that command was called make.
实际上，通过此命令“ make hello”，我们可以编写一个程序吗？
And literally via this command, "make hello," could we make a program
打个招呼。
called hello.
而且make有点花哨。
And make was a little fancy.
它假定如果您要编写一个名为hello的程序，
It assumed that if you want to make a program called hello,
它将查找名为hello.c的文件。
it would look for a file called hello.c.
这只是为您自动发生的。
That just happens automatically for you.
当然，最终结果是一个名为hello的附加文件。
And the end result, of course, was an additional file called hello
最终将其放入您的当前目录。
that would end up getting put into your current directory.
这样，您就可以执行./hello并随心所欲了。
So you could then do ./hello and be on your way.
但是事实证明，make实际上是自动化的
But it turns out that make is actually automating
为我们准备的一组更具体的步骤
a more specific set of steps for us that we'll
现在可以更仔细地查看。
see a little more closely now instead.
所以在屏幕上，这是完全相同的代码
So on the screen here is exactly the same code
我们上周写的，很简单地说，“你好，世界”。
that we wrote last week to say, quite simply, "hello, world."
回想一下，任何时候您运行“ make hello”或“ make mario”
And recall that any time you run "make hello" or "make mario"
或“赚钱”或“赚钱”中的任何问题
or "make cash" or "make credit," any of the problems
您可能最近才解决过，
that you might have tackled more recently,
您会在屏幕上看到一些神秘的输出。
you see some cryptic output on the screen.
希望没有红色或黄色错误消息，但即使一切正常，
Hopefully, no red or yellow error messages, but even when all is well,
您会看到白色的文字，表示一切都很好。
you see this white text which is indicative of all having been well.
上周，我们只是忽略了这一点，继续前进，并立即做了
And last week, we just kind of ignored this and moved on and immediately did
诸如./hello之类的东西。
something like ./hello.
但是今天，让我们更好地了解
But today, let's actually better understand
我们一直视而不见的是什么
what it is that we've been turning a blind eye to
这样，随着时间的流逝，每个星期都有越来越少的您不了解的东西
so that each week, as it passes, there's less and less that you don't understand
关于屏幕上显示的内容的全部信息。
the entirety of with respect to what's going on your screen.
再说一次，如果我在这里执行ls，我们不仅会看到hello.c，还会看到
So again, if I do ls here, we'll see not only hello.c, but also
我实际上是通过make创建的名为hello的可执行程序。
the executable program called hello that I actually created via make.
但是看看这个输出。
But look at this output.
这里提到了一些叫Clang的东西。
There's some mention of something called Clang here.
然后还有很多其他单词或神秘短语，在计算机中
And then there's a lot of other words or cryptic phrases, something in computer
在这里说，所有这些连字符都摆在前面。
speak here that has all of these hyphens in front of them.
事实证明，make在为我们做些什么
And it turns out that what make is doing for us
是自动执行更具体地称为clang的命令。
is it's automating execution of a command more specifically called clang.
Clang实际上是我们上周提到的编译器，一个编译器
Clang is actually the compiler that we alluded to last week, a compiler
是将源代码转换为机器代码的程序。
being a program that converts source code to machine code.
实际上，我们一直以来都在使用Clang。
We've actually been using Clang this whole time.
但是请注意，Clang需要更多的技巧。
But notice that Clang requires a bit more sophistication.
为了使用它，您必须进一步了解正在发生的事情。
You have to understand a bit more about what's going on in order to use it.
因此，让我继续删除名为hello的程序。
So let me go ahead and remove the program called hello.
我将使用上次简短看到的rm命令。
I'm going to use the rm command that we saw briefly last time.
我将通过点击y进行确认。
I'm going to confirm by hitting y.
而且，如果我现在再次输入ls，则hello.c是剩下的唯一文件。
And if I type ls again now, hello.c is the only file that remains.
好吧，暂时，让我取消使用make的能力。
Well, temporarily, let me take away the ability to use make.
现在让我们直接使用Clang。
And let's now use Clang directly.
Clang是CS50 IDE中安装的另一个程序。
Clang is another program installed in CS50 IDE.
这是一个非常流行的编译器，您可以将其下载到自己的Mac和PC上
It's a very popular compiler that you can download onto your own Macs and PCs
也一样
as well.
但是运行它有点不同。
But to run it is a little different.
我要继续说clang然后是文件名
I'm going to go ahead and say clang and then the name of the file
我要编译的东西，hello.c是这个。
that I want to compile, hello.c being this one.
我要继续并按Enter。
I'm going to go ahead and hit Enter.
现在看来，什么也没有发生。
And now nothing happens, seemingly.
但坦率地说，正如您可能已经收集到的一样，
But frankly, as you've probably gleaned already,
当似乎没有坏事发生时，那隐含地
when nothing bad seems to happen, that implicitly
往往意味着好事发生了。
tends to mean that something good happened.
您的程序已成功编译。
Your program compiled successfully.
但奇怪的是，如果我现在输入ls，您将看不到该程序，您好。
But curiously, if I type ls now, you don't see the program, hello.
您会看到这个奇怪的文件名，称为a.out。
You see this weird file name called a.out.
这实际上是历史遗留物。
And this is actually a historical remnant.
几年前，当人们使用编译器来编译代码时，
Years ago, when humans would use a compiler to compile their code,
每个程序都被赋予的默认文件名
the default file name that every program was given
是输出汇编输出。
was a.out for assembly output.
稍后再进行更多说明。
More on that in a moment.
但这对于程序来说是一个愚蠢的名字。
But this is kind of a stupid name for a program.
它根本不能描述其功能。
It's not at all descriptive of what it does.
因此事实证明，可以在命令行中配置Clang之类的程序。
So it turns out that programs like Clang can be configured at the command line.
命令行再次指的是闪烁的提示，您可以在其中
The command line, again, refers to the blinking prompt where you can
键入命令。
type commands.
所以的确，我现在要继续删除该文件-rm space a.out，
So indeed, I'm going to go ahead and remove this file now-- rm space a.out,
然后用y确认。
and then confirm with y.
现在，我回到了从hello.c开始的地方。
And now I'm back to where I began with just hello.c.
现在让我继续做一些不同的事情。
And let me go ahead now and do something a little different.
我将执行“ clang -o hello”，然后执行“ hello.c”一词。
I'm going to do "clang -o hello" and then the word "hello.c."
而我在这里所做的实际上是提供
And what I'm doing here is actually providing
我们将要开始调用命令行参数的内容。
what we're going to start calling a command-line argument.
因此，有时这些命令（例如make和rm）
So these commands, like make and rm, sometimes
可以自己全部运行。
can just be run all by themselves.
您只需键入一个单词，然后按Enter。
You just type a single word and hit Enter.
但是，我们经常看到他们在某种意义上接受了投入。
But very often, we've seen that they take inputs in some sense.
您键入“打个招呼”。
You type, "make hello."
您键入“ rm hello”。
You type, "rm hello."
在这种情况下，第二个单词“你好”
And the second word, "hello," in those cases,
是命令的一种输入，否则
is kind of an input to the command, otherwise
现在称为命令行参数。
now known as a command-line argument.
这是命令的输入。
It's an input to the command.
因此，在这里，我们有更多的命令行参数。
So here, we have more command-line arguments.
我们有“ clang”一词，这是我们将要运行的编译器“ -o”
We've got the word "clang," which is the compiler we're about to run, "-o,"
原来是“输出”的简写形式，
which it turns out is shorthand notation for "output,"
因此，请输出以下内容。
so please output the following.
您要输出什么？
What do you want to output?
好吧，下一个词是“你好”。
Well, the next word is "hello."
然后最后一个词是“ hello.c”。
And then the final word is "hello.c."
长话短说，这个命令现在更加冗长
So long story short, this command now more verbose
就是说，运行Clang，输出一个名为hello的文件，
though it is, is saying, run Clang, output a file called hello,
并将其作为输入文件hello.c。
and take as input file called hello.c.
因此，当我按Enter键后运行此命令时，似乎什么也没有发生。
So when I run this command after hitting Enter, nothing again seems to happen.
但是，如果键入ls，则看不到a.out的默认默认文件名。
But if I type ls, I don't see that stupid default file name of a.out.
现在我看到了文件名，你好。
Now I see the file name, hello.
因此，这就是Clang最终如何帮助我编译代码的方式。
So this is how ultimately Clang is helping me compile my code.
这是所有这些过程的自动化。
It's kind of automating all of those processes.
但是请记住，这不是我们上周运行的唯一程序类型
But recall that that's not the only type of program we ran last week
或上周写过。
or wrote last week.
我们宁愿采用这样的代码并开始对其进行增强
We rather took code like this and began to enhance it
还有一些额外的行。
with some additional lines.
因此，《 Hello，World》的第2版实际上涉及
So version 2 of Hello, World actually involved
使用CS50的get_string函数提示用户输入，
prompting the user for input using CS50's get_string function,
将输出存储在名为name的变量中。
storing the output in a variable called name.
但是请记住，我们还必须在文件顶部添加cs50.h。
But recall that we also had to add cs50.h at the top of the file.
因此，让我继续执行该操作。
So let me go ahead and do that.
我继续删除您好，因为这是旧版本。
Let me go ahead and remove hello because that's now the old version.
现在让我进入，开始在此处更新代码，并进入我的hello.c文件，
Let me go in now and start updating my code here and go into my hello.c file,
包括cs50.h，现在给我自己一个名为name的字符串，
include cs50.h, now get myself a string called name,
但是我们可以调用它，调用函数get_string，
but we could call it anything, call the function get_string,
并问“您叫什么名字”，问号末尾有一个空格
and ask, "What's your name," question mark with a space at the very end
只是造成差距。
just to create a gap.
然后在这里，而不是总是打印出“ hello world”，
And then down here, instead of printing out "hello, world" always,
让我打印出“你好，％s”，这是一个占位符，
let me print out "Hello, %s," which is a placeholder recall,
并输出此人的名字。
and output the person's name.
所以上周，我们编译该程序的方式仅仅是
So last week, the way we compiled this program was just
“打个招呼”，与现在没什么不同。
"make hello," no different from now.
但是这个星期，假设我要摆脱制造，
But this week, suppose I were to instead get rid of make, only
因为对于我来说，这对我来说是一种自动化的步骤
because it's sort of automating steps for me that I now
想更详细地了解。
want to understand in more detail.
我可以使用clang -o hello hello.c再次编译该程序，所以
I could compile this program again with clang -o hello hello.c, so just
重新应用了传递三个参数-o，hello的相同想法
a reapplication of that same idea of passing in three arguments, -o, hello,
和你好c。
and hello.c.
但是现在的收获是我实际上要去
But the catch now is that I'm actually going
查看这些红色错误消息之一。
to see one of these red error messages.
让我们考虑一下这实际上是在说什么。
And let's consider what this is actually saying.
这里仍然会有很多神秘的东西。
There's still going to be a bunch of cryptic stuff here.
但是请注意，像往常一样，我们将希望看到，
But notice, as always, we're going to see, hopefully,
有点熟悉的东西。
something that's a little familiar.
因此，“对get_string的未定义引用”。
So "undefined reference to get_string."
我还不知道什么是未定义的引用。
I don't yet know what an undefined reference is, necessarily.
我不知道链接程序命令是什么。
I don't know what a linker command is.
但是我至少认识到get_string发生了一些事情。
But I at least recognize there's something going on with get_string.
这是有原因的。
And there's a reason for this.
事实证明，使用库时，无论是CS50的库还是其他库
It turns out that when using a library, whether it's CS50's library or others'
同样，有时仅包含标头有时是不够的
as well, it's sometimes not sufficient only to include the header
文件放在您自己的代码顶部。
file at the top of your own code.
有时，您还必须告诉计算机
Sometimes, you additionally have to tell the computer
在哪里可以找到某人编写的要实现的0和1
where to find the 0's and 1's that someone has written to implement
像get_string这样的函数。
a function like get_string.
因此，头文件（如cs50.h）仅告诉编译器
So the header file, like cs50.h, just tells the compiler
该功能存在。
that the function exists.
但是直到现在，还有第二种机制，
But there's a second mechanism that, up until now,
对我们来说是自动化的，它告诉计算机在哪里
has been automated for us, that tells the computer where
查找实现该标头中的功能的实际0和1
to find the actual 0's and 1's that implements the functions in that header
文件。
file.
因此，我将需要实际添加另一个命令行
So with that said, I'm going to need to actually add another command line
该命令的参数。
argument to this command.
而且，除了执行clang -o hello hello.c之外，我还要
And instead of doing clang -o hello hello.c, I'm going to additionally,
并坦白地讲，在最后执行-lcs50
and admittedly, cryptically, do -lcs50 at the end
该命令，它很简单地指的是CS50库中的链接。
of this command, which quite simply refers to link in the CS50 library.
因此，“链接”是一个艺术术语，我们将了解它的含义。
So "link" is a term of art that we'll see what it
稍后会详细说明。
means in more detail in just a moment.
但是，这个额外的最终命令行参数告诉Clang，
But this additional final command-line argument tells Clang,
您已经知道像get_string这样的函数已经存在。
you already know that a function like get_string exists.
-lcs50表示在编译hello.c时
-lcs50 means when compiling hello.c, make
确保合并CS50库中的所有机器代码
sure to incorporate all of the machine code from CS50's library
进入您的程序。
into your program as well.
简而言之，当您使用某些库时，这是您必须要做的事情。
In short, it's something you have to do when you use certain libraries.
所以现在当我按Enter键时，一切似乎都很好，因为没有坏处被打印出来。
So now when I hit Enter, all seems to be well because nothing bad got printed.
如果输入ls，我会打招呼。
If I type ls, I see hello.
瞧，我可以做./你好，输入我的名字，大卫。
And voila, I can do ./hello, type in my name, David.
瞧，“你好，大卫。”
And voila, "hello, David."
那么为什么我们上周不做所有这一切呢？
So why didn't we do all of this last week?
坦率地说，我们没有取得任何根本进展。
And frankly, we've made no fundamental progress.
我们所做的只是揭示引擎盖下发生的事情。
All we've done is reveal what's going on underneath the hood.
但坦率地说，我会声明通过键入来编译代码
But I'll claim that, frankly, compiling your code by typing out
所有这些冗长的命令行参数都很快变得乏味。
all of these verbose command-line arguments just gets tedious quickly.
因此，计算机科学家和程序员，更具体地说，
And so computer scientists and programmers, more specifically,
倾向于自动化单调的步骤。
tend to automate monotonous steps.
因此，make最终会发生的事情是，所有这些
So what's happening ultimately with make is that all of this
正在为我们自动化。
is being automated for us.
因此，当您上周输入“打招呼”时，此后，
So when you typed "make hello" last week-- and henceforth,
欢迎您继续使用make，
you're welcome to continue using make as well--
请注意，它会生成此超长命令，其中一些命令
notice that it generates this extra long command, some of which
我们甚至都没有谈论过。
we haven't even talked about.
但是我一开始就承认叮当声。
But I do recognize clang at the beginning.
我认识hello.c请参阅此处。
I recognize hello.c see here.
我在这里认识到-lcs50。
I recognize -lcs50 here.
但是请注意，还有很多其他的东西，
But notice there's a bunch of other stuff as well,
不仅-o你好，而且-lm，其中
not only the -o hello, but also -lm, which
指的是数学库-lcrypt，它指的是
refers to a math library, -lcrypt, which refers
加密或加密库。
to a cryptography or an encryption library.
简而言之，我们的员工已经预先配置好了
In short, we the staff have preconfigured
确保只是在编译代码时
make to just make sure that when you compile your code,
所有必需的依赖项，库等，
all of the requisite dependencies, libraries, and so forth,
可供您使用而不必担心所有
are available to you without having to worry about all
这些命令行参数。
of these command-line arguments.
因此，从此以后，您当然可以编译您的代码
So henceforth, you can certainly compile your code
以这种方式直接使用Clang。
in this way using Clang directly.
或者您可以整周回到我们上周的位置
Or you can come back full circle to where we were last week
然后运行“打个招呼”。
and just run "make hello."
但是我们运行make hello是有原因的，因为执行了所有这些步骤
But there's a reason we run make hello, because executing all of those steps
手动操作往往会很快变得乏味。
manually tends to just get tedious quickly.
因此，的确如此，我们在这里所做的就是编译我们的代码。
And so indeed, what we've done here is compile our code.
编译意味着从源代码到机器代码。
And compiling means going from source code to machine code.
但是今天，我们发现确实还有更多
But today, we revealed that there's a little more, indeed,
在引擎盖下面，这种“联系”
going on underneath the hood, this "linking"
我所提到的以及其他几个步骤。
that I referred to and a couple of other steps as well.
因此，当您将代码从源代码编译为机器代码时，
So it turns out when you compile your code from source code to machine code,
最终还涉及一些其他步骤。
there's a few more steps that are ultimately involved.
当我们说“编译”时，我们实际上是指这四个步骤。
And when we say "compiling," we actually mean these four steps.
而且，我们将不讨论这些底层细节。
And we're not going to dwell on these kinds of low-level details.
但这只是启发性的
But it's perhaps enlightening just to see
简要了解从源代码开始时发生的情况
a brief tour of what's going on when you start with your source code
并最终尝试生成机器代码。
and end up trying to produce machine code.
因此，让我们考虑一下。
So let's consider this.
这是计算机正在执行的步骤1
This is step 1 that the computer is doing
在您编译代码时为您服务。
for you when you compile your code.
因此，第1步采用您自己的源代码
So step 1 takes your own source code that
看起来有点像这样。
looks a little something like this.
并从上到下，从左到右预处理您的代码。
And it preprocesses your code, top to bottom, left to right.
预处理代码本质上意味着
And to preprocess your code essentially means
它会寻找任何以井号符号开头的行，因此
that it looks for any lines that start with a hash symbol, so
#include cs50.h，＃include stdio.h。
#include cs50.h, #include stdio.h.
预处理步骤的作用就像是查找并替换。
And what the preprocessing step does is it's kind of like a find and replace.
它会注意到，哦，这是#include行。
It notices, oh, here's a #include line.
让我继续并将该文件cs50.h的内容复制到您自己的代码中。
Let me go ahead and copy the contents of that file, cs50.h, into your own code.
同样，当我遇到#include stdio.h时，请让我，
Similarly, when I encounter #include stdio.h, let me,
所谓的预处理器，打开该文件stdio.h，然后复制/粘贴
the so-called preprocessor, open that file, stdio.h, and copy/paste
该文件的内容，以便文件中的内容现在看起来更像这样。
the contents of that file so that what's in the file now looks more like this.
因此，这是自动发生的。
So this is happening automatically.
您不必手动执行此操作。
You never have to do this manually.
但是为什么要进行此预处理步骤？
But why is there this preprocessing step?
如果您还记得我们上周关于这些代码行的讨论，
If you recall our discussion last week of these lines of code that
倾向于放在文件的顶部，有人吗
tend to go at the top of your file, does anyone
知道预处理器对我有什么作用，为什么？
perceive what the preprocessor is doing for me and why?
为什么我要编写包含这些哈希符号的代码，例如#include cs50.h
Why do I write code that has these hash symbols, like #include cs50.h
和#include stdio.h，但是这个预处理器显然
and #include stdio.h, but this preprocessor apparently
自动将这些行替换为实际内容
is automatically replacing those lines with the actual contents
这些文件？
of those files?
这些黄色的东西在这里现在是什么？
What are these things here in yellow now?
是的，杰克，你怎么看？
Yeah, Jack, what do you think?
杰克：是否定义了供您在代码中使用的所有功能，
JACK: Is it defining all the functions for you to use in your code,
否则计算机将不知道该怎么办？
otherwise the computer wouldn't know what to do?
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的。
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
它定义了我代码中的所有功能
It's defining all of the functions in my code
使计算机知道该怎么办。
so that the computer knows what to do.
因为请记住，上周我们遇到了这种令人讨厌的错误，
Because remember that we ran into that sort of annoying bug last week,
因此我试图实现一个称为
whereby I was trying to implement a function called,
我认为，get_positive_int。
I think, get_positive_int.
回想一下，当我在文件底部实现该功能时，
And recall that when I implemented that function at the bottom of my file,
编译器有点笨，因为它没有意识到
the compiler was kind of dumb in that it didn't realize
之所以存在是因为已经实施了
that it existed because it was implemented
一直到我文件的底部。
all the way at the bottom of my file.
杰克的观点是，通过提及此功能，如果可以的话，一个提示，
So to Jack's point, by putting a mention of this function, a hint, if you will,
在最顶端，就像训练编译器一样
at the very top, it's like training the compiler
提前知道我不知道它是如何实现的，
to know in advance that I don't know how it's implemented yet,
但是我知道get_string将会存在。
but I know get_string is going to exist.
我还不知道它是如何实现的，但是我知道printf将会存在。
I don't know how it's implemented yet, but I know printf is going to exist.
因此，过去一周来我们一直包含的这些头文件
So these header files that we've been including for the past week essentially
包含所有原型
contain all of the prototypes--
也就是说，该库中存在的所有功能的所有提示-
that is, all of the hints for all the functions that exist in the library--
这样，您的代码在编译时就可以自上而下地了解
so that your code, when compiled, know from the top down
这些功能确实会存在。
that those functions will indeed exist.
因此预处理器可以为我们省去麻烦
So the preprocessor just saves us the trouble
如果需要，您必须复制并粘贴所有这些原型，
of having to copy and paste all of these prototypes, if you will,
所有这些提示，我们自己。
all of these hints, ourselves.
那么在那一步之后会发生什么呢？
So what happens after that step there?
接下来是什么？
What comes next?
好吧，可能还有其他头文件。
Well, there might very well be other header files.
这些文件中可能还有其他内容。
There might very well be other contents in those files.
但是现在，让我们假设只有原型。
But for now, let's just assume that only in there is the prototype.
所以现在编译实际上具有更精确的含义
So now compiling actually has a more precise meaning
我们今天要定义。
that we'll define today.
现在要编译您的代码意味着要使用此C代码
To compile your code now means to take this C code
并将其从此处的源代码转换为此处的另一种类型的源代码。
and to convert it from source code here to another type of source code here.
现在，这可能将成为我们所见过的最神秘的东西。
Now, this is probably going to be the most cryptic stuff we ever see.
这不是您需要了解的代码。
And this is not code you need to understand.
但是，屏幕上显示的是汇编代码。
But what's on the screen here is what's called assembly code.
长话短说，世界上有很多不同的计算机。
So long story short, there's a lot of different computers in the world.
具体来说，有很多不同的类型
And specifically, there's a lot of different types
中央处理单元（计算机的大脑）中的CPU数量。
of CPUs in the, Central Processing Units, the brains of a computer.
CPU可以理解某些命令。
And a CPU understands certain commands.
这些命令倾向于以这种语言来表达，即汇编代码。
And those commands tend to be expressed in this language called assembly code.
现在，老实说，我本人并不真正了解其中的大部分内容。
Now, I honestly don't really understand most of this myself.
自从我认真思考汇编代码以来，肯定已经有一段时间了。
It's certainly been a while even since I thought hard about assembly code.
但是，如果我在这里强调几个操作性人物，
But if I highlight a few operative characters here,
注意，这里提到了main，get_string，printf。
notice that there's mention of main, get_string, printf.
因此，这就像main的较低层实现，
So this is of like a lower-level implementation of main,
get_string和printf的代码，称为汇编语言。
of get_string and printf, in a different language called assembly.
因此，您编写了C代码。
So you write the C code.
但是，计算机会将其转换为对计算机更友好的语言
The computer, though, converts it to a more computer-friendly language
称为汇编代码。
called assembly code.
几十年前，人类写下了这些东西。
And decades ago, humans wrote this stuff.
人类编写了汇编代码。
Humans wrote assembly code.
但是如今，我们有了C。如今，我们拥有Python之类的语言-
But nowadays, we have C. And nowadays, we have languages like Python--
几周后还会有更多相关内容-更加人性化，
more on that in a few weeks-- that are just more user friendly,
即使过去一周感觉不是这样。
even if it didn't feel like that this past week.
汇编代码更接近于计算机本身的理解。
Assembly code is a little closer to what the computer itself understands.
但是还有另外一步。
But there's still another step.
有一个步骤称为组装。
There's this step called assembling.
再说一次，所有这些都在您简单运行时发生
And again, all of this is happening when you simply run
make，然后依次执行此命令clang。
make and, in turn, this command, clang.
汇编代码意味着获取该汇编代码并最终将其转换
To assemble your code means to take this assembly code and finally convert it
机器码，0和1。
to machine code, 0's and 1's.
因此，您编写了源代码。
So you write the source code.
编译器将其汇编为汇编代码。
The compiler assembles it into assembly code.
然后将其编译为汇编代码。
Then it compiles it into assembly code.
然后将其汇编为机器代码，直到我们得到实际的0和1。
Then it assembles it into machine code until we have the actual 0's and 1's.
但是实际上还有最后一步。
But there's actually one final step.
仅仅因为您编写的代码已转换为0和1，
Just because your code that you wrote has been converted into 0's and 1's, it
仍然需要与CS50编写的0和1关联
still needs to be linked in with the 0's and 1's that CS50 wrote
以及C语言的设计师几年前写的
and that the designers of the C language wrote years ago
在我们的案例中实施CS50库时，
when implementing the CS50 library in our case,
和printf函数（在这种情况下）。
and the printf function in their case.
所以这就是说，当您拥有这样的代码时，
So this is to say that when you have code like this that's not only
包括功能原型，例如get_string和printf
including the prototypes for functions like get_string and printf at the very
顶部，这些黄色的行是最终转换的行
top, these lines here in yellow are what are ultimately converted
分为0和1。
into 0's and 1's.
现在，我们必须将cs50.c中的0和1与0和1结合起来，
We now have to combine those 0's and 1's with the 0's and 1's from cs50.c,
这是工作人员前一段时间写的，甚至是一个文件
which the staff wrote some time ago, and even a file
叫做stdio.c，是C的设计师几年前写的。
called stdio.c, which the designers of C wrote years ago.
从技术上讲，它可能被称为不同的东西
And technically, it might be called something different
引擎盖下。
underneath the hood.
但是实际上有三个文件
But there's really three files that are getting
编写程序时结合在一起。
combined when you write your program.
我刚刚声称，第一个经过预处理和编译后
The first, I just claimed, once it's preprocessed and compiled
并组装起来，就变成了全0和1的形式。
and assembled, it's then in this form of all 0's and 1's.
在CS50 IDE的某个地方，有一堆
Somewhere on the CS50 IDE, there's a whole bunch
0和1代表cs50.c。
of 0's and 1's representing cs50.c.
在CS50 IDE中的某个地方，还有另一个文件
Somewhere in CS50 IDE, there's another file
代表stdio.c的0和1。
representing the 0's and 1's for stdio.c So this final fourth step, a.k.a.
链接，只需要我所有的0和1，所有CS50 0和1，全部
linking, just takes all of my 0's and 1's, all of CS50 0's and 1's, all
的printf的0和1，并将它们全部链接到一个大的blob中，
of printf's 0's and 1's, and links them all together into one big blob,
如果可以的话，那代表您的程序，您好。
if you will, that collectively represent your program, hello.
因此，我的天哪，这是一个非常艰巨的步骤。
So, my god, like, that's quite a mouthful and so many steps.
而且我所描述的步骤都与您实施的步骤没有任何关系
And none of the steps have I described are really germane to you implementing
马里奥的金字塔或现金或信贷，因为我们真正拥有的是
Mario's pyramid or cash or credit, because what we've really
过去一周一直在做的是全部四个
been doing over the past week is taking all four
这些相当低级的复杂概念，如果您愿意，
of these fairly low-level, sophisticated concepts and, if you will,
将它们抽象化，以便我们仅参考整个过程
abstracting them away so that we just refer to this whole process
作为编译。
as compiling.
因此，即使是，从技术上讲，
So we even though, yes, technically, compiling
只是四个步骤之一，通常是程序员
is just one of the four steps, what a programmer typically
在说编译是他们的时候，只是挥手致意，
does when saying compiling is they're, just with a wave of the hand,
引用所有这些较低级别的细节。
referring to all of those lower-level details.
但是事实是，引擎盖下发生了多个步骤。
But it is the case that there's multiple steps happening underneath the hood.
这就是make以及Clang在为您做的事情，
And this is what make and, in turn, Clang are doing for you,
自动执行从源代码到汇编代码的过程
automating this process of going from source code to assembly code
机器代码，然后将其与您所使用的任何库链接在一起
to machine code and then linking it all together with any libraries you
可能已经用过。
might have used.
因此，不再将正在发生的事情视为理所当然。
So no longer take for granted what's happening.
希望能给您带来更多的了解
Hopefully, that offers you a glimpse a bit more
编译自己的代码时实际发生的情况。
of what's actually happening when you compile your own code.
好吧，让我暂停一下，因为那是一个很大的嘴，
Well, let me pause there, because that's quite a mouthful,
看看是否有关于预处理，编译，
and see if there's any questions on preprocessing, compiling,
或组装或链接
or assembling, or linking, a.k.a.
编译。
compiling.
再说一次，我们不会停留在这个低水平上。
And again, we won't dwell at this low level.
如果我们可以同意的话，我们现在倾向于将所有内容抽象出来
We'll tend to now just abstract this all away if we can sort of agree
好的，是的，有那些步骤。
that, OK, yes, there's those steps.
但是真正重要的是整个过程，而不是细节。
But what's really important is the whole process, not the minutia.
索菲亚？
Sophia?
SOPHIA：我对第一步的问题是什么时候
SOPHIA: I had a question about with the first step, when
我们将替换顶部的所有信息，
we're replacing all the information at the top,
这些信息包含在IDE中吗？
is that information contained within the IDE?
还是我们在哪里-
Or where do we--
是否有文件保存在该IDE中的某个位置，例如
are there files saved somewhere in that IDE, like, where
从所有这些信息？
it's getting all this information from?
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，这是一个很好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, really good question.
这些文件都来自哪里？
Where are all these files coming from?
因此，是的，坦率地说，当您使用CS50 IDE时，
So yes, when you are using CS50 IDE, or frankly,
如果您使用的是自己的Mac或PC，
if you're using your own Mac or your own PC,
就像我们已经将编译器预装到Mac或PC上一样
and you have preinstalled a compiler into your Mac or PC just like we have
到CS50 IDE，您得到的是一堆.h文件
to CS50 IDE, what you get is a whole bunch of .h files somewhere
在计算机系统上。
on the computer system.
您可能还会有一堆.c文件或其编译版本，
You might also have a whole bunch of .c files, or compiled versions thereof,
系统上的某处。
somewhere on the system.
是的，当您下载并安装编译器时，
So yes, when you download and install a compiler,
您正在为您添加所有这些库。
you are getting all of these libraries added for you.
我们预先安装了一个名为CS50的库，
And we preinstalled an additional library called CS50's library that
此外，它还带有自己的.h文件和自己的机器代码。
additionally comes with its own .h file and its own machine code as well.
因此，所有这些文件都在CS50 IDE中的某个位置，
So all of those files are somewhere in CS50 IDE,
或等效地，如果您在本地工作，则在您自己的Mac或PC中。
or equivalently, in your own Mac or PC if you're working locally.
而在这种情况下，编译器Clang只是
And the compiler, Clang, in this case, just
知道如何找到它，因为安装中涉及的步骤之一
knows how to find that because one of the steps involved in installing
您自己的编译器要确保已将其配置为知道
your own compiler is making sure it's configured to know,
根据Sophia的问题，所有这些文件都在哪里。
per Sophia's question, where all those files are.
[？巴斯利？ ？]对不起，我很抱歉。
[? Basili? ?] I'm sorry if I'm mispronouncing it.
[？巴斯利？ ？]
[? Basili? ?]
[？ BASILI：吗？]因此，每当我们编译问候时，
[? BASILI: ?] So whenever we're compiling hello,
例如，编译器是否也在编译CS50？
for example, is the compiler also compiling, for example, CS50?
还是CS50在下面的某个机器代码中已经存在？
Or does CS50 already exist in machine code somewhere beneath?
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，这也是一个很好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, really good question too.
所以我有点避开了索菲亚问题的这一部分
So I was kind of skirting this part of Sophia's question
因为从技术上来讲，系统上可能未安装cs50.c。
because technically speaking, probably cs50.c is not installed on the system.
从技术上讲，stdio.c可能未安装在系统中。
And technically, stdio.c is probably not installed in the system.
为什么？
Why?
只是不需要。
It just doesn't need to be.
这将是一种效率低下的问题，也就是说，
It would be kind of inefficient, that is,
慢，如果每次您编译自己的程序，
slow, if every time you compiled your own program,
您还必须编译CS50的程序和stdio的程序，
you had to additionally compile CS50's program, and stdio's program,
等等。
and so forth.
因此，实际上有理由认为计算机通常会做什么
So it actually stands to reason that what computers typically do
他们为您预编译了所有这些库文件吗？
is they precompile all of those library files for you
以便更有效地将它们链接起来。
so that more efficiently they can just be linked in.
而且您不必保留预处理，编译，
And you don't have to keep preprocessing, compiling,
并汇编第三方代码。
and assembling third-party code.
您只需对自己的代码执行这些步骤，然后将所有内容链接在一起。
You only perform those steps on your own code and then link everything together.
的确如此。
And indeed, that's the case.
这一切都是提前完成的。
It's all done in advance.
虹膜，你的问题。
Iris, question from you.
爱丽丝：当我们用原型替换头文件时，
IRIS: When we replace the header files with prototypes,
我们是否仅将其替换为使用过的原型？
are we only replacing it with the prototypes that get used?
还是所有原型在技术上都得到了替代？
Or are all the prototypes technically substituted?
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，所以我有点扫兴了
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, so I was kind of sweeping that detail
在地毯下，用我的点，点，点。
under the rug with my dot, dot, dot.
这些文件中还有很多其他内容。
There's a whole lot of other stuff in those files.
您将获得这些文件的全部内容，
You're getting the entire contents of those files,
即使您唯一需要的就是原型。
even if the only thing you need is the prototype.
但是，这就是为什么我从技术上也提到这个事实，
But, and this is why I alluded to the fact too that technically,
可能没有stdio.c文件，因为那里
there probably isn't a stdio.c file, because there
里面会有很多东西。
would be so much stuff in it.
可能不仅只有一个包含所有内容的stdio.h文件。
There's probably not just one stdio.h file with everything in it.
可能还有些魔术般地包含了一些较小的文件。
There's probably some smaller files that get magically included as well.
但是，是的，这些文件中还有更多的代码行。
But yes, there are many more lines of code in those files.
但是没关系。
But that's OK.
您的编译器将仅使用其实际关心的行。
Your compiler is only going to use the lines that it actually cares about.
好问题。
Good question.
好吧，这么说，过去一周
All right, so with that said, this past week
无疑在某些方面有点令人沮丧
undoubtedly was a bit frustrating in some ways
因为您可能会遇到问题。
because you probably ran into problems.
您在自己的代码中遇到了错误和错误。
You ran into bugs, mistakes in your own code.
您可能看到一个或多个黄色或红色错误消息。
You probably saw one or more yellow or red error messages.
您可能只是为了使代码编译而苦苦挣扎。
And you might have struggled a little bit just to get your code to compile.
再说一次，这很正常。
And again, that's normal.
随着时间的流逝，这将消失。
That will go away over time.
但说实话，每当我写C时，假设有20％的时间，
But honestly, whenever I write C, let's say 20% of the time,
我自己的代码中仍然有一个编译错误，更不用说逻辑错误了。
I still have a compilation error, let alone logical errors, in my own code.
因此，这只是编写代码的经验的一部分。
So this is just part of the experience of writing code.
人类在各种形式的生活中都会犯错。
Humans make mistakes in all forms of life.
在代码的上下文中，这一点变得更加正确，在这种情况下，
And that's ever more true in the context of code, where again,
每两个星期的准确性和正确性都很重要。
per our first two weeks precision is important as is correctness.
有时很难同时实现这两个目标。
And it's hard sometimes to achieve both of those goals.
现在让我们考虑一下您可能会变得更多
So let's consider now how you might be more
有权调试您自己的代码-即在您自己的代码中查找问题。
empowered to debug your own code-- that is, find problems in your own code.
这个词实际上有一些词源。
And this word actually has some etymology.
这不一定是第一个错误。
This isn't necessarily the first bug.
但也许最著名的错误是这张照片
But perhaps the most famous bug is this one pictured
这是格雷斯·霍珀（Grace Hopper）的研究笔记本，
here from the research notebook of Grace Hopper,
一位著名的计算机科学家，他发现了
a famous computer scientist, who had discovered
哈佛Mark II电脑出现了一些问题，
that there were some problems with the Harvard Mark II computer, a very
如今名垂青史的计算机，实际上寿命将很快
famous computer nowadays that actually lives over soon
在校园里的新工程学校里
in the new engineering school on campus--
曾经住在科学中心。
used to live in the Science Center.
电脑出现问题。
The computer was having problems.
可以肯定的是，当工程师们浏览这个大型主机时
And sure enough, when the engineers took a look inside of this big mainframe
电脑，实际上有一个错误，如图所示
computer, there was actually a bug, pictured here
并贴在Grace Hopper的笔记本上。
and taped to Grace Hopper's notebook.
因此，这不一定是“错误”一词的首次使用，
So this wasn't necessarily the first use of the term "bug,"
但这是实际计算机中实际错误的一个非常著名的示例。
but it is a very well-known example of an actual bug in an actual computer.
如今，我们比喻多说了一个错误
Nowadays, we speak a little more metaphorically that a bug is just
一个程序中的一个错误。
a mistake in one program.
上周我们确实为您提供了一些工具，用于对错误进行故障排除。
And we did give you a few tools last week for troubleshooting bugs.
Help50使您可以更好地了解一些隐秘的错误消息。
Help50 allows you to better understand some of the cryptic error messages.
那是因为员工写了这个程序
And that's just because the staff wrote this program that
分析了您遇到的问题，我们尝试
analyzed the problem you're having, and we try
将其翻译成更人性化的语言。
to translate it to just more human-friendly speak.
我们看到了一个名为style50的工具，该工具可以帮助您避免准确性问题，
We saw a tool called style50, which helps you not with your correctness,
但只是出于代码美感的考虑，
but just with the aesthetics of your code,
帮助您更好地缩进事物并添加空白-
helping you better indent things and add white space-- that
是空白行或空格字符-因此用户更多了
is, blank lines or space characters-- so it's a little more user
对人类友好的阅读。
friendly to the human to read.
然后检查50，这当然是工作人员
And then check50, which, of course, the staff
请写信以便我们可以立即向您提供反馈
write so that we can give you immediate feedback on
根据问题集或实验室的代码是否正确
whether or not your code is correct per the problem sets or the lab
规格。
specification.
但是，您的工具箱中还应该包含其他一些工具。
But there's some other tools that you should have in your toolkit.
今天，我们会把这些给您。
And we'll give those to you today.
坦率地说，其中之一就是这个通用调试工具，
And one, frankly, is this universal debugging tool just called,
在C的上下文中，printf。
in the context of C, printf.
所以printf当然就是这个功能
So printf, of course, is just this function
将内容打印到屏幕上。
that prints stuff out onto the screen.
但这本身就是一个非常强大的工具
But that in and of itself is a wonderfully powerful tool
通过它您可以查找代码中的问题。
via which you can chase down problems in your code.
即使我们在几周后离开C并介绍
And even after we leave C in a few weeks and introduce
Python和其他语言，几乎所有的编程语言都可以
Python and other languages, almost every programming language out there
具有某种形式的printf。
has some form of printf.
也许叫做打印。
Maybe it's called print.
也许像在Scratch中那样被称为说，
Maybe it's called say, as it was in Scratch,
但具有向人类显示信息或向他人展示信息的能力。
but some ability to display information or present information to a human.
因此，让我们尝试使用这种基本形式，即打印f的概念，
So let's try to use this primitive, this notion of print f,
追查一个人的代码中的错误。
to chase down a bug in one's code.
因此，让我继续并故意编写一个有问题的程序。
So let me go ahead and deliberately write a buggy program.
我什至将文件称为buggy0.c。
I'm going to even call the file buggy0.c.
在此文件的顶部，我将继续执行#include stdio.h。
And at the top of this file, I'm going to go ahead and #include stdio.h.
不需要CS50库。
No need for the CS50 library for this one.
然后我要去做int main（void），这是我们上周看到的，
And then I'm going to do int main(void), which we saw last week,
我们今天将更详细地解释。
and we'll explain in more detail today.
然后我要给自己一个快速循环。
And then I'm going to give myself a quick loop.
我只想继续打印出来，哦，我不知道，就像，
I just want to go ahead and print out, oh, I don't know, like,
屏幕上有10个散列。
10 hashes on the screen.
所以我想打印一个垂直列，有点像
So I want to print a vertical column, kind of like one
超级马里奥兄弟（Super Mario Bros.）而非金字塔的屏幕截图中，
of those screenshots from Super Mario Bros., not a pyramid,
仅一列哈希，其中有10个。
just a single column of hashes, and 10 of them.
所以我要做类似int i = 0的事情，
So I'm going to do something like, int i = 0,
因为我觉得我在课堂上学到一般
because I feel like I learned in class that I generally
应该从0开始计数。
should start counting from 0.
然后，我将在此for循环中获取条件。
Then I'm going to have my condition in this for loop.
我想做10次。
And I want to do this 10 times.
我将执行小于或等于10的操作。
I'm going to do it less than or equal to 10.
然后我要继续增加我的体重，
Then I'm going to go ahead and have my increment,
可以很简单地表示为i ++。
which quite simply can be expressed as i++.
然后在这个循环中，我将继续进行打印
And then inside this loop, I'm just going to go ahead and print out
单个哈希值后接换行。
a single hash followed by a new line.
我要保存程序。
I'm going to save the program.
我将使用clang -o buggy0 buggy0--进行编译
I'm going to compile it with clang -o buggy0 buggy0--
我的意思是
I mean, no.
您不必以这种方式手动使用Clang。
You don't have to use Clang manually in this way.
只是将其抽象化，要简单得多-
It's a lot simpler to just abstract that away--
那不是命令
that's not a command--
将其抽象并运行，使buggy0。
to abstract that away and run make buggy0.
并且make将为您处理调用Clang的过程。
And make will take care of the process of invoking Clang for you.
我要继续运行它。
I'm going to go ahead and run it.
似乎编译成功，因此无需帮助50。
Seems to be compiling successfully, so no need for help50.
它的样式已经很不错了。
It's already pretty well styled.
实际上，如果我在此buggy0上运行style50，则还没有任何评论。
In fact, if I run style50 on this buggy0, I don't have any comments yet.
但是至少它看起来非常缩进。
But at least it looks very nicely indented.
所以我认为我可以。
So I think I'm OK with that.
但让我添加该评论并执行“打印10个散列”
But let me add that comment and do "Print 10 hashes" just
提醒自己我的目标。
to remind myself of my goal.
现在让我继续运行此文件，./buggy0，Enter。
And now let me go ahead and run this, ./buggy0, Enter.
我知道了，好的。
And I see, OK, good.
我认为是1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8、9、10、11。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, I think.
好的，这是一个愚蠢的错误。
All right, so it's a stupid bug.
也许它明显跳了出来给你们中的一些人。
And maybe it's jumped out obviously to some of you.
但也许对您的其他人来说有些微妙。
But maybe it's a little more subtle to others of you.
但是，您从哪里开始呢？
But where do you begin?
假设我要运行check50。
Suppose I were to run check50.
Check50表示，不，您打印了11个散列而不是10个。
And check50 were to say, nope, you printed out 11 hashes instead of 10.
但是我的代码对我来说似乎是正确的，至少乍一看。
But my code looks right to me, at least at first glance.
好吧，我该如何进行调试或解决呢？
Well, how can I go about debugging this or solving this?
好吧，printf再次是您的朋友。
Well, again, printf is your friend.
如果您想进一步了解自己的程序，
If you want to understand more about your own program,
使用printf将更多信息临时打印到屏幕上，
use printf to temporarily print more information to the screen,
不是我们想要的最终版本，不是您的TF想要看到的，
not that we want in the final version, not that your TF wants to see,
但是您，程序员，可以暂时看到。
but that you, the programmer, can temporarily see.
因此，在我打印此哈希之前，请先打印一些内容
So before I print this hash, let me print something
有点像这样的书呆子
a little more pedantic like this--
“我现在是％i反斜杠n。”
"i is now %i backslash n."
所以我从字面上想知道，仅就我自己的心理数学而言，我的价值是什么
So I literally want to know, just for my own mental math, what is the value of i
在此之前，我打印该哈希？
at this point before I print that hash?
现在，我将继续粘贴i的值。
Now I'm going to go ahead and paste in the value of i.
因此，我将％i用作占位符。
So I'm using %i as a placeholder.
我插入变量i的值。
I'm plugging in the value of the variable i.
我现在要保存我的代码。
I'm going to save my code now.
我将使用make buggy0重新编译它。
I'm going to recompile it with make buggy0.
我现在要重新运行它。
And I'm going to rerun it now.
让我继续增加窗口的大小
And let me go ahead and increase the size of my window
这样我们现在就可以专注于输出了。
just so we can focus now on the output.
我要继续./buggy0，回车。
And I'm going to go ahead and ./buggy0, Enter.
好的，所以现在我不仅看到我的输出，还看到了
OK, so now I see not only my output, but also
与该输出混合，如果需要的话，可以提供一些诊断输出，
commingled with that output, some diagnostic output, if you will,
一些调试输出。
some debugging output.
而且只是在学问上告诉我，“ i现在为0”，“ i现在为1”。
And it's just more pedantically telling me, "i is now 0," "i is now 1,"
“我现在是2，”点，点，点，“我现在是9”，“我现在是10”。
"i is now 2," dot, dot, dot, "i is now 9," "i is now 10."
好吧，我不讨厌我10岁。
OK, I don't hate the fact that i is 10.
但我不喜欢这样的事实：如果我从0开始并打印一个哈希，
But I'm not loving the fact that if I started at 0 and printed a hash,
而且我达到10并打印另一个哈希，很明显，
and I'm hitting 10 and printing another hash, well, obviously,
这是我的问题。
there's my problem.
所以可能还没有那么明显
So it might not have been all that much more obvious
而不是看代码本身。
than looking at the code itself.
但是通过使用printf，您可以更加清楚
But by using printf, you can just be a lot more clear
对自己来说，这是怎么回事。
to yourself what's going on.
因此，如果现在我看到，好吧，如果我从0开始，则必须上升到10。
So if now I see, OK, well, if I start at 0, I have to go up to 10.
我可以更改代码以使其小于10。
I could change my code to do this to be less than 10.
我可以不理会它，从1跳到10。
I could leave that alone and go from 1 through 10.
但同样，程序员的惯例是从0到10。
But again, programmer convention would be to go from 0 up to 10.
所以我认为我现在很好。
So I think I'm good now.
实际上，现在我将继续进行编译，生成buggy0。
And in fact, now I'll go ahead and recompile this, make buggy0.
让我继续并再次增加窗口的大小，以便
Let me go ahead and increase the size of the window again just so I can
暂时看到这个和./buggy0。
temporarily see this and ./buggy0.
好的，我现在从0、1、2，点，点，点开始。
OK, I start now at 0, 1, 2, dot, dot, dot.
现在我停在9点。
Now I stop at 9.
当然，这给了我10个哈希值。
And that, of course, gives me 10 hashes.
再说一遍，我在最终输出中不需要这个。
So again, I don't need this in the final output.
我要继续删除它。
And I'm to go ahead and delete this now.
它是临时输出。
It's temporary output.
但是再说一次，拥有这些直觉-如果您不完全
But again, having those instincts-- if you don't quite
了解为什么您的代码正在编译但无法正常运行，
understand why your code is compiling but not running properly,
而您想更好地了解计算机清楚地看到了什么，
and you want to better see what the computer is clearly seeing,
它的心灵之眼，使用printf只是告诉自己
its mind eye, use printf to just tell yourself
在代码中的任何位置，一个或多个变量的值是多少
what the value of some variable or variables are anywhere in your code
您想了解更多细节。
that you want to see a little more detail.
好吧，让我暂停片刻
All right, let me pause for just a moment
看看仅使用printf的这项技术是否有任何疑问
to see if there's any questions on this technique of just using printf
开始调试代码并查看变量的值
to begin to debug your code and to see the values of variables
在某种程度上更明确。
in a way that's a little more explicit.
不？
No?
好的。
All right.
好吧，让我提出一个更强大的工具
Well, let me propose an even more powerful tool that admittedly
需要一点时间来适应。
takes a little getting used to.
但这只是其中的一课，
But this is kind of one of those lessons,
如果可以的话，请相信我，如果您再花几分钟的时间，甚至
trust me, if you will, that if you spend a few more minutes, maybe even
这个星期一个小时左右，学习以下工具，
an hour or so this week, learning the following tool,
您将节省自己的时间，甚至可以节省多个时间
you will save yourself hours, plural, maybe even
在接下来的几个星期中要花费数十个小时
tens of hours over the course of the next many weeks
因为此工具可以帮助您真正了解代码内部的情况。
because this tool can help you truly see what's going on inside of your code.
因此，我们今天将要添加到列表中的该工具称为debug50。
So this tool we're going to add to the list today is called debug50.
虽然这确实以50结尾，这意味着它是CS50工具，
And while this one does end with 50, implying that it's a CS50 tool,
它建立在称为GDB（即GNU）的行业标准工具之上
it's built on top of an industry standard tool known as GDB, the GNU
DeBugger，这是许多不同计算机系统的标准工具
DeBugger, that's a standard tool that a lot of different computer systems
用于为您提供以更复杂的方式调试代码的功能
use to provide you with the ability to debug your code in a more sophisticated
不仅仅是单独使用printf。
way than just using printf alone.
因此，让我们继续执行此操作。
So let's go ahead and do this.
让我回到该程序的错误版本
Let me go back to the buggy version of this program
回想一下，这让我从0跳到10，这是太多步骤了。
which, recall, had me going from 0 through 10, which was too many steps.
刚才，我建议我们只使用printf来查看i的值。
A moment ago, I proposed that we just use printf to see the value of i.
但坦率地说，我们的程序越大，越复杂
But frankly, the bigger our programs get, the more complicated
他们得到了，他们需要在屏幕上获得更多的输出。
they get, the more output they need to have on the screen.
很快就会变得非常混乱
It's just going to get very messy quickly
如果您要打印出不应该存在的内容，对吗？
if you're printing out stuff that shouldn't be there, right?
回想一下马里奥。
Think back to Mario.
马里奥的金字塔就是这种图形输出。
Mario's pyramid is this sort of graphical output.
而且它很快就会变得丑陋，并且很难理解您的金字塔
And it would very quickly get ugly and kind of hard to understand your pyramid
如果您要将金字塔与printf的实际文本输出混为一谈
if you're comingling that pyramid with actual textual output from printf
也一样
as well.
因此，debug50，然后是任何语言的调试器，
So debug50, and in turn a debugger in any language,
是一个允许您逐步运行代码的工具
is a tool that allows you to run your code step by step
并查看计算机内部的变量和其他内存的内部
and look inside of variables and other pieces of memory inside of the computer
在您的程序运行时。
while your program is running.
现在，几乎我们运行的每个程序都需要一秒钟的时间才能运行。
Right now, pretty much every program we run takes a split second to run.
那对我（人类）来说太快了，我无法全神贯注
That's way too fast for me, the human, to wrap my mind
围绕逐步进行的事情。
around what's going on step by step.
调试器可让您运行程序，
A debugger allows you to run your program,
但要一步一步一步，所以您可以看到发生了什么。
but much more slowly, step by step, so you can see what's going on.
所以我现在要继续并运行debug50 ./hello。
So I'm going to go ahead now and run debug50 ./hello.
不，抱歉，debug50 ./buggy0。
No, sorry, debug50 ./buggy0.
所以我先写一个debug50，一个空格，然后
So I write debug50 first, a space, and then
点斜杠和该程序的名称
dot slash and the name of the program that's
已经编译，我想调试。
already compiled that I want to debug.
因此，我将继续并按Enter。
So I'm going to go ahead and hit Enter.
并请注意，哦，这很聪明。
And notice that, oh, it was smart.
它注意到我更改了代码。
It noticed that I changed my code.
我刚才做了。
And I did a moment ago.
我将其还原为越野车版本。
I reverted it back to the buggy version.
因此，让我解决此问题-制作buggy0。
So let me fix this-- make buggy0.
好的，没有错误。
All right, no errors.
现在让我继续并再次运行debug50。
Now let me go ahead and run debug50 again.
而且，如果您还没有注意到这一点，有时我似乎会快速输入疯子。
And if you haven't noticed this already, sometimes I seem to type crazy fast.
我不一定要打字那么快。
I'm not necessarily typing that fast.
我正在回顾CS50 IDE的历史。
I'm going through my history in CS50 IDE.
使用向上和向下箭头键，可以向后滚动
Using your arrow keys, Up and Down, you can scroll back
及时处理您过去几分钟输入的所有命令
in time for all of the commands you've typed over the past few minutes
甚至数小时甚至数天。
or hours or even days.
这将开始为您节省击键次数。
And this will just start to save you keystrokes.
所以我将继续前进。
So I'm going to go ahead and hit Up.
现在，我不必再打整个命令。
And now I don't have to bother typing this whole command again.
这是节省时间的有用方法。
It's a helpful way to just save time.
我现在要进入并按Enter。
I'm going to go head in now and hit Enter.
现在请注意此错误消息-
And now notice this error message--
我没有设置任何断点。
I haven't set any breakpoints.
“通过单击行号左侧的至少一个断点，然后
"Set at least one breakpoint by clicking to the left of a line number and then
重新运行debug50！”
re-run debug50!"
好吧，这是怎么回事？
Well, what's going on here?
好吧，debug50需要我提前告诉计算机在哪一行
Well, debug50 needs me to tell the computer in advance at what line
我想闯入一步一步来。
I want to break into and step through step by step.
所以，我可以做到。
So, I can do that.
正如我所说的，我将在这里转到文件的一侧。
I'm going to go over to the side of the file here, as it says.
你知道吗？
And you know what?
第一个有趣的行是这里的第6行。
The first interesting line is this one here, line 6.
因此，我点击了屏幕左侧的所谓的装订线，
So I clicked in the so-called gutter, the left-hand side of the screen,
在第6行。
on line 6.
并自动在该处放置一个红点，例如停车标志。
And that automatically put a red dot there, like a stop sign.
现在，最后一次，我要继续运行debug50 ./buggy0并点击
Now, one last time, I'm going to go ahead and run debug50 ./buggy0 and hit
进入。
Enter.
现在请注意，该新面板在右侧打开。
And now notice this fancy new panel opens up on the right-hand side.
首先，它看起来有些神秘。
And it's going to look a little cryptic at first.
但是，让我们考虑一下屏幕上发生了什么变化。
But let's consider what has changed on the screen.
现在注意，以这种黄色以外的颜色突出显示的是第6行。
Notice now that highlighted in this sort of off-yellow color is line 6.
那是因为debug50所做的是正在运行我的程序，
And that's because what debug50 is doing is it's running my program,
但它已在第6行暂停了执行。
but it has paused execution on line 6.
这样就完成了从第1行到第5行的所有操作
So it's done everything from line 1 through 5,
但现在它在6号线上等着我。
but now it's waiting for me on line 6.
这里有趣的是-让
And what's interesting over here is this-- let
我在这里放大此窗口。
me zoom in on this window over here.
诚然，这里发生了很多事情。
And there's a lot going on here, admittedly.
但是，让我们暂时只关注Watch Expressions，而不是Call Stack，
But let's focus for just a moment not on Watch Expressions, not on Call Stack,
但仅适用于局部变量。
but only on Local Variables.
注意，我有一个名为i的变量，其初始值为0，
And notice, I have a variable called i whose initial value is 0,
它是int类型的。
and it's of type int.
现在，这很有趣，因为请注意我可以通过这些图标执行的操作
Now, this is kind of interesting because watch what I can do via these icons
上面这儿。
up here.
我可以单击“跳过”行，然后开始逐步执行我的代码行
I can click on this Step Over line and start to step through my code line
按行。
by line.
因此，让我继续进行缩小。
So let me go ahead and zoom out.
让我继续，然后单击“跳过”。
Let me go ahead and click Step Over.
并观察黄色突出显示会发生什么。
And watch what happens to the yellow highlighting.
它向下移动到下一行。
It moves down to the next line.
但是请注意，如果我在此处再次放大，则i的值没有改变。
But notice, if I zoom in again up here, the value of i has not changed.
现在让我继续前进。
Now let me go ahead and step over again.
并注意黄色突出显示加倍。
And notice the yellow highlighting doubles back.
这是有道理的，因为我处于循环中。
That makes sense because I'm in a loop.
因此它应该来回走动。
So it should be going back and forth, back and forth.
但是接下来会发生什么呢？
But what next happens in a loop?
每当您回到循环的开始，
Every time you go back to the beginning of the loop,
请记住，您的增量发生了，例如i ++。
remember that your incrementation happens, like the i++.
因此，现在在右上角仔细观看，
So watch now closely in the top right-hand corner,
当我现在跳过时，请注意调试器中i的值
when I Step Over now, notice that the value of i in my debugger
刚刚更改为1。
has just been changed to 1.
因此，我不必使用printf。
So I didn't have to use printf.
我不必弄乱屏幕的输出。
I didn't have to mess up the output of my screen.
我可以在这个GUI中看到这个图形用户
I can literally see in this GUI, this Graphical User
在右侧的界面上，i的值是多少。
Interface on the right-hand side, what the value of i is.
现在，如果我开始快速点击一下，
Now if I just start clicking a little more quickly,
请注意，在循环执行一次又一次时，i的值
notice that as the loop is executing, again and again, the value of i
不断更新。
keeps getting updated.
你知道吗？
And you know what?
我敢打赌，即使我们从0开始，如果我做了足够多次，
I bet, even though we started at 0, if I do this enough times,
我将看到该值现在是10，因此
I will see that the value is 10 now, thereby
在底部再给我一个printf，从而解释了11个哈希值
giving me another printf at the bottom, thereby explaining the 11 total hashes
我看到的。
that I saw.
因此，我在这里没有任何新信息。
So I haven't gotten any new information here.
但是请注意，我已经获得了无动于衷的信息。
But notice I've gotten unperturbed information.
我并没有杂乱无章地打印出所有这些printf语句
I've not messily and sloppily printed out all of these printf statements
屏幕上。
on the screen.
我只是有条不紊地看着
I'm just kind of watching a little more methodically
右上角的变量状态发生了什么。
what's happening to the state of my variable over on the top right there.
好吧，我也要在这里暂停一下，看看对什么有任何疑问
All right, let me pause here too to see if there's any questions on what
该调试器可以。
this debugger does.
同样，您可以编译代码。
Again, you compile your code.
您可以在代码上运行debug50，但只有在设置了所谓的断点之后，
You run debug50 on your code, but only after setting a so-called breakpoint,
您在哪里预先决定要在哪里暂停执行代码。
where you decide in advance where do you want to pause execution of your code.
即使我在程序开始时就做了很多，
Even though here I did it pretty much at the beginning of my program,
对于更大的程序，它将是超级
for bigger programs, it's going to be super
方便在代码中途暂停
convenient to be able to pause halfway through your code
而不必经历整个过程。
and not have to go through the whole thing.
彼得，问题。
Peter, question.
PETER：关于调试器，Step Over有什么区别
PETER: About the debugger, what's the difference between Step Over
然后进入并退出，并且-
and Step Into and Step Out and--
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：很好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
让我回到片刻，
Let me come back to that in just a moment,
因为我们将再做一个示例，其中实际上是“跳入”和“跳出”
because we'll do one other example where Step Into and Step Out actually
是紧密联系的。
are germane.
但是在我们这样做之前。
But before we do that.
在我们了解Step Into和Step之前，还有其他关于debug50的问题。
Any other questions about debug50 before we reveal what Step Into and Step
为我们做的也结束了吗？
Over do for us as well?
哦那好吧。
Oh, all right.
好吧，让我们来看看彼得的问题。
Well, let's take Peter's question right there.
现在让我继续前进，退出调试器。
Let me go ahead now and get out of the debugger.
老实说，我看不出一种明显的出路
And honestly, I don't see an obvious way to get out
目前的调试器。
of the debugger at the moment.
但是Control-C也是您今天的新朋友。
But Control-C is your new friend today too.
几乎在您失去程序控制权的任何时候
Pretty much any time you lose control of a program
因为调试器正在运行，您对此失去了兴趣。
because the debugger's running, and you've lost interest in it.
也许是上周，您编写了一个程序
Or maybe last week, you wrote a program that
有一个无限循环，不断循环，
has an infinite loop that just keeps going and going and going,
Control-C将退出该程序。
Control-C will break out of that program.
但是，让我们现在快速编写另一个程序，这次，
But let's now write quickly another program that, this time,
有第二个功能。
has a second function.
今天，我们将看到调试器的另一功能。
And we'll see one other feature of the debugger today.
我将继续创建一个新文件，现在称为buggy1.c。
I'm going to go ahead and create a new file now called buggy1.c.
同样，这将是故意存在的缺陷。
Again, it's going to be deliberately flawed.
但这次我将首先进行#includecs50.h。
But I'm going to first going to go ahead and #include cs50.h this time.
我要去#include stdio.h。
And I'm going to #include stdio.h.
我要做int main void。
I'm going to do int main void.
我将继续进行以下操作-给我自己
And I'm going to go ahead and do the following-- give myself
称为i的变量。
a variable called i.
我将尝试通过调用来获取负整数
And I'm going to try to get a negative int by calling
一个名为get_negative_int的函数。
a function called get_negative_int.
然后，很简单，我将打印出该值“％i反斜杠n”，
And then quite simply, I'm going to print out this value, "%i backslash n",
我，分号。
i, semicolon.
现在，只有一个问题-
Now, there's only one problem--
get_negative_int不存在。
get_negative_int does not exist.
因此，就像上周我们在其中实现get_positive_int一样，
So like last week, where we implemented get_positive_int,
这周，我将实现get_negative_int。
this week, I'll implement get_negative_int.
但是我一开始会做的不正确。
But I'm going to do it incorrectly at first.
现在，顾名思义，get_negative_int需要返回一个整数。
Now, get_negative_int, as the name implies, needs to return an integer.
即使我们在上周只花了很短的时间，
And even though we only spent brief time on this last week,
回想一下，您可以指定函数的输出，
recall that you can specify the output of a function,
您编写的自定义函数，即所谓的return
a custom function that you wrote, by putting its so-called return
值首先在此行。
value first on this line.
然后，您可以输入函数名称，例如get_negative_int，
And then you can put the name of the function, like get_negative_int,
然后在括号中，您可以将输入内容放到函数中。
and then in parentheses, you can put the input to the function.
但是，如果不输入任何内容，您可以直接写上“ void”一词，
But if it takes no input, you can literally write the word "void,"
这是一个艺术术语，仅表示没有任何内容。
which is a term of art that just means, nothing goes here.
我现在要继续执行get_negative_int。
I'm going to go ahead now and implement get_negative_int.
坦率地说，我认为这将与上周非常相似。
And frankly, I think it's going to be pretty similar to last week.
但是我的记忆有些朦胧。
But my memory is a little hazy.
再说一次，这将是故意存在的缺陷。
So again, it will be deliberately flawed.
但是我将继续声明一个名为n的变量。
But I'm going to go ahead and declare a variable called n.
然后，我将执行以下操作-
Then I'm going to do the following--
我将设置n等于get_int。
I'm going to set n equal to get_int.
我只是要明确要求用户输入“负整数”
And I'm just going to explicitly ask the user for "Negative integer" followed
一个空格。
by a space.
然后，当n小于0时，我将继续执行此操作。
And then I'm going to keep doing this while n is less than 0.
然后在最后一行，我将返回n。
And then at the very last line, I'm going to return n.
再说一次，我声称这个功能会
So again, I claim that this function will
从用户那里得到负整数。
get me a negative int from the user.
而且它将一直反复进行直到用户合作为止。
And it's going to keep doing it again and again until the user cooperates.
但是，有一个错误。
However, there is a bug.
实际上，有几个错误。
And there's a couple of bugs, in fact.
现在，让我继续犯一个故意的错误-造成越野车1，
Right now, let me go ahead and make a deliberate mistake-- make buggy1,
进入。
Enter.
我在这里看到很多错误。
And I see a whole bunch of errors here.
我可以在此使用help50。
I could use help50 on this.
但是基于上周，有没有人记得这里的错误可能是什么？
But based on last week, does anyone recall what the error here might be?
“错误-函数&#39;get_negative_int&#39;的隐式声明
"Error-- implicit declaration of function 'get_negative_int'
在C99中无效。”
is invalid in C99."
所以我不知道所有这些，而是函数的隐式声明
So I don't know all of that, but implicit declaration of function
是您将开始看到的东西
is something you're going to start to see
如果您犯此错误，则更多。
more often if you make this mistake.
有人回想起这是什么意思，而无需借助help50的解决方法是什么？
Anyone recall what this means and what the fix is without resorting to help50?
是的，茉莉，你觉得呢？
Yeah, Jasmine, what do you think?
贾斯敏：所以基本上，因为你宣布了它
JASMINE: So basically, since you declared it
在代码中使用它之后，
after you already used it in your code, it
不知道在处理它时会读什么。
doesn't know what to read that as when it's processing it.
因此，当您实际启动代码时，必须将第一行移到上方。
So you have to move the first line above when you actually start the code.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：完美。
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
这是我唯一要声明复制/粘贴的时间
And this is the only time I will claim that copy/paste
是可以接受和鼓励的。
is acceptable and encouraged.
我将仅复制该函数的第一行。
I'm going to copy the very first line only of that function.
正如Jasmine提议的那样，我将其粘贴到文件的最顶部，
And as Jasmine proposed, I'm going to paste it at the very top of the file,
从而给自己一个暗示，也就是所谓的原型。
thereby giving myself a hint otherwise known as a prototype.
所以我什至会贴上这样的标签，以提醒自己为什么它在那里-
So I'll even label it as such to remind myself why it's there--
该功能的原型。
prototype of that function.
在这里，我将继续进行“从用户那里获取负整数”。
And here, I'm going to go ahead and "Get negative integer from user."
然后，该功能保持不变。
And then this function is as left as written.
所以我现在最顶部有这个原型
So I now have this prototype at the very top
我的文件，我认为确实可以摆脱此错误。
of my file, which I think will indeed get rid of this error.
让我再去制作越野车1。
Let me go to make buggy1 again.
现在，我看到确实已编译好。
Now I see that indeed compiled OK.
但是当我现在运行它时，./buggy1--
But when I run it now, ./buggy1--
让我继续输入负整数1。
let me go ahead and input a negative integer, negative 1.
嗯
Hm.
负2，负3-
Negative 2, negative 3--
我觉得函数应该对此感到满意，而事实显然并非如此。
I feel like the function should be happy with this, and it's obviously not.
所以有一个错误。
So there's a bug.
我要继续并按Control-C退出程序
I'm going to go ahead and hit Control-C to get out of my program
因为否则，它将永远运行下去。
because otherwise, it would run potentially forever.
现在，我将使用debug50。
And now I'm going to use debug50.
但是，对于Peter的问题，debug50真的很有趣
But debug50 just got really interesting, to Peter's question
更早的时候，因为现在有我可以介入的事情。
earlier, because now I have things I can step into.
我不是在main中编写所有代码。
I'm not writing all of my code in main.
现在有另一个函数称为get_negative_int。
There's this other function now called get_negative_int.
因此，让我们看看现在会发生什么。
So let's see what happens now.
让我继续，在第一个有趣的代码行上设置一个断点，
Let me go ahead and set a breakpoint on the first interesting line of code,
第10行。
line 10.
有趣的是，在其他方面
And it's interesting only in the sense that everything else
在这一点上是样板。
is kind of boilerplate at this point.
您只需要执行此操作即可启动程序。
You just have to do it to get your program started.
我现在要去这里。
I'm going to now go down here.
我将执行debug50 ./buggy1。
And I'm going to do debug50 ./buggy1.
稍后，它将打开侧边栏。
And in a moment, it's going to open up that sidebar.
我现在不仅要关注局部变量
And I'm going to focus now not only on local variables--
就像我之前所做的那样，请注意，默认情况下，我在此处再次等于0。
like I did before, notice that i is again equal to 0 here by default.
但是，我还将在此展示此选项，即调用堆栈。
But I'm also going to reveal this option here, Call Stack.
因此，调用堆栈是引用所有函数的一种理想方式
So Call Stack is a fancy way of referring to all of the functions
此时您的程序已执行但尚未返回。
that your program at this point in time has executed and not yet returned from.
所以现在，调用堆栈上只有一件事
So right now, there's only one thing on the call stack
因为当前正在执行的唯一功能当然是
because the only function that is currently executing is, of course,
主要，因为为什么？
main, because why?
我在第10行设置了一个断点，根据定义，该断点位于main内部。
I set a breakpoint at line 10, which is, by definition, inside of main.
但是，对于彼得早些时候的问题，我觉得第10和11行-
But to Peter's question earlier, I feel like lines 10 and 11--
坦白说，它们看起来很正确，对吧？
frankly, they look pretty correct, right?
在这一点上很难搞砸
It's hard at this point to have screwed up
第10行和第11行除外，因为在语法上，因为我得到的是负整数。
lines 10 and 11 except syntactically, because I'm getting a negative int.
我将其存储在i中，然后打印出i的值
I'm storing it in i, and then I'm printing out the value of i
在这两行上。
on those two lines.
但是，如果相反，我对get_negative_int感到好奇吗？
But what if instead, I'm curious about get_negative_int?
我觉得这是错误-从逻辑上讲，
I feel like the bug-- logically, it's got
之所以加入其中，是因为这是我编写的较难的代码。
to be in there because that's the harder code that I wrote.
请注意这次，不要单击“跳过”，
Notice this time, instead of clicking Step Over,
让我继续并单击“进入”，这是彼得的按钮之一
let me go ahead and click on Step Into, which is one of the buttons Peter
暗指。
alluded to.
当我单击“单步执行”时，请注意，您有点像兔子洞了。
And when I click Step Into, notice that you sort of go down the rabbit hole.
然后debug50跳入函数get_negative_int，
And debug50 jumps into the function get_negative_int,
它着重于第一个有趣的代码行。
and it focuses on the first interesting line of code.
这样做本身并不是一件有趣的事情。
So do, in and of itself, really isn't that interesting.
Int n没那么有趣，因为它不是
Int n isn't that interesting because it's not
甚至给它分配一个值。
assigning a value to it even yet.
多汁的第一行代码似乎是第19行。
The first juicy line of code seems to be line 19.
这就是调试器跳到那条线的原因。
And that's why the debugger has jumped to that line.
现在，n = get_int感觉很正确。
Now, n = get_int feels pretty correct.
很难滥用get_int。
It's hard to misuse get_int.
但是，现在请注意右侧发生了什么。
But notice now on the right-hand side what has happened.
在“调用堆栈”下，您现在看到了两件事，不仅是主要的，
Under Call Stack, you now see two things, not only main,
而且还有堆栈中的get_negative_int。
but also get_negative_int in a stack.
就像自助餐厅里的一堆托盘一样。
It's like a stack of trays in a cafeteria.
底部的第一个纸盘像主纸盘一样。
The first tray at the bottom is like main.
自助餐厅中堆栈上的第二个纸盒现在是get_negative_int。
The second tray on the stack in the cafeteria is now get_negative_int.
最酷的是，请注意，现在，我
And what's cool about this is that notice that right now, I
可以看到我的局部变量
can see my local variables, n.
这确实是我使用的变量。
And that's indeed the variable I used.
所以我不再见我了。
So I no longer see i.
我看到n是因为我正在使用get_negative_int函数。
I see n because I'm into the get_negative_int function.
现在，如果我不断单击“跳过”
And now if I keep clicking Step Over again and again
输入数字后。
after typing in a number.
让我在这里输入负1。
Let me type in negative 1 here.
现在注意在屏幕的右上角，您可以在调试器中看到
Now notice on the top right of the screen, you can see in the debugger
n等于负1。
that n equals negative 1.
我现在要继续，然后单击“跳过”。
I'm going to now go ahead and click Step Over.
我想我将在第22行结束。
And I think I'm going to end up in line 22.
如果人类输入了像负1这样的负整数，
If the human has typed in a negative integer like negative 1,
显然，这是负面的。
obviously, that's negative.
让我们继续第22行。
Let's proceed to line 22.
但是请注意当我单击“跳过”时会发生什么。
But watch what happens when I click Step Over.
它实际上似乎一次又一次地回到do循环
It actually seems to be going back to the do loop again and again
再一次，我将继续提供负整数。
and again, as it will, I keep providing negative integers.
所以我的逻辑应该是，好的，如果n为负1，
So my logic then should be, well, OK, if n is negative 1,
但我的循环仍在运行，您的逻辑要点是什么？
but my loop is still running, what should your logical takeaway here be?
如果n为负1，并且根据定义为负整数，
If n is negative 1, and that is by definition a negative integer,
但我的循环仍在运行，您的诊断结论可能是什么
but my loop is still running, what could be your diagnostic conclusion
如果调试器本质上是向您显示此提示？ n为负1
if the debugger is essentially revealing this hint to you? n is negative 1,
但循环仍在进行。
but the loop is still going.
奥马尔，你会得出什么结论？
Omar, what would you conclude?
OMAR：或者条件错误，或者某种布尔逻辑
OMAR: Either the condition is wrong, or maybe some sort of Boolean logic
可能有缺陷。
could be flawed.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：完美。
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
所以很明显，要么条件不对，
So obviously, either the condition is wrong,
或我的布尔逻辑有问题。
or there's something wrong with my Boolean logic.
布尔逻辑只是指真或假。
And Boolean logic just refers to true or false.
所以在某个地方，我说的是真而不是假，
So somewhere, I'm saying true instead of false,
或者我说的是假而不是真。
or I'm saying false instead of true.
坦白说，这是我唯一拥有代码的地方
And frankly, the only place where I have code
从逻辑上讲，这将使循环一次又一次地进入第21行。
that's going to make this loop go again and again must logically be on line 21.
因此，即使您不太确定如何解决它，只需通过演绎，
So even if you're not quite sure how to fix it yet, just by deduction,
您应该意识到，好吧，负1是变量中的值。
you should realize that, OK, negative 1 is what's in the variable.
但这还不够。
But that's not good enough.
循环仍在进行。
The loop is still going.
我一定搞砸了循环。
I must have screwed up the loop.
确实，让我现在就说出来。
And indeed, let me just now call it out.
第21行确实是该错误的来源。
Line 21 is indeed the source of the bug.
所以我们隔离了它。
So we've isolated it.
在23行中，我们至少找到了一行
Out of 23 lines, we've at least found the one line
我知道解决方案必须在哪里。
where I know the solution has to be.
有什么解决方案？
What's the solution?
得益于调试器，我现在该如何解决逻辑问题？
How do I fix the logic now thanks to the debugger having led me down this road?
如何在此处修复第21行？
How do I fix line 21 here?
解决办法是什么？
What's the fix?
你有什么建议？
What do you propose?
是的，雅各布？
Yeah, Jacob?
JACOB：您必须从n小于0开始对其进行更改
JACOB: You would have to change it from while n is less than 0
当n大于0时。
to while n is greater than 0.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的。
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
因此，我要说的是n大于0，而不是n小于0。
So instead of n less than 0, I want to say n greater than 0.
我认为-稍作澄清，我认为
And I think-- slight clarification, I think
我想在这里包括0，因为0不是负数。
I want to include 0 here because 0 is not negative.
如果我想要一个负整数，我想我可能是
And if I want a negative int, I think what I'm probably
要说的是，当n大于或等于0时，
going to want to say is while n is greater than or equal to 0,
继续做循环。
keep doing the loop.
因此，我很容易理解，只是倒置了逻辑。
So I very understandably sort of just inverted the logic.
没什么大不了。
No big deal.
我在想负面情绪，但我做不到。
I'm thinking negatives, and I did less than.
但是修复很容易。
But the fix is easy.
关键是调试器将您引向了这一点。
The point is the debugger led you to this point.
现在，那些之前已经编程的人
Now, those of you who have programmed before probably
看到虫子向您跳来跳去。
saw the bug jumping out at you.
那些以前可能没有编程的人，
Those of you who haven't programmed before, probably with some time,
会找出错误所在，因为在23行中，
would have figured out what the bug was, because out of 23 lines,
它必须是其中之一。
it's got to be one of those.
但是随着我们的程序变得越来越复杂，
But as our programs get more sophisticated,
我们通常会开始编写更多行代码，debug50和调试器
and we start writing more lines of code, debug50 and debuggers in general
将成为您的朋友。
will be your friend.
我意识到这说起来容易做起来难，因为首先
And I realize that this is easier said than done because at first,
当使用调试器时，您会觉得，啊，我
when using a debugger, you're going to feel like, ah, I'm
只是要使用printf。
just going to use printf.
啊，我要为此奋斗。
Ah, I'm just going to fight through this.
因为有一些学习曲线，
Because there's a bit of a learning curve,
您将获得更多的时间，仅此而已
you will gain back that time and more by just
解决此类问题时，首先将调试器用作本能。
using a debugger as your first instinct when chasing down problems like this.
好的，这就是debug50，它是您工具箱中的新工具
All right, so that's it for debug50, a new tool in your toolkit in addition
打印
to printf.
但是debug50是两者中比较强大的一个。
But debug50 is hands down the more powerful of the two.
现在，你们中有些人想知道过去几周
Now, some of you have wondered over the past couple of weeks
为什么这里有这个小橡皮鸭。
why there's this little rubber duck here.
实际上，这也是有原因的。
And there actually is a reason for this too.
认真地说，有一种最终的调试技术，
And there's one final debugging technique that, in all seriousness,
我们今天将向您介绍被称为橡皮鸭调试。
we'll introduce you today to known as rubber duck debugging.
你可以用谷歌搜索。
And you can google this.
有整篇维基百科文章。
There's a whole Wikipedia article about it.
对于计算机科学家来说，这在计算机科学界是一回事
And this is kind of a thing in computer science circles for computer scientists
或程序员在桌子上放橡皮鸭。
or programmers to have rubber ducks on their desk.
关键是有时候
And the point here is that sometimes, when
试图了解代码中的错误，
trying to understand what is wrong in your code,
进行交谈会有所帮助。
it helps to just talk it through.
在理想的世界中，我们只需要与我们的同事或合作伙伴交谈
And in an ideal world, we would just talk to our colleague or our partner
在某些项目上。
on some project.
只是听到自己发声说出你的代码是什么
And just in hearing yourself vocalize what it is your code
经常会发生这样的情况，即众所周知的灯泡熄灭。
is supposed to do, very often, that proverbial light bulb goes off.
你就像，哦，等等，没关系，我明白了，
And you're like, oh, wait a minute, never mind, I got it,
只是因为您听见自己说话不合逻辑
just because you heard yourself speaking illogically when
您想要的是真正合乎逻辑的东西。
you intended something actual logical.
现在，我们并非经常都有同事，合作伙伴或朋友
Now, we don't often all have colleagues or partners or friends with whom we're
与一个项目一起工作。
working on a project with.
而且我们经常没有家人或朋友
And we don't often have family members or friends
谁想知道我们所有事物的代码。
who want to hear about our code of all things.
因此，是那个伙伴的绝佳代理
And so a wonderful proxy for that conversant partner
从字面上看是橡皮鸭。
would be literally a rubber duck.
因此，在更健康的时期，我们将为大家提供橡皮鸭。
And so here in healthier times, we would be giving all of you rubber ducks.
在舞台上，我们带来了一个更大的供大家共享。
Here on stage, we brought a larger one for us all to share.
如果您注意到相机上的一些广角镜头，
If you've noticed in some of the wide shots on camera,
一直有一只鸭子在看
there's a duck who's been watching this whole time.
因此，无论何时我搞砸了，我都会
So that any time I screw up, I literally have
在这种情况下，我可以与某人进行非言语交谈。
someone I can sort of talk to nonverbally, in this case.
但是除了printf之外，我们不能强调得太多
But we can't emphasize enough that in addition to printf, in addition to
更复杂的debug50，讨论您的代码问题
the more sophisticated debug50, talking through your problems with code
是一件非常有价值的事情。
is a wonderfully valuable thing.
如果您的朋友或家人愿意听
And if your friends or family are willing to hear
关于您正在编写的一些低级代码和一些错误
about some low-level code you're writing and some bug you're
试图解决，很棒。
trying to solve, great.
但是如果没有这种情况，请与您房间里的毛绒动物聊天。
But in the absence of that, talk to a stuffed animal in your room.
如果有的话，请与实际的橡皮鸭交谈。
Talk to an actual rubber duck if you have one.
大声说话或大声思考。
Talk even aloud or think aloud.
这只是一个令人信服的好习惯
It's just a wonderful compelling habit to get
进入，因为只是在听到自己的声音就能表达出您认为合理的内容
into because just in hearing yourself vocalize what you think is logical
不合逻辑的事情会经常跳出来向你冲来。
will the illogical very often jump out at you instead.
好的，话虽这么说，这已经很多了。
All right, so with that said, that's been a lot.
让我们继续在这里休息五分钟，
Let's go ahead here and take a five-minute break,
给大家一点喘息的机会。
give everyone a bit of a breather.
当我们回来时，我们现在来看一看
And when we come back, we'll take a look now
C的一些更强大的功能
at some of the more powerful features of C
现在我们可以相信我们可以解决所有问题
now that we can trust that we can solve any problems with all
这些新工具。
of these new tools.
所以我们将回到五分之一。
So we'll be back in five.
好吧，我们回来了。
All right, we are back.
因此，让我们来看一下引擎盖下的情况，可以这么说，
So let's take a look underneath the hood, so to speak,
一台计算机，因为像这些设备一样花哨
of a computer, because as fancy as these devices
和看起来一样强大，他们是
are and as powerful as they seem, they're
他们的能力和实际能力相对较简单。
relatively simple in their capabilities and what they can actually do.
并且让我们通过上周的类型讨论来揭示更多信息。
And let's reveal as much by way of last week's discussion of type.
因此，请回想一下C支持不同的数据类型。
So recall that C supports different data types.
因此，我们看到了char，string，int和依此类推。
So we saw char, and string, and int, and so forth.
综上所述，我们拥有了所有这些。
So to recap, we had all of these.
好吧，事实证明，每种数据类型
Well, it turns out that each of these data types
在典型的计算机系统上被定义为占用固定空间。
is defined on a typical computer system as taking up a fixed amount of space.
它取决于计算机，无论是Mac或PC，还是旧的还是新的，
And it depends on the computer, whether it's Mac or PC, or old or new,
这些数据类型通常使用多少空间。
just how much space is used typically by these data types.
但是在CS50 IDE上，所有这些类型的大小如下：
But on CS50 IDE, the sizes of all of these types are as follows--
布尔值（true或false）仅使用1个字节。
a bool, true or false, uses just 1 byte.
现在，这实际上有点浪费，因为1字节是8位，天哪，
Now, that's actually a little wasteful because 1 byte is 8 bits, and gosh,
对于布尔，您只需要1位。
for a bool, you should only need 1 bit.
在C语言中，您不能轻松地在单位级别上工作。
You can't work at the single-bit level easily in C.
因此，我们通常只在布尔上花费1个完整字节。
And so we just typically spend 1 whole byte on a bool.
Char也将是1个字节。
Char is going to be 1 byte as well.
这听起来可能很熟悉，因为上周我们谈论ASCII时，
And that might sound familiar, because last week when we talked about ASCII,
我们建议可能的字符总数
we proposed that the total number of possible characters
您可以用一个char表示256，因为8位和2
you can represent with a char was 256 because of 8 bits and 2
到第八力量。
to the eighth power.
因此，一个字符是1个字节。
So one char is 1 byte.
不管怎样，这在C语言中都是固定的。
And that's fixed in C, no matter what.
然后是所有其他这些数据类型。
Then there were all of these other data types.
有浮点数，是带小数点的实数。
There was float, which is a real number with a decimal point.
碰巧使用了4个字节。
That happens to use 4 bytes.
双精度数也是带小数点的实数，
A double is also a real number with a decimal point,
但是它使用8个字节，因此可以提供更高的精度。
but it uses 8 bytes, which gives you even more precision.
例如，小数点后可以有更多有效数字。
You can have more significant digits after the decimal point, for instance.
整数，我们用了一堆。
Ints, we've used a bunch.
这些通常是4个字节。
Those are 4 bytes, typically.
长是两倍大，这只允许
A long is twice as big, and that just allows
您代表更大的数字。
you to represent an even bigger number.
你们中有些人可能是完全在信用时做到了这一点
And some of you might have done that exactly on credit when
存储整个信用卡号。
storing a whole credit card number.
目前，字符串是可变数目的字节。
Strings, for now, are a variable number of bytes.
它可以是一小段文字，一长段文字，整个段落。
It could be a short string of text, a long string of text, a whole paragraph.
因此，这将有所不同。
So that's going to vary.
因此，下一次我们将回到字符串的概念。
So we'll come back to this notion of string next time.
但是今天，如果您愿意的话，只关注这些原始类型。
But today, focus on just these primitive types, if you will.
这是您计算机内部内容的图片。
And here is a picture of what is inside of your computer.
因此，这是一块内存或RAM，即随机存取存储器。
So this is a piece of memory or RAM, Random Access Memory.
它可能会小一点。
And it might be a little smaller.
可能会更大一点，具体取决于它是否是笔记本电脑，
It might be a little bigger depending on whether it's a laptop,
或台式机，手机或类似产品。
or desktop, or phone, or the like.
但是程序在内存或RAM中
But it's in memory, or RAM, that programs
在运行时存储。
are stored while they're running.
这是打开文件时存储文件的位置。
And it's where files are stored when they are open.
因此，通常，如果您保存，安装程序或保存文件，
So typically, if you save, install programs, or save files,
这些被保存在通常称为您的硬盘驱动器或硬盘上，
those are saved on what's generally called your hard drive, or hard disk,
或固态磁盘，CD或其他某种物理介质。
or solid-state disk, or CD, or some other physical medium.
而且，[听不清]是他们不需要电
And that, the [INAUDIBLE] of which is that they don't require electricity
长期存储您的数据。
to store your data long term.
RAM是不同的。
RAM is different.
可以这么说，它是易变的。
It's volatile, so to speak.
但这甚至比硬盘或固态磁盘快得多。
But it's much faster than a hard disk or a solid-state disk, even.
它更快，因为它是纯电子的。
It's much faster because it's purely electronic.
实际上，没有活动部件。
And indeed, there are no moving parts.
如图所示，它是纯电子的。
It's purely electronic, as pictured here.
因此，有了RAM，您就可以打开文件并运行程序
And so with RAM, you have the ability to open files and run programs
更快，因为当您双击某个程序以运行它时，
more quickly because when you double-click a program to run it,
或者您打开文件以查看或编辑它，
or you open a file in order to view or edit it,
它被临时存储在RAM中。
it's stored temporarily in RAM.
长话短说，如果您的笔记本电脑电池没电了，
And long story short, if your laptop battery has ever died,
或拔掉计算机的电源，或者手机掉线了，
or your computer's gotten unplugged, or your phone dies,
您和我倾向于丢失数据的原因，您刚才提到的那段
the reason that you and I tend to lose data, the paragraph that you just
在文章中写道您尚未保存，
wrote in the essay that you hadn't yet saved,
是因为RAM（内存）是易失的。
is because RAM, memory, is volatile.
也就是说，它需要电力才能继续为其供电。
That is, it requires electricity to continue powering it.
但是出于我们的目的，我们只专注于RAM，
But for our purposes, we're only going to focus on RAM,
还没有那么多的长期磁盘空间，因为
not so much long-term disk space yet, because when
您正在用C运行程序，实际上，按照定义，
you're running a program in C, it is indeed, by definition,
运行在计算机的内存中。
running in your computer's memory.
但是有趣的是，像这张照片一样简单的东西
But the funny thing about something as simple as this picture
这些黑色矩形中的每一个都是一种芯片。
is that each of these black rectangles is kind of a chip.
在这些筹码中，所有的0和1都存储了
And in those chips are stored all of the 0's and 1's, the little
我们在第0周提到的切换。
switches that we alluded to in week 0.
因此，让我们集中精力并仅放大这些芯片之一。
So let's focus on and just zoom in on just one of these chips.
现在，我不知道这根RAM棒有多大是有道理的。
Now, it stands to reason that I don't know how big this stick of RAM is.
也许是1 GB，十亿字节。
Maybe it's 1 gigabyte, a billion bytes.
也许是4 GB。
Maybe it's 4 gigabytes.
也许它更大或更小。
Maybe it's even smaller or bigger.
该硬件物理上表示一些字节。
There's some number of bytes represented physically by this hardware.
所以，如果我们进一步放大，让我建议一下，
So if we zoom in further, let me propose that, all right,
我不知道这里有多少字节。
I don't know how many bytes are here.
但是如果有一定数量的字节，无论是十亿字节还是20亿字节，
But if there's some number of bytes, whether it's a billion or 2 billion,
或更少或更多，这是我们合理的理由
or fewer or more, it stands to reason that we
可以对所有这些字节编号。
could just number all of these bytes.
我们可以考虑一下这个物理设备，这个内存，
We could sort of think of this physical device, this memory,
就像是一个网格，从上到下，从左到右。
as just being a grid, top to bottom, left to right.
而我刚刚覆盖在此物理设备上的每个正方形
And each of the squares I've just overlaid on this physical device
可能代表一个字节。
might represent an individual byte.
再说一次，实际上，也许还有更多。
And again, in reality, maybe there's more of them.
也许他们更少了。
Maybe there's fewer of them.
但这是有道理的，无论有多少，
But it stands to reason, no matter how many there are,
我们可以将每个位置都视为一个位置。
we can think of each of these as having a location.
就像，这是第一个字节，第二个字节，第三个字节，依此类推。
Like, this is the first byte, second byte, third byte, and so forth.
那么，一个char占用1个字节是什么意思呢？
Well, what does it mean, then, for a char to take up 1 byte?
这意味着，如果您的计算机内存正在运行某个程序，则可能
That means that if your computer's memory is running a program maybe
您写的或我写的是在其中某处使用char变量的情况，
that you wrote or I wrote that's using a char variable somewhere in it,
您存储在该变量中的字符可能很好
the char you're storing in that variable may very well
实际存储在该RAM的左上角。
be stored in the top left-hand corner physically of this piece of RAM.
也许在那里。
Maybe it's there.
也许在别处。
Maybe it's elsewhere.
但这只是一个物理正方形。
But it's just one physical square.
如果您要存储一个像int这样的东西，它占用4个字节，
If you're storing something like an int, which takes up 4 bytes,
好吧，坦率地说，可能会占据那里顶部的所有四个正方形
well, that frankly might take up all four squares along the top there
或者别的地方。
or somewhere else.
如果您使用的很长，那将占用两倍的空间。
If you're using a long, that's going to take up twice as much space.
因此，在您的计算机内存中代表更大的数字
So representing an even bigger number in your computer's memory
将要求您使用所有0和1
is going to require that you use all of the 0's and 1's
而是由这8个字节组成。
comprising these 8 bytes instead.
但是现在让我们远离物理硬件。
but let's now move away from physical hardware.
如果您愿意的话，让我们抽象一下，现在就开始想起我们的记忆
Let's abstract it away, if you will, and just now start to think of our memory
就像这个网格一样。
as just this grid.
从技术上讲，它不是二维结构。
And technically, it's not a two-dimensional structure.
我可以很容易地从左到右绘制所有这些字节。
I could just as easily draw all of these bytes from left to right.
我只需要在屏幕上放几个就行了。
I could just fit fewer of them on the screen.
因此，我们将进一步比喻物理隐喻
So we'll take the physical metaphor a bit further
并把我们计算机的内存想象成这个网格，这个字节网格。
and just think of our computer's memory as this grid, this grid of bytes.
这些字节均为8位。
And those bytes are each 8 bits.
这些位只是0和1。
Those bits are just 0's and 1's.
因此，我们真正要做的是隐喻地放大计算机的内存
So what we've really done is zoom in metaphorically on our computer's memory
开始思考当您将事物最终存储在内存中的位置时
to start thinking about where things are going to end up in memory when you
双击Mac或PC上的程序，或者在CS50 IDE中，
double-click on a program on your Mac or PC or, in CS50 IDE,
当您执行./hello或./buggy0或./buggy1时，
when you do ./hello or ./buggy0 or ./buggy1,
这些是计算机内存中的所有字节
it's these bytes in your computer's memory that are filled with all
变量的值。
of your variables' values.
因此，让我们在这里考虑一个示例。
So let's consider an example here.
假设我写了一些涉及声明三个分数的代码。
Suppose I had written some code that involved declaring three scores.
也许这是一门课，需要进行三项测试。
Maybe it's a class that's got, like, three tests.
您想在所有这三个测试中平均学生的成绩。
And you want to average the student's grade across all three of those tests.
好吧，让我们继续编写一个完成此任务的快速程序。
Well, let's go ahead and write a quick program that does exactly this.
在CS50 IDE中，我将创建一个名为scores.c的程序。
In CS50 IDE, I'm going to create a program called scores.c.
在scores.c中，我将继续并#include stdio.h。
And in scores.c, I'm going to go ahead and #include stdio.h.
然后，我将照常做int main（void）。
I'm going to then do my int main(void) as usual.
然后在这里，我将使其非常简单。
And then inside of here, I'm going to keep it very simple.
我要给自己一个称为score1的整数。
I'm going to give myself one int called score1.
只是为了好玩，我要
And just to be a little playful, I'm going
像上周一样将其设置为72。
to set it equal to 72, like last week.
我要给自己第二个分数并设定
I'm going to give myself a second score and set
它等于73，然后是第三个分数，其值为33。
it equal to 73, and then a third score whose value is going to be 33.
然后让我继续打印这三个值的平均值
And then let me go ahead and print out the average of those three values
通过插入占位符获取浮点值，对吗？
by plugging in a placeholder for floating point value, right?
如果您将三个整数相加并除以3，
If you add three integers together and divide them by 3,
我可能会得到一个带小数点的分数或实数。
I may very well get a fraction or a real number with a decimal point.
所以我将使用％f代替％i，因为我不想截断
So I'm going to use %f instead of %i because I don't want to truncate
某人的成绩。
someone's grade.
否则，如果它们具有99.9％的百分比，则不会将它们四舍五入为100％。
Otherwise, if they have, like, a 99.9%, they're not being rounded up to 100%.
正如我们上周所讨论的，由于截断，他们将获得99％的收益。
They're going to get the 99% because of truncation, as we discussed last week.
那么，现在我该如何做平均数学呢？
So how do I do now the math of an average?
好吧，这很简单-score1
Well, it's pretty straightforward-- score1
加上圆括号中的score2和score3，
plus score2 plus score3 in parentheses, just
就像在数学上一样，除以3（分号）。
like in math, divided by 3, semicolon.
让我保存该文件。
Let me save that file.
让我在最底端打分。
Let me do make scores at the bottom.
同样，我们不会手动使用Clang。
Again, we're not going to use Clang manually.
不需要，因为make的运行要容易得多。
No need to, because it's a lot easier to run make.
但是我确实搞砸了。
But I did mess up here.
“格式指定类型为&#39;double&#39;，但参数的类型为&#39;int&#39;。”
"Format specifies type 'double', but the argument has type 'int'."
所以我不太明白。
So I don't quite understand that.
但这引起了我对％f的注意，而且我的数学运算看起来像
But it's drawing my attention to the %f and the fact that my math looks like
这。
this.
那么这里有什么想法吗？
So any thoughts here?
我不认为printf会在这里帮助我，因为该错误是
I don't think printf is going to help me here because the bug is
在printf行中。
within the printf line.
我认为debug50不会对我有真正的帮助，因为我已经
I don't think that debug50 is going to really help me here because I already
知道错误所在的代码行。
know what line of code the bug is in.
感觉就像是与实物鸭说话的机会
This feels like an opportunity to talk to the physical duck
或其他无生命的物体。
or some other inanimate object.
或者，也许我们可以考虑一下上周我们遇到了什么错误。
Or we can perhaps think about what errors we ran into even last week.
[？ Arpan ，?]您怎么看？
[? Arpan, ?] what do you think?
[？ ARPAN ：?]我想这是在告诉您，因为它是
[? ARPAN: ?] I think it's telling you this because it's
接收的所有值都是整数类型，
receiving in all the values are integer type,
但是您告诉它是浮动的。
but you are telling it to be in float.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
所以score1，score2，score3都是整数，
So score1, score2, score3 are all integers,
而数字3实际上是整数。
and the number 3 is literally an integer.
因此，这次，编译器足够聪明，可以意识到，等一下，
And so this time, the compiler is smart enough to realize, wait a minute,
您试图将整数结果强制为浮点值，
you're trying to coerce an integer result into a floating point value,
但是如果可以的话，您还没有执行任何浮点运算。
but you haven't done any floating point arithmetic, if you will.
那你知道吗？
So you know what?
有几种方法可以解决此问题。
There's a few ways to fix this.
上周，回想一下，我们建议您可以使用演员表，
Last week, recall we proposed that you could use a cast,
您可以将其中一个或多个这些值显式转换为浮点数。
and you could explicitly cast one or more of those values to a float.
因此，例如，我可以这样做。
So I could do this, for instance.
或者我可以将所有这些都转换为浮点数，或者将其中之一转换为浮点数。
Or I could cast all of these to floats or one of these to floats.
有很多不同的可能性。
There's many different possibilities.
但坦率地说，最简单的解决方法是例如除以3.0。
But frankly, the simplest fix is just to divide, for instance, by 3.0.
我可以避免仅仅从一个人投射到另一个人的一些麻烦
I can avoid some of the headaches of casting from one to another by just
确保至少有一个浮点
making sure that there's at least one floating point
此算术中涉及的值。
value involved in this arithmetic.
现在让我重新编译分数。
So now let me recompile scores.
这次，编译正常。
This time, it compiles OK.
让我来做./得分，瞧，我的平均值不是很高，59.333333。
Let me do ./scores, and voila, my average isn't so high, 59.333333.
好吧，所以里面到底发生了什么
All right, so what is actually going on inside
不论浮点运算是什么，
of the computer irrespective of the floating point arithmetic, which was,
再次，上个星期的话题？
again, a topic of last week?
好吧，让我们考虑这三个变量，score1，score2，score3--
Well, let's consider these three variables, score1, score2, score3--
它们实际存储在计算机内存中的什么位置？
where are they actually being stored in the computer's memory?
好吧，让我们再次考虑该网格。
Well, let's consider that grid again.
再说一次，为了方便起见，我将从左上方开始。
And again, I'm going to start at top left for convenience.
但从技术上讲-我们将在以后看到这一点-
But technically speaking-- we'll see this down the road--
您计算机的内存就像这张大画布一样。
your computer's memory is just like this big canvas.
价值可能会出现在所有不同的地方。
And values can end up in all different places.
但是今天，我们将保持清洁。
But for today, we'll keep it clean.
我声称第一个变量score1会在这里，
The first variable, score1, I claim is going to be here,
为了简单起见，左上方。
top left, for simplicity.
但是，分数1在何处重要？
But what's important about where score1--
也就是说，正在存储72个，是否要占用其中四个盒子。
that is, 72-- is being stored, is it's taking up four of these boxes.
回想一下，这些框中的每一个都代表1个字节。
Each of these boxes, recall, represents 1 byte.
回想一下，CS50 IDE中的整数是4个字节。
And an integer, recall, in CS50 IDE is 4 bytes.
因此，我使用了4个字节的空间来表示数字72。
Therefore, I have used 4 bytes of space to represent the number 72.
同样，score2中的数字73
The number 73 in score2 similarly is going
占据四个盒子，score3也将占据四个盒子。
to take up four boxes, as is score3 going to take up four boxes as well.
但是，这里的引擎盖下到底发生了什么？
But what's really going on underneath the hood here?
好吧，如果每个正方形代表一个字节，
Well, if each of these squares represents a byte,
这些字节中的每一个都是8位，而一位只是0或1，
and each of those bytes is 8 bits, and a bit is just a 0 or 1,
引擎盖下面真正发生的事情是这样的。
what's really going on underneath the hood is something like this.
不知何故，这个电子存储器正在存储
Somehow, this electronic memory is storing
以正确的方式储存电力
electricity in just the right way so that it's storing
0和1的这种模式，又名
this pattern of 0's and 1's, a.k.a.
十进制为72，即0和1的模式，又名
72 in decimal, this pattern of 0's and 1's, a.k.a.
十进制73，即0和1的模式，又名
73 in decimal, this pattern of 0's and 1's, a.k.a.
小数点后为33。
33 in decimal.
但是同样，我们不必继续思考或居住
But again, we don't have to keep thinking about or dwelling
在二进制级别。
on the binary level.
但这只是说，到目前为止，我们已经讨论过的所有内容
But this is only to say that everything we've discussed thus far
现在在这张照片中走到一起
is coming together now in this one picture
因为计算机只是为我们存储了这些模式，
because a computer is just storing these patterns for us,
由于我们的编程，我们现在正在分配空间
and we are allocating space now thanks to our programming
语言通过这样的代码。
language via code like this.
但是此代码虽然正确，但实际上是59.333333，依此类推，依此类推
But this code, correct though it may be, indeed 59.333333 and so forth
如果我的考试分数分别是72、73和33，则是我的平均值。
was my average if my test scores were 72, 73, and 33.
但是我觉得这里有机会进行更好的设计。
But I feel like there's an opportunity for better design here.
因此，回想一下设计，不仅是正确性，还不仅仅是风格
So not just correctness, not just style, recall that design
这是代码质量的另一个指标。
is this other metric of code quality.
这有点主观，而且
And it's a little more subjective, and it's
多一些合理的人之间的辩论。
a little more subject to debate among reasonable people.
但是我真的不喜欢我使用这种命名方案所做的事情。
But I don't really love what I was doing with this naming scheme.
实际上，如果我们看一下代码，
And in fact, if we look at the code, there really
对我的程序而言，仅此三行而已。
wasn't much more to my program than these three lines.
我担心该程序的设计不是特别好。
I worry this program isn't particularly well designed.
可能是什么让您对这三行代码有误呢？
What rubs you the wrong way, perhaps, about those three lines of code?
有什么更好的办法吗？
What could be better?
即使您不知道解决方案，尤其是
And even if you don't know the solution, especially
如果您以前从未编程过，那三行的气味是什么？
if you've never programmed before, what kind of smells about those three lines?
这实际上是一个艺术术语。
This is actually a term of art.
“代码气味”就像是某种东西-出于某种原因而不喜欢它。
"Code smell" is like something-- not loving that for some reason.
如果您不能全力以赴，那不是最好的设计。
If you can't put your finger on it, it's not the best design.
代码闻起来。
The code smells.
如果您愿意，关于score1，score2，score3会有什么臭味？
What's smelly, if you will, about score1, score2, score3?
瑞安，你怎么看？
Ryan, what do you think?
赖安：如果您要进行平均计算，
RYAN: If you're doing an average calculation,
您无需在代码中将它们全部加在一起。
you don't need to add them up all together in the code.
您可以预先添加它们并将其存储为一个变量。
You can add them up beforehand and store it as one variable.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的。
DAVID MALAN: Absolutely.
如果要计算平均值，则不需要保持这三个平均值。
If I'm computing the average, I don't need to keep all three around.
我可以保留一个总和，然后将总和除以总数。
I can just keep a sum and then divide the whole sum by the total number.
我喜欢那种本能。
I like that, that instinct.
您现在可能不喜欢该代码的设计吗？
What else might you not like about the design of this code now?
得分1，得分2，得分3。
Score1, score2, score3.
仍有机会进行改进吗？
Might there be opportunity still for improvement?
我觉得您随时都可以看到这种重复。
I feel like any time you start to see this repetition, maybe.
安德鲁，你的想法吗？
Andrew, your thoughts?
ANDREW：不是将三个分数一起硬编码吗？
ANDREW: Not hard code the three scores together?
DAVID MALAN：好的，所以不要硬编码这三个分数。
DAVID MALAN: OK, so not hard code the three scores.
而您会怎么做呢？
And what would you do instead?
ANDREW：也许要输入一个信息，否则我会-
ANDREW: Maybe take an input, or I would--
是的，我不会自己写下分数。
yeah, I wouldn't write out the scores themselves.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，另一个很好的本能。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, another good instinct.
我写了一个程序，编译了一个程序，这有点愚蠢，
It's kind of stupid that I've written a program, compiled a program,
只能计算某个字面上得到这三个部分的学生的平均值
that only computes the average for some student who literally got those three
测试成绩，没有其他人。
test scores and no others.
就像，这里没有动力。
Like, there's no dynamism here.
而且，我打电话也有点懒
Moreover, it's a little lazy too that I called
我的变量score1，score2，score3。
my variables score1, score2, score3.
我的意思是，那之后在哪里结束？
I mean, where does it end after that?
如果我想在下学期进行第四次考试，现在
If I want to have a fourth test next semester, now
我必须去并获得评分4。
I have to go and have score4.
如果我有五分，得分5。
If I've got a fifth, score5.
这开始让人想起上周的复制/粘贴，
That starts to be reminiscent of last week's copy/paste, which
确实不是最佳实践。
really wasn't the best practice.
因此，我建议我们对此进行清理。
And so let me propose that we clean this up.
事实证明，我们可以通过以下方式进行清理
And it turns out we can clean this up by way
另一个主题，C的另一个功能是
of another topic, another feature of C that's
也以其他语言（称为数组）呈现。
also present in other languages, known as arrays.
如果您碰巧在Scratch中使用了称为列表的内容，
And if you happened to use something called a list in Scratch,
在精神上与Scratch的清单非常相似。
very similar in spirit to Scratch's lists.
但是第一周我们在讲座中没有看到这些。
But we didn't see those in lecture that first week.
与其他语言一样，C语言中的数组是一个序列
An array in C, as in other languages, is a sequence
背对背存储在内存中的值的数量，
of values stored in memory back to back to back,
一系列连续值，可以说是背靠背。
a sequence of contiguous values, so to speak, back to back to back.
因此从某种意义上讲，它就像是从左到右的值列表
So in that sense, it's like a list of values from left to right
如果我们使用图片的隐喻，我们一直在画画。
if we use the metaphor of the picture we've been drawing.
那么，这与这里有何关系？
So how might this be germane here?
好吧，事实证明，如果您要存储一堆值，
Well, it turns out that if you want to store a whole bunch of values,
但它们都是相互关联的，就像分数一样，
but they're all kind of interrelated, like they're all scores,
您不必求助于这种懒惰，score1，score2，score3，score4，
you don't have to resort to this sort of lazy, score1, score2, score3, score4,
score5，最高为99，具体取决于有多少个分数。
score5, up to score99, depending on how many scores there are.
为什么不把所有这些数字都称为分数
Why don't you just call all of those numbers scores,
但使用略有不同的语法？
but use a slightly different syntax?
该语法使您可以访问所谓的数组。
And that syntax gives you access to what are called arrays.
因此，屏幕上的语法是一个示例
So the syntax here on the screen is an example
一次声明三个整数的空间
of declaring space for three integers all at once
并统称为“分数”。
and collectively referring to all of them as the word "scores."
因此，不再有分数1、2和3。
So there's no more scores 1, 2, and 3.
所有这三个分数都在一个称为“分数”的变量中。
All three of those scores are in a variable called "scores."
而这里的新内容是方括号，其中包含
And what's new here is the square brackets, inside of which
是一个从字面上暗示您有多少个整数的数字
is a number that literally connotes how many integers do you
想要以“分数”的名称存储。
want to store under the name "scores."
那这允许我做什么？
So what does this allow me to do?
它仍然允许我在该数组中定义三个整数。
It allows me still to define three integers in that array.
所以这个数组将是一块内存
So this array is going to be a chunk of memory
背对背，我可以输入值。
back to back to back that I can put values in.
在我看来，这些价值的表达方式将在语法上看起来像这样。
And the way I put those values is going to look syntactically like this.
我仍然使用数字，但是现在我使用了新的符号。
I still use numbers, but now I'm using a new notation.
这与我之前所诉的相似，
And it's similar to what I resorted to before,
但现在更加通用化了，而且更加动态。
but it's a little more generalized now and dynamic.
现在，如果我想更新该数组中的第一个分数，
Now if I want to update the very first score in that array,
我从字面上写出可变分数的名称，
I literally write the name of the variable scores,
方括号[0]，然后为其分配值。
bracket[0] and then assign it the value.
如果我想获得第二个分数，我会得分[1]。
If I want to get at the second score, I do scores[1].
如果我想要第三个分数，那就是分数[2]。
If I want the third score, it's scores[2].
唯一有点奇怪并且需要一些适应的事情是
And the only thing that's a little weird and takes some getting used to is
我们正在对数组进行“零索引”这一事实。
the fact that we are "zero-indexing" our arrays.
因此，在过去的示例中，例如for循环和while循环，
So in past examples, like for loops and while loops,
我有点说，嗯，这是编程中的惯例
I've sort of said, eh, it's a convention in programming
从0开始计数。
to start counting from 0.
当涉及到数组时，它们是连续的
When it comes to arrays, which are contiguous
计算机内存中的值序列必须从0开始。
sequences of values in a computer's memory, they have to start at 0.
因此，否则，如果您不从0开始计数，
So otherwise, if you don't start counting at 0,
您实际上会通过忽略一个值来浪费空间。
you're literally going to be wasting space by overlooking one value.
现在，如果我们要重命名屏幕上的内容，
So now if we were to rename things on the screen,
而不是调用这三个矩形score1，score2，score3，
instead of calling these three rectangles score1, score2, score3,
他们都被称为分数。
they're all called scores.
但是，如果您要专门参考第一个，
But if you want to refer specifically to the first one,
您使用这个花哨的括号符号，第二个使用这个括号符号，
you use this fancy bracket notation, and the second one, this bracket notation,
第三个是这个括号符号。
and the third one, this bracket notation.
但是请注意二分法。
But notice the dichotomy.
在声明数组时，在创建数组时，说，给我三个整数，
When declaring the array, when creating the array, saying, give me three ints,
您使用[3]，其中[3]是值的总数。
you use [3] where [3] is the total number of values.
当您索引到阵列中时
When you index into the array--
也就是说，当您转到该内存块中的特定位置时-
that is, when you go to a specific location in that chunk of memory--
您同样使用数字。
you similarly use numbers.
但是现在这些指的是它们的相对位置，位置0，
But now those are referring to their relative positions, position 0,
位置1，位置2。
position 1, position 2.
这是空格总数。
This is the total number of spaces.
这是第一个，第二个和第三个特定的空间。
This is the specific space first, second, and third.
好吧，从图片上看，什么都没有改变，
All right, so pictorially, nothing has changed,
只是我们的命名法真正拥有的。
just our nomenclature really has.
因此，让我着手开始改进此程序，
So let me go ahead and start to improve this program,
接受关于如何改进设计的建议
taking in the advice that was offered too on how we can improve the design
并摆脱它的臭味。
and get rid of the smelliness of it.
我先来-
Let me take the first--
让我采取这些方法中最简单的方法
let me take the easiest of these approaches
首先要摆脱这三个独立的变量
first by just getting rid of these three separate variables
而是给我一个变量，称为分数，大小为3的数组。
and instead giving me one variable called scores, an array of size 3.
然后，我不需要声明score1，score2。
And then I don't need to declare score1, score2.
再说一次，一切都消失了。
Again, that's all going away.
这一切都消失了。
That's all going away.
现在，如果我要使用这三个值初始化该数组，
Now if I want to initialize that array with these three values,
我说分数[0]。
I say scores[0].
在这里，我说分数[1]。
And down here, I say scores[1].
在这里，我说分数[2]。
And down here, I say scores[2].
因此，我添加了一行代码。
So I've added one line of code.
但是现在请注意动态性。
But notice the dynamism now.
如果我想有第四个，我可以在这里分配，然后
If I want to have a fourth one, I can just allocate here and then
用另一行代码或5、6、7或8输入值。
put in the value with another line of code, or 5, or 6, or 7, or 8.
我不必开始复制和粘贴
I don't have to start copying and pasting
按照惯例，所有这些不同的变量名。
all of these different variable names by convention.
但是我认为，如果我们接受刚才提供的一些建议，
But I think if we take some of the advice that was offered a moment ago,
我们也可以通过循环或类似的方式来清理它。
we can also clean this up by way of a loop or such as well.
因此，让我们做到这一点。
So let's do that.
让我继续，首先给我自己，首先是CS50库，
Let me go ahead and give myself, actually, first the CS50 library so
我可以使用get_int。
that I can use get_int.
让我们采纳第一条建议，那就是，
And let's take this first piece of advice, which is,
让我们开始使用get_int要求得分。
let's start asking for a score using get_int.
我将做三遍。
And I'm going to do this three times.
是的，我有点懒了。
And yeah, I'm getting a little lazy.
我已经有点无聊了。
I'm getting a little bored already.
所以我要复制/粘贴。
So I'm going to copy/paste.
再说一次，这预示着总体上不好。
And again, that does not bode well in general.
复制和粘贴时，我们可能还会做得更好。
When copying and pasting, we can probably do better still.
但是现在我想我只需要在这里更改另一件事。
But now I think I need to change just one more thing here.
在进行数学运算时，我想要分数[0]加分数[1]加分数[2]。
When doing the math, I want scores[0] plus scores[1] plus scores[2].
但是在我解决这个问题之前-逻辑仍然是一样的，
But before I solve this problem here-- the logic is still the same,
但我现在要动态地输入三个整数
but I'm now taking in dynamically three integers--
仍然有一种气味。
there's still a smell to it as well.
它仍然没有很好的设计。
It's still not as well designed.
因此，为了明确起见，我现在能做得更好吗？
And so just to make clear, what could I do be doing better now?
我如何清理此代码，并使其不仅正确，而且不仅仅如此
How could I clean up this code and make it not just correct, not just
风格不错，但设计更好？
well styled, but better designed?
这里还剩下什么？
What remains here?
妮娜
Nina?
你怎么认为？
What do you think?
NINA：该代码仅针对三个分数。
NINA: The code is specific for only three scores.
所以您可以作为输入，[听不清]多少分数
So you could, as an input, [INAUDIBLE] how many scores
它在一开始就想要。
it wants at the very beginning.
然后，得分为[1]，而不是得分为[0]，
And then instead of having scores[0], scores[1],
您可以使用从0到n减去1或更少的for循环
you could use a for loop that goes through from 0 to n minus 1 or less
比将要询问的n，应改为一行代码。
than n that will ask, and it should be one line of code instead.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，非常好。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, really good.
这就是我们拥有get_int，get_int，get_int的事实。
It's the fact that we have get_int, get_int, get_int.
这是您可能做得不太理想的第一个迹象。
That's the first sign that you're probably doing something suboptimally.
可能是正确的，但设计可能不正确
It might be correct, but it's probably not well designed
因为我确实从字面上复制/粘贴。
because I did literally resort to copy/paste.
我肯定可以在这里找到一种模式
There's sort of a pattern here that I could certainly
集成到一个循环中。
integrate into something like a loop.
所以，让我这样做。
So let me do that.
实际上，让我摆脱其中的两行代码。
Let me actually get rid of two of these lines of code.
让我上到这里做类似int的事情，我现在得到0，现在我还不到3，
Let me go up here and do something like for int i get 0, i less than 3 for now,
我++。
i++.
让我打开这个for循环。
Let me open up this for loop.
让我缩进剩下的代码行。
Let me indent that remaining line of code.
而不是分数[0]-
And instead of scores[0]--
这是阵列变得真正强大的地方-
this is where arrays get really powerful--
您可以使用变量来索引数组-
you can use a variable to index into an array--
即去一个特定的位置。
that is, to go to a specific location.
我要为变量使用什么？
What do I want to use for my variable?
好吧，我想我在这里。
Well, I would think i here.
因此，现在我将代码行从所有三个一式三份减少到三个
So now I've whittled my lines of code down from all three triplicate, three
几乎完全相同的行，实际上是
nearly identical lines, into just one really
在一个循环中，它将一次又一次地为我做同样的事情。
inside of a loop that's going to do the same thing for me again and again.
而且正如Nina所提议的那样，我不必硬编码
And as Nina proposed too, I don't have to hard code
这3个到处都是。
these 3's all over the place.
也许我可以做这样的事情。
Maybe I could do something like this.
我可以说类似，int total获得get_int。
I could say something like, int total gets get_int.
我可能会问，“总分数”。
And I might ask, "Total number of scores."
我可以从一开始就问人类
And I could literally ask the human from the get-go
有多少总成绩。
how many total scores are there.
然后，我甚至可以在多个地方更强大地使用此变量total
Then I can even more powerfully use this variable, total, in multiple places
这样，我现在可以更加动态地进行数学运算。
so that now, I'm doing my math much more dynamically.
但是，我怕，妮娜，这有点破裂了。
This, though-- I'm afraid, Nina, this broke a bit.
我要多一点-
I'm going to be a little more--
我需要在第14行上付出更多的努力，因为现在我
I need to exert a little more effort here on line 14 because now I
不能对分数[0]，[1]和[2]进行硬编码，因为如果分数总数
can't hard code scores[0], [1], and [2] because if the total number of scores
不仅如此，我还需要做更多的事情。
is more than that, I need to do more addition.
如果少于这个数，那么我需要做的加法运算就更少了。
If it's fewer than that, I need to do less addition.
因此，我认为我们已经引入了一个错误，但是我们可以修复该错误。
So I think we've introduced a bug, but we can fix that.
但是，让我提议一会。
But let me propose for just a moment.
我们不要让它充满活力，因为我担心那只会使我的生活更加艰难。
Let's not make it dynamic because I worry that's just made my life harder.
让我们至少在这里首先介绍另一个功能。
Let's at least introduce one other feature here first.
我将继续在这里定义C的新功能，该功能
I'm going to go ahead up here and define a new feature of C today, which
被称为常数。
is known as a constant.
如果我事先知道我想声明一个我想要的数字
If I know in advance that I want to declare a number that I want
一次又一次地使用而无需复制和粘贴
to use again and again and again without copying and pasting
字面上的数字3，我可以给自己一个常数int
literally that number 3, I can give myself a constant int
由const int total = 3。
by a const int total = 3.
这声明了编程中所谓的常量，
This declares what's called a constant in programming,
这是许多语言的功能，您可以在其中声明各种变量
which is a feature of many languages whereby you declare a variable of sorts
其价值永远不会改变。
whose value can never change.
设置后，将无法更改。
Once you set it, you cannot change it.
那是一件好事，因为它不应该
And that's a good thing because, one, it shouldn't
在此程序的上下文中进行更改。
change in the context of this program.
还有两个，以防万一您（人类）容易犯错，
And two, just in case you, the human, are fallible,
您不想在不想要的时候不小心更改它。
you don't want to accidentally change it when you don't intend.
这是编程语言的功能
So this is a feature of a programming language
这样的保护可以保护您免受自己的伤害。
that sort of protects you from yourself.
所以现在我可以将自己的本能和Nina融合在一起，并使用
So now I can sort of take an amalgam of my instincts and Nina's and use
这个变量，总计。
this variable, total.
实际上，在声明常量时的另一种约定
And actually, another convention when declaring constants
是要大写它们只是为了使视觉上清楚地知道
is to capitalize them just to make visually clear that there's
关于此变量的某些不同或特殊之处。
something different or special about this variable.
所以我将其更改为TOTAL，并在这里使用该值
So I'm going to change this to TOTAL, and I'm going to use that value here
在这里，在这里
and here and also down here.
但是我怕Nina和我都要做一些清理工作
But I'm afraid both Nina and I have a little bit of cleanup here to do
因为我仍然有硬编码的分数[0]，分数[1]和分数[2]。
in that I still have hard coded scores[0], scores[1], and scores[2].
我想将数量不断变化的值加在一起。
And I want to add a changing number of values together.
那你知道吗？
So you know what?
我有一个主意。
I've got an idea.
让我继续创建一个
Let me go ahead and create a function that's
为我计算一个平均值。
going to compute an average for me.
因此，如果我想创建自己的计算平均值的函数，
So if I want to create my own function that computes an average,
我希望它返回一个浮点值，
I want it to return a floating point value,
只是为了避免截断任何数学运算。
just so that we don't truncate any math.
我将其称为平均值。
I'm going to call this average.
这个函数的输入将是长度
And the input to this function is going to be the length
数组和实际数组的关系。
of an array and the actual array.
这是目前为止时髦的语法的最后一部分。
And this is the last piece of funky syntax for now.
事实证明，当您要将数组作为输入传递给自定义函数时，
It turns out that when you want to pass an array as input to a custom function,
您实际上再次使用了这些方括号，但未指定大小。
you literally use those square brackets again, but you don't specify the size.
这样做的好处是
And the upside of this is that your function then
可以支持其中有一个空格，两个空格，三个空格的数组
can support an array that's got one space in it, two spaces, three,
一百。
a hundred.
这样更动态。
It's more dynamic this way.
那么，如何在这里计算平均值？
So how do I compute an average here?
我可以通过几种不同的方式来做到这一点。
I can do this a few different ways.
但是我认为早先的建议使
But I think what was suggested earlier makes
感觉上，我可以进行某种总结。
sense, where I can do some kind of summation.
所以让我做int sum = 0。
So let me do int sum = 0.
因为您如何计算一堆数字的平均值？
Because how do you compute the average of a bunch of numbers?
好吧，您将它们全部加在一起，然后除以总数。
Well, you add them all together, and you divide by the total.
好吧，让我们看看我该怎么做。
Well, let's see how I might do that.
让我做一下，我得到0，而我小于-
Let me do for int i gets 0, i less than--
这应该是什么？
what should this be?
好吧，如果我作为自定义函数传递数组的长度
Well, if I'm being passed as this custom function the length of the array
和实际的数组，我想我可以从头到尾进行迭代，
and the actual array, I think I can iterate from i up to length,
然后在每次迭代中使用i ++。
and then i++ on each iteration.
然后在每次迭代中，我想
And then on each iteration, I think I want
求和，再加上数组第i个位置中的任何值，可以这么说。
to do sum plus whatever is in the array's i-th location, so to speak.
同样，这是上周为此的简写形式。
So again, this is shorthand notation per last week for this.
总和等于任意总和加上数组i中的任意位置。
Sum equals whatever sum is plus whatever is in location i of the array.
当我完成所有这些操作后，我想
And once I've done all of that, I think what
我可以做的是返回总和除以数组的长度。
I can do is return the total sum divided by the length of the array.
我喜欢整个方法，假设我的代码是正确的，
And what I like about this whole approach-- assuming my code's correct,
而且我认为这还不是-请注意我可以做的主要工作。
and I don't think it is just yet-- notice what I can do back up in main.
现在我可以抽象出计算平均值的概念
Now I can abstract away the notion of calculating an average
并在此处使用此行代码执行类似的操作。
and just do something like this with this line of code here.
那我刚才做了什么？
So what did I just do?
发生了很多事情，但让我们在这里重点关注第14行。
A lot's going on, but let's focus for a moment on line 14 here.
在第14行，我仍然只是打印一些浮点数的平均值
On line 14, I'm still just printing the average of some floating point
占位符。
placeholder.
但是我现在作为输入传递的是这个函数，平均值，
But what I'm passing as input now is this function, average,
其输入将为TOTAL，这又仅仅是
whose inputs are going to be TOTAL, which again is just
最上层的这个常数-哦，对不起，我真讨厌。
this constant at the very top-- oh, sorry, I goofed.
我应该大写它，这在最上面就是那个常数。
I should have capitalized it, which is just that constant at the very top.
我在传递分数，同样，这只是
And I'm passing in scores, which again, is just
所有这些分数的数组。
this array of all of those scores.
同时，在函数中，在函数的上下文中，
Meanwhile, in the function, in the context of the function,
请注意，函数输入的名称
notice that the names of the inputs to a function
不需要匹配所要变量的名称
do not need to match the names of the variables being
传递给该函数。
passed into that function.
因此，即使总的来说，它们被称为TOTAL和得分，
So even though in main, they're called TOTAL and scores,
在我的职能范围内，平均而言，
in the context of my function, average, I
可以将它们称为x和y，a和b，或更笼统地说是长度和数组。
can call them x and y, a and b, or more generically, length and array.
我不知道数组是什么，但这是一个整数数组。
I don't know what the array is, but it's an array of ints.
我不知道它有多长，但是答案将是冗长的。
And I don't know how long it is, but that answer is going to be in length.
但是这里仍然有一个错误。
But there's still a bug here.
仍然有一个错误。
There's still a bug.
如果暂时忽略main，这是一个微妙的问题。
And if we ignore main for a moment, this is a subtle one.
有没有人看到我第三次犯的错误
Does anyone see a mistake that I've made probably for the third time
现在过去两个星期了吗？
now over the past two weeks?
我在这里用代码做了什么细微的错误
What mistake subtle have I made here with my code
仅在这种平均功能下？
only in this average function?
这有点微妙。
This one's a little more subtle.
但目标是计算整堆整数的平均值
But the goal is to compute the average of a whole bunch of integers
并返回答案。
and return the answer.
尼古拉斯？
Nicholas?
NICHOLAS：您已经在函数中声明了变量。
NICHOLAS: You've declared the variable within the function.
DAVID MALAN：我已经在函数中声明了变量。
DAVID MALAN: I've declared the variable within the function.
可以，因为我在这里声明了变量和，我想你的意思是。
That's OK because I've declared my variable sum here, I think you mean.
但这在平均功能之内。
But that's inside of the average function.
我在最外面的花括号内使用sum
And I'm using sum inside of the outermost curly braces
那是定义的。
that was defined.
这样就可以了。
And so that's OK.
没关系。
That's OK.
让我们在这里再考虑一下。
Let's take another thought here.
奥利维亚（Olivia），该错误可能还会出现在哪里？
Olivia, where might the bug still be?
OLIVIA：返回类型是浮点数，但是你是
OLIVIA: The return type's a float, but you're
返回一个整数除以一个整数。
returning an int divided by an int.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：完美。
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
所以我又犯了同样的愚蠢错误
So I again made that same stupid mistake that's
随着时间的流逝会越来越明显
just going to get more obvious as time goes on
如果我想做浮点运算，就像阿丽亚娜火箭一样
that if I want to do floating point arithmetic, just like the Ariane rocket
讨论，爱国者导弹-诸如此类的细节
discussion, the Patriot missile-- like, these kinds of details
程序中的问题。
matter in a program.
现在是正确的，因为我实际上要去
Now it's correct because I'm actually going
确保即使此处的上下文
to ensure that even though the context here
比现实世界中的重要得多，
is much less important than those real-world contexts,
只是计算分数的平均值，我不会意外地截断
just computing some average of scores, I'm not going to accidentally truncate
我的任何价值观。
any of my values.
同样，在此功能的上下文中，
So again, in the context here of this function,
平均而言，这只是应用上周的一些原则。
average is just applying some of last week's principles.
我有一个变量。
I've got a variable.
我有一个循环。
I've got a loop.
最终，我正在做一些浮点运算。
And I'm doing some floating point arithmetic, ultimately.
现在，我正在创建一个接受两个输入的函数。
And I'm now creating a function that takes two inputs.
一个是长度，一个是长度-
One is length, and one is the length--
一个是数组本身，另一个是返回类型，正如Olivia指出的那样，
one is the array itself, and the return type, as Olivia notes,
是一个浮点数，因此我的输出也得到了很好的定义。
is a float so that my output is also well defined.
但是，这又是一件好事，
But what's nice about this is, again, you
可以将这些功能视为抽象。
can think of these functions as abstractions.
现在，我不必担心如何计算平均值，因为我现在
Now I don't need to worry about how I calculate an average because I now
具有此帮助功能，自定义功能
have this helper function, a custom function
我写的那可以帮助我回答这个问题。
I wrote that can help me answer that question.
在这里，请注意该平均值函数的输出
And here, notice that the output of this average function
将成为printf的输入。
will become an input into printf.
我在这里添加到混合中的唯一其他功能
And the only other feature I've added to the mix here
现在不仅是数组，这使我们能够创建
now are not only arrays, which allow us to create
多个变量，可变数量的变量，如果您愿意，
multiple variables, a variable number of variables, if you will,
而且这个常数的概念。
but also this notion of a constant.
如果我发现自己一次又一次地使用相同的数字，
If I find myself using the same number again and again and again,
这个常数可以帮助我保持代码干净。
this constant can help me keep my code clean.
并注意这一点。
And notice this.
如果明年（也许是另一个学期）有四个分数或四个测试，
If next year, maybe another semester, there's four scores or four tests,
我在一处更改。
I change it in one place.
我重新编译。
I recompile.
繁荣，我完成了。
Boom, I'm done.
精心设计的程序不需要您
A well-designed program does not require that you
仔细阅读全文，在此固定数字，在此固定数字。
go reading through the entirety of it, fixing numbers here, numbers there.
在一处更改它可以使我改进此程序，
Changing it in one place can allow me to improve this program,
使其明年支持四个测试，而不仅仅是三个。
make it support four tests next year instead of just the three.
但我认为最好还是采取
But better still would be to take, I think,
尼娜之前的建议，也许只是使用get_int并问人类
Nina's advice before, which was to maybe just use get_int and ask the human
他们实际有多少测试。
for how many tests they actually have.
那也行得通。
That too would work.
好吧，让我在这里暂停一下，看看是否有
Well, let me pause here to see if there's
关于数组或常量的任何问题
any questions then about arrays or about constants
或以这种方式将它们作为输入和输出传递。
or passing them around as inputs and outputs in this way.
是的，交给索菲娅。
Yeah, over to Sophia.
SOPHIA：我对使用浮点数以及为什么使用一个浮点数有疑问
SOPHIA: I had question about the use of float and why the use of one float
使整个输出为浮点型。
causes the whole output to be a float.
为什么会发生这种情况？
Why does that occur?
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，这是一个很好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, really good question.
这就是C的行为方式。
That's just how C behaves.
只要涉及一个或多个浮点值
So long as there is one or more floating point values involved
在数学公式中，它将使用该数据类型，
in a mathematical formula, it is going to use that data type, which
如果愿意的话，它是功能更强大的工具，而不是冒着被截断的风险。
is the more powerful one, if you will, rather than risk truncating anything.
所以你只需要一个花车就可以参加
So you just need one float to be participating
在有关公式中。
in the formula in question.
好问题。
Good question.
关于数组或常量的其他问题，或者它们的传递？
Other questions on arrays or constants or this passing around of them?
是的，到亚历山德拉。
Yeah, over to Alexandra.
亚历山德拉：我对数组的声明，分数有疑问。
ALEXANDRA: I have a question about the declaring of the array, scores.
当您在main中声明它时，您说的是int分数。
When you declared it in main, you said int scores.
在方括号中，您有TOTAL。
And in the brackets, you have TOTAL.
您能在没有TOTAL的情况下声明它吗？
Can you declare it without the TOTAL--
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：很好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
亚历山德拉：-仅是括号？
ALEXANDRA: --only the brackets?
DAVID MALAN：简短的回答，不。
DAVID MALAN: Short answer, no.
所以我做到的方式就是您要做的方式。
So the way I did it is the way you do have to do it.
实际上，如果我强调我在这里所做的事情，那么现在它表示的是TOTAL。
And in fact, if I highlight what I did here, now it currently says TOTAL.
如果我摆脱了这一点，我会回到第一个版本，我说
If I get rid of that, and I go back to our first version where I said
像3、3和3这样的东西，您不能这样做，我认为，
something like 3 and 3 and 3 over here, you cannot do this, which I think,
亚历山德拉（Alexandra），是您的建议。
Alexandra, is what you were proposing.
创建阵列时，计算机需要知道阵列的大小。
The computer needs to know how big the array is when you are creating it.
唯一的例外是当您
The exception to that is that when you're
将数组从一个函数传递给另一个函数，
passing an array from one function to another,
您无需告诉该自定义功能
you do not need to tell that custom function
数组有多大，因为同样，您事先也不知道。
how big the array is because, again, you don't know in advance.
您正在编写一个相当通用的动态函数，其作用是实现生命
You're writing a fairly generic, dynamic function whose purpose in life
将任何数组作为整数和任意长度的输入
is to take any array as input of integers and any length
并相应地以与该事物的大小相匹配的平均值进行响应。
and respond accordingly with an average that matches the size of that thing.
顺便提一下，你们当中那些曾经编程的人，尤其是在Java中，
And those of you, as an aside, who have programmed before, especially in Java,
与Java和某些其他语言不同，数组的长度
unlike in Java and certain other languages, the length of an array
没有内置到数组本身中。
is not built into the array itself.
如果您没有将数组的长度传递给另一个函数，
If you do not pass in the length of an array to another function,
无法确定数组的大小。
there is no way to determine how big the array is.
这不同于Java和其他语言，
This is different from Java and other languages,
从某种意义上讲，您可以在哪里询问数组的长度。
where you can ask the array, in some sense, what is its length.
在C语言中，您必须同时传递两个数组
In C, you have to pass both the array itself
和它的长度分开。 [？新浪吗？]
and its length around separately. [? Sina? ?]
[？新浪：？]我只是-我对如何做还有些困惑，
[? SINA: ?] I just-- I'm still a little bit confused about how,
当我们编写第二个命令时，括号中的内容何时无效？
when we write that second command, when is it void in the parentheses?
以及何时定义int？
And when do we define the int?
因为正如我记得我们做的那样-
Because as I remember when we did the--
得到一个负数，我们得到一个正数，它是无效的，
get a negative number, we get a positive number, it was void,
但是我们还是给了它一些输入。
but we still kind of gave it an input.
我只是没有被完全卖掉。
I'm just not completely sold on that.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的，很好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Sure, good question.
让我继续打开前面的示例，
Let me go ahead and open up that previous example,
这是一个小问题，但是在这里它具有正确的语法。
which was a little buggy, but it has the right syntax here.
因此，这是之前的get_negative_int函数。
So here was the get_negative_int function from before.
和， [？新浪，？]，您知道输入的内容无效。
And, [? Sina, ?] you know it was void as input.
因此，您发表了一条评论，仍然需要输入。
So there was one comment you made where it still took input.
事实并非如此。
That was not so.
因此get_negative_int没有接受任何输入。
So get_negative_int did not take any input.
举例来说，如果我们向上滚动到main，
And case in point, if we scroll up to main,
请注意，当我在第10行调用它时，我
notice that when I called it on line 10, I
get_negative_int表示，右括号，右括号，
said get_negative_int, open parenthesis, close parenthesis,
这些括号内没有任何输入。
with no inputs inside of those parentheses.
这个关键字“ void”，上周我们已经见过几次了
This keyword "void," which we've seen a few times now last week
而本周，这只是C语言中的一个显式关键字，
and this week, is just an explicit keyword in C that says,
不要在这里放任何东西，也就是说，对我来说这是不正确的
do not put anything here, which is to say, it would be incorrect for me up
在这里做这样的事情，喜欢传递数字，
here to do something like this, like to pass in a number,
或传递提示或括号内的任何内容。
or to pass in a prompt, or anything inside of those parentheses.
事实上，此函数get_negative_int
The fact that this function, get_negative_int
将void作为其输入意味着它不接受任何输入。
takes void as its input means it does not take any inputs whatsoever.
没关系。
That's fine.
对于get_negative_int，函数的名称说明了一切。
For get_negative_int, the name of the function says it all.
就像，不需要参数化或自定义
Like, there's no need to parameterize or customize
获得负int本身的行为。
the behavior of getting negative int itself.
您只想得到一个负整数。
You just want to get a negative int.
相反，尽管如此，我们刚刚编写的函数
By contrast, though, with the function we just wrote,
平均而言，此功能确实具有接受输入的概念意义，
average, this function does make conceptual sense to take inputs,
因为你不能只说，给我平均值。
because you can't just say, give me the average.
喜欢，平均水平是多少？
Like, average of what?
就像，它需要接受输入才能为您回答该问题。
Like, it needs to take input so as to answer that question for you.
在这种情况下，输入是数字数组本身
And the input, in this case, is the array itself of numbers
以及该数组的长度，以便您可以进行算术运算。
and the length of that array so you can do the arithmetic.
所以， [？希望可以帮助我们做出区分。
And so, [? Sina, ?] hopefully, that helps make the distinction.
当您不想接受输入时，可以使用void。
You use void when you don't want to take input.
您实际上指定了逗号分隔的参数列表
And you actually specify a comma-separated list of arguments
当您确实想接受输入时。
when you do want to take input.
好吧，所以到目前为止，我们确实专注于整数。
All right, so we focused up until now on integers, really.
但是让我们简化一下，因为事实证明
But let's simplify a little bit because it turns out
数组和内存实际上相交
that arrays and memory actually intersect
创建大多数任何计算机程序的一些非常熟悉的功能，即
to create some very familiar features of most any computer program, namely
文本或字符串更一般。
text or strings more generally.
因此，假设我们进一步简化了，没有更多的整数，没有更多的整数数组。
So suppose we simplify further, no more integers, no more arrays of integers.
让我们从一个字符开始片刻
Let's just start for a moment with a single character
并编写一个程序，可以从该马里奥游戏中创建单个积木。
and write a program that just creates a single brick from that Mario game.
让我继续在这里创建一个名为brick.c的程序。
Let me go ahead and create a program here called brick.c.
在brick.c中，我要去#include
And in brick.c, I'm just going to #include
stdio.h，int main（void）还有更多关于此void的信息，请稍后再讨论。
stdio.h, int main(void) And more on this void a little later today.
字符c得到，用引号引起来，“＃”。
Char c gets, quote unquote, '#'.
然后在这里，让我继续简单地打印一个占位符，
And then down here, let me just go ahead and print very simply a placeholder,
％c，反斜杠n，然后输出c。
%c, backslash n, and then output c.
因此，这是一个非常愚蠢的程序。
So this is a pretty stupid program.
它的唯一目的是打印单个哈希
Its sole purpose in life is to print a single hash
正如您可能在高度为1的马里奥金字塔中所看到的那样，非常简单。
as you might have in a Mario pyramid of height 1, so very simple.
让我继续做砖头。
Let me go ahead and make brick.
看来编译OK了。
It seems to compile OK.
让我用./brick运行它。
Let me run it with ./brick.
瞧，我们得到了一块砖。
And voila, we get a single brick.
但是，让我们考虑一下这里到底发生了什么
But let's consider for just a moment exactly what just happened here
引擎盖下到底发生了什么
and what actually was going on underneath the hood.
好吧，你知道吗？
Well, you know what?
我很好奇
I'm kind of curious.
我记得从上周开始，我们可以将价值从一件事投射到另一件事。
I remember from last week, we could cast values from one thing to another.
如果我有点好奇，但我没有打印出c，该怎么办？
What if I got a little curious, and I didn't print out c,
哪个哈希字符（如％c）是字符的占位符？
which is this hash character, as %c, which is a placeholder for a character?
如果我有点发疯说％i怎么办？
What if I got a little crazy and said %i?
我想我可以通过将其转换为int来强制转换此char
I think I could probably coerce this char by casting it to an int
所以我可以看到它的十进制等值
so I can see its decimal equivalent.
我可以看到它的实际ASCII码。
I could see its actual ASCII code.
因此，让我用制砖块对其进行重建。
So let me rebuild this with make brick.
现在让我做./brick。
Now let me do ./brick.
我们会看到多少个数字？
And what number might we see?
上周，我们看到“ HI！”的数量很多，分别为72和73和33。
Last week, we saw 72 a lot, 73, and 33 for "HI!"
这周，您可以看到35。
This week, you can see 35.
事实证明，这是代码和ASCII哈希。
It turns out it's the code for and an ASCII hash.
例如，如果我访问的网站是-
And you can see this, for instance, if I go to a website like--
让我们去asciichart.com。
let's go to asciichart.com.
可以肯定的是，如果我去上周的同一张图表，
And sure enough, if I go to the same chart from last week,
我在这里寻找井号，它的ASCII码是35。
and I look for the hash symbol here, its ASCII code is 35.
事实证明，在C语言中，它对于计算机而言非常简单
And it turns out, in C, if it's pretty straightforward to the computer
那是的，如果这是一个字符，我知道我可以将其转换为int，
that, yes, if this is a character, I know I can convert it to an int,
您不必显式转换它。
you don't have to explicitly cast it.
您可以只在上下文中将一种数据类型隐式转换为另一种数据类型。
You can instead implicitly cast one data type to another just from context here.
所以printf和C在这里足够聪明，知道，你在给我
So printf and C are smart enough here to know, OK, you're giving me
变量c形式的字符。
a character in the form of variable c.
但是您想将其显示为％i（整数）。
But you want to display it as a %i, an integer.
没关系。
That's going to be OK.
确实，我仍然看到数字35。
And indeed, I still see the number 35.
所以这只是简单的转换。
So that's just simple casting.
但是，现在让我们将其放在今天的图片中。
But let's now put this into the context of today's picture.
这个角色如何布置？
How is that character laid out?
好吧，很简单，如果这是我的记忆，
Well, quite simply, if this is my memory again,
我们已经摆脱了所有的数字，
and we've gotten rid of all of the numbers, c,
否则，存储此散列的数据只是存储在这些字节之一中。
otherwise storing this hash, is just being stored in one of these bytes.
它仅需要一个平方，因为同样，char是一个字节。
It only requires one square because, again, a char is a single byte.
但等效地，35是实际存储在此处的数字。
But equivalently, 35 is the number that's actually being stored there.
但是我想知道，我想知道。
But I wonder, I wonder.
上周，我们花了很多时间来存储
Last week, we spent quite a bit of time storing
不仅是单个字符，还包括诸如“ hi”和其他表达式之类的实际单词。
not just single characters, but actual words like "hi" and other expressions.
那如果我要做这样的事情怎么办？
And so what if I were to do something like this?
让我回到我的代码。
Let me go back to my code.
让我还不练习我刚才讲的话。
And let me not quite yet practice what I just preached.
这次让我给自己三个变量-c1，c2和c3。
And let me give myself three variables this time-- c1, c2, and c3.
让我故意将这三个变量H，I大写，
And let me deliberately store in those three variables H, I, in all caps,
其次是感叹号。
followed by an exclamation point.
在上周，当您处理单个角色时，
And per last week, when you're dealing with individual characters,
您必须在C语言中使用单引号。
you must, in C, use single quotes.
当您处理多个字符时，
When you're dealing with multiple characters,
否则上周称为字符串，请使用双引号。
otherwise known last week as strings, use double quotes.
但这就是为什么我使用单引号，因为我们只是在玩
But that's why I'm using single quotes, because we're only playing
目前只有单个字符。
at the moment with single characters.
现在让我继续打印这些值。
Now let me go ahead and print these values out.
让我打印出％c，％c，％c，并输出c1，c2，c3。
Let me print out %c, %c, %c, and output c1, c2, c3.
因此，这也许是最愚蠢的方式，您可以打印出一个完整的单词，例如“ HI！”。
So this is perhaps the stupidest way you could print out a full word like "HI!"
在C中，通过将每个单个字符存储在其自己的变量中，但事实并非如此。
in C by storing every single character in its own variable, but so be it.
我只是在这里使用这些首要原则。
I'm just using these first principles here.
我使用％c作为占位符。
I'm using %c as my placeholder.
我正在打印这些字符。
I'm printing out these characters.
所以，现在让我做砖。
So let me do make brick now.
编译确定。
Compiles OK.
如果我做点斜线-
And if I do a dot slash--
你知道，我真的应该重命名了这个文件，
you know, I really should have renamed this file,
但我们稍后会重命名-
but we'll rename it in a moment--
./brick，“嗨！”
./brick, "HI!"
让我继续执行此操作。
And let me go ahead and do this.
现在让我继续并实际上关闭文件。
Let me go ahead now and actually close the file.
回想一下上周，如果我想从brick.c重命名我的文件，
And recall from last week, if I want to rename my file from brick.c,
假设，要访问hi.c，我可以使用move命令mv。
let's say, to hi.c, I can use the move command, mv.
现在，如果我打开此文件，可以肯定的是，有hi.c。
And now if I open up this file, sure enough, there's hi.c.
而且我更正了我的重命名错误。
And I've fixed my renaming mistake.
好吧，再说一次，如果我现在打个招呼，我也打个招呼。
All right, so again, if I now do make hi, and I do ./hi, voila,
我看到“嗨！”
I see the "HI!"
但是，这又是一种愚蠢的实现字符串的方式。
But again, this is kind of a stupid way of implementing a string.
但是，让我们仍然在引擎盖下看。
But let's still look underneath the hood.
让我继续好奇。
Let me go ahead and get curious.
让我打印％i，％i和％i。
Let me print out %i, %i, and %i.
这次让我包括空格
And Let me include spaces this time just so I
可以看到数字之间的分隔。
can see separation between the numbers.
让我再打个招呼，。/ hi。
Let me make hi again, ./hi.
好，那是72。
OK, there's that 72.
就是73。
There's that 73.
上周有33个。
And there's that 33 from last week.
所以这也很有趣。
So that's interesting too.
那么，计算机内存的底层到底是怎么回事？
So what's going on underneath the hood in the computer's memory?
好吧，当我存储这三个字符时，
Well, when I'm storing these three characters,
现在我只是将它们存储在三个不同的盒子中，所以c1，c2，c3。
now I'm just storing them in three different boxes, so c1, c2, c3.
当您集体看时，它看起来像是一个完整的词
And when you look at it collectively, it kind of looks like a whole word
即使是这些字符，当然也是如此。
even though it's, of course, just these individual characters.
因此，引擎盖下面是72、73、33。
So what's underneath the hood, of course, though, is 72, 73, 33.
或等效地，以二进制形式表示。
Or equivalently, in binary, just this.
所以故事是一样的，即使我们现在正在谈论
So the story is the same even though we're now talking
关于字符而不是整数。
about chars instead of integers.
但是，当我这样做时会发生什么呢？
But what happens when I do this?
当我执行字符串s时，如果不加引号，“ HI！”，会发生什么情况？
What happens when I do string s gets, quote unquote, "HI!"
使用双引号？
using double quotes?
好吧，让我们相应地更改此程序。
Well, let's change this program accordingly.
让我继续做上周要做的事情，
Let me go ahead and do what we would have done last week, string--
我称它为s代表字符串-
I'll call it s just for s for string--
“你好！”
"HI!"
大写。
in all caps.
我可以简化下一行。
I can simplify this next line.
我将使用％s作为字符串s的占位符。
I'm going to use %s as a placeholder for string s.
但是，现在让我们来揭示一个真正的字符串
But let's, for now, reveal what a string really
是，因为弦是艺术术语。
is, because string is a term of art.
每种编程语言都有“字符串”，即使在技术上没有
Every programming language has "strings" even if it doesn't technically
具有称为字符串的数据类型。
have a data type called string.
从技术上讲，C没有称为字符串的数据类型。
C does not technically have a data type called string.
我们通过CS50的库将此类型添加到了C中。
We have added this type to C by way of CS50's library.
但是现在，如果我打招呼，请注意我的代码可以编译。
But now if I do make hi, notice that my code compiles OK.
如果我按./hi Enter，瞧，我仍然看到“ HI！”，
And if I do ./hi Enter, voila, I still see "HI!",
这也是我上周也会看到的。
which is what I would have seen last week as well.
如果我们在计算机的内存中描述这一点，那是因为“嗨！”是三个字母，
And if we depict this in the computer's memory, because "HI!" is three letters,
就像在说，好吧，给我三个盒子，
it's kind of like saying, well, give me three boxes,
让我称这个字符串为s。
and let me call this string s.
所以这感觉像是一个合理的艺术家的演绎
So this feels like a reasonable artist's rendition
如果它存储的是三个字母的单词，例如“ HI！”，它是什么
of what s is if it's storing a three-letter word like "HI!"
但是任何时候我们都有这样的字符序列，
But any time we have sequences of characters like this,
我觉得我们现在正在看到适当编程的能力
I feel like we're now seeing the capability of a proper programming
语言。
language.
之前我们介绍了字符串的概念。
We introduced a little bit ago the notion of a string.
所以也许有人可以像我们一样重新定义字符串
So maybe could someone redefine string as we've
根据今天的一些术语使用它吗？
been using it in terms of some of today's nomenclature?
就像什么是字符串？
Like, what is a string?
有一个例子“ HI！”，它占用了三个盒子。
There's an example of one, "HI!", taking up three boxes.
但是我们CS50可能是如何在引擎盖下实现字符串的呢？
But how did we, CS50 maybe implement string underneath the hood,
你可以说？
would you say?
它是什么？
What is it?
塔克？
Tucker?
TUCKER：嗯，它是一个由字符和整数组成的数组。
TUCKER: Well, it's an array of characters and integers.
好吧，字符串中使用了整数，
Well, it's integers are used in the string,
但这是一个基本由单个字符组成的数组。
but it's an array of basically single characters.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：完美。
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
如果我们现在有能力表达-
If we now have the ability to express--
塔克，做得非常好。
very nicely done, Tucker.
如果我们现在能够表示事物序列，整数，
If we now have the ability to represent sequences of things, integers,
例如，像乐谱一样
for instance, like scores, well, it stands
导致我们可以采用另一种原始数据，一种非常基本的数据类型
to reason that we can take another primitive, a very basic data type
像个字符。
like a char.
如果我们想用这些字符拼写东西，例如英语单词，
And if we want to spell things with those chars, like English words,
好吧，让我们将字符串真正视为一个数组
well, let's just think of a string really as an array
字符，一个字符数组。
of characters, an array of chars.
确实，这实际上就是字符串。
And indeed, that's exactly what string actually is.
因此，从技术上来说，这里的“ HI！”是一个名为s的数组。
So this thing here, "HI!", technically speaking is an array called s.
这是s [0]这是s [1]。
And this is s[0] This is s[1].
这是s [2]。
This is s[2].
它只是一个名为s的数组。
It's just an array called s.
现在，我们上周没有使用单词数组
Now, we didn't use the word array last week
因为它不像“文本字符串”的概念那样熟悉，
because it's not as familiar as the notion of a "string of text,"
例如。
for instance.
但是字符串显然只是一个数组。
But a string is apparently just an array.
如果它是一个数组，这意味着我们可以访问（如果需要），
And if it's an array, that means we can access, if we want to,
用方括号将该数组的各个字符
the individual characters of that array by way of the square bracket
从今天开始。
notation from today.
但事实证明，弦乐有些特殊之处
But it turns out there's something a little special about strings
在实施过程中。
as they're implemented.
回顾我们涉及分数的示例，这是唯一的方法
Recall in our example involving scores, the only way
我们知道那个数组有多久了，因为我
we knew how long that array was was because I
还有一个第二个变量，叫做length或TOTAL
had a second variable called length or TOTAL
在该数组中存储了整数的总数。
that stored the total number of integers in that array.
也就是说，在我们的分数示例中，我们不仅
That is to say in our scores example, not only did we
分配数组本身。
allocate the array itself.
我们还使用两个变量跟踪该数组中有多少东西。
We also kept track of how many things were in that array with two variables.
但是，到目前为止，每次您和我都使用printf函数时，
However, up until now, every time you and I have used the printf function,
并且我们已经将诸如s之类的字符串传递给该printf函数，
and we have passed to that printf function a string like s,
我们只为printf提供了字符串本身。
we have only provided printf with the string itself.
或者从逻辑上讲，我们只提供了printf
Or logically, we have only provided printf
与字符数组本身有关。
with the array of characters itself.
但是，以某种方式，printf神奇地计算出字符串有多长。
And yet somehow, printf is magically figuring out how long the string is.
毕竟，当printf打印s的值时，
After all, when printf prints the value of s,
它正在打印H，I，感叹号，仅此而已。
it is printing H, I, exclamation point, and that's it.
它不会打印4个字符或5或20个字符，对不对？
It's not going and printing 4 characters or 5 or 20, right?
可以肯定的是，计算机内存中还有其他内容
It stands to reason that there's other stuff in your computer's memory
如果您正在运行其他变量或其他程序。
if you've got other variables or other programs running.
但是printf似乎足够聪明，可以知道，
Yet printf seems to be smart enough to know,
给定一个数组，数组有多长，因为，很简单，它
given an array, how long the array is because, quite simply, it
只打印出那个单词。
only prints out that single word.
那么，如果所有的字符串都在，那么计算机如何知道字符串在内存中的结尾
So how then does a computer know where a string ends in memory if all a string
是一个字符序列？
is is a sequence of characters?
好吧，事实证明，如果您的字符串长度为3，那么H，I，
Well, it turns out that if your string is length 3, as is this one, H, I,
感叹号（技术上是字符串）在引擎盖下实现，
exclamation point, technically a string, implemented underneath the hood,
使用4个字节。
uses 4 bytes.
它使用4个字节。
It uses 4 bytes.
它使用第四个字节初始化为
It uses a fourth byte to be initialized to what
我们将其描述为反斜杠0，这是一种怪异的描述方式。
we would describe as backslash 0, which is a weird way of describing it.
但这仅代表一个特殊字符，否则称为
But this just represents a special character, otherwise known
作为空字符，这只是一个特殊的值，
as the null character, which is just a special value that
表示字符串的结尾。
represents the end of a string.
这就是说，当您创建一个字符串时，引用
So that is to say when you create a string, quote
用双引号取消引号，“嗨！”-
unquote with double quotes, "HI!"--
是的，字符串的长度为3。
yes, the string is length 3.
但是，您浪费或花费了4个总字节。
But you're wasting or spending 4 total bytes on it.
为什么？
Why?
因为这是计算机了解“ HI！”位置的线索。
Because this is a clue to the computer as to where "HI!"
结束，下一个字符串可能在哪里开始。
ends and where the next string maybe begins.
仅仅开始在里面打印字符是不够的
It is not sufficient to just start printing characters inside
一次从左到右打印一次。
of printf one at a time, left to right.
必须有这种等同的停车标志
There needs to be this sort of equivalent of a stop sign
在字符串的末尾说，就是这个字符串。
at the end of the string, saying, that's it for this string.
那么，这些值是什么？
Well, what are these values?
好吧，让我们将它们转换回十进制-
Well, let's convert them back to decimal--
72、73、33。
72, 73, 33.
花式反斜杠0只是一种表示字符形式的方式，它是0。
That fancy backslash 0 was just a way of saying, in character form, it's 0.
更具体地说，它是该正方形内的八个0位。
More specifically, it is eight 0 bits inside of that square.
因此，要存储一个字符串，您不知道的计算机，
So to store a string, the computer, unbeknownst to you,
一直使用一个额外的字节全0位，否则写为反斜杠0，
has been using one extra byte all, 0 bits, otherwise written as backslash 0,
但实际上也称为值0。
but otherwise known as literally the value 0.
所以这个东西，俗称null，
So this thing, otherwise colloquially known as null,
只是一个特殊的角色。
is just a special character.
我们实际上可以再次看到它。
And we can actually see it again.
如果我从以前回到我的asciichart.com，
If I go back to my asciichart.com from before,
注意编号0在所有大写字母中都称为NUL，NUL。
notice number 0 is known as NUL, N-U-L in all caps.
好了，这么说了，那么关于字符串的强大之处是什么
All right, so with that said, what is powerful then about strings
一旦我们具备了这种能力？
once we have this capability?
好吧，让我继续执行此操作。
Well, let me go ahead and do this.
让我回到刚才的代码中。
Let me go back into my code from a moment ago.
让我继续进行一些改进
And let me go ahead and enhance this program a little bit
只是对发生的事情有点好奇。
just to get a little curious as to what's going on.
你知道我能做什么吗？
You know what I can do?
我敢打赌，在这个版本中我可以做的就是这个。
I bet what I can do here in this version here is this.
你知道吗？
You know what?
如果我要打印出s的所有这些字符，
If I want to print out all of these characters of s,
我可以再次感到好奇，并打印出％c，％c，％c。
I can get a little curious again and print out %c, %c, %c.
如果s是一个数组，按照今天的语法，我可以从技术上做s [0]，
And if s is an array, per today's syntax, I can technically do s[0],
s [1]，s [2]。
s[1], s[2].
然后，如果我保存了此代码，请使用make hi，OK，。/ hi重新编译我的代码，
And then if I save this, recompile my code with make hi, OK, ./hi,
我仍然看到“嗨！”
I still see "HI!"
但是你知道吗？
But you know what?
让我有点好奇。
Let me get a little more curious.
让我使用％i，以便实际上可以看到那些ASCII码。
Let me use %i so I can actually see those ASCII codes.
让我继续并用make hi./hi重新编译。
Let me go ahead and recompile with make hi, ./hi.
有72、73、33。
There's the 72, 73, 33.
现在让我变得更加好奇。
Now let me get even more curious.
让我在这里打印第四个值s [3]，
Let me print a fourth value like this here, s[3],
请注意，这是第四个位置。
which is the fourth location, mind you.
因此，如果我现在将hi和./hi设为hi，瞧，现在您看到0。
So if I now do make hi and ./hi, voila, now you see 0.
这实际上暗示着C的一个非常危险的特性。您知道，
And what this hints at is actually a very dangerous feature of C. You know,
假设我很好奇看到的还不止于此。
suppose I'm curious at seeing what's beyond that.
从技术上讲，我可以做s [4]，第五个位置，
I could technically do s[4], the fifth location,
即使根据我的照片，真的不应该有任何东西
even though according to my picture, there really shouldn't be anything
在第五位置，至少我现在还不知道。
at the fifth location, at least not that I know about just yet.
但是我可以在C语言中做到。没有什么可以阻止我。
But I can do it in C. Nothing's stopping me.
所以，让我打招呼，。/ hi。
So let me do make hi, ./hi.
这很有趣。
And that's interesting.
显然有37。
Apparently there's the number 37.
37是多少？
What is the number 37?
好吧，让我回到我的ASCII图表。
Well, let me go back to my ASCII chart.
让我得出结论，数字37是百分号。
And let me conclude that number 37 is a percent sign.
这有点奇怪，因为我没有打印出明确的百分比。
So that's kind of weird because I didn't print out an explicit percent.
现在，我在某些地方闲逛着计算机的内存
Now I'm kind of poking around the computer's memory in places
从某种意义上说，我不应该看。
I shouldn't be looking, in some sense.
实际上，如果我真的很好奇，那就让我们不要看位置4。
In fact, if I get really curious, let's look not at location 4.
位置40怎么样，就像进入那张照片一样？
How about location 40, like way off into that picture?
打个招呼，。/ hi，24，无论是什么。
Make hi, ./hi, 24, whatever that is.
我可以查看位置400，重新编译代码，打个招呼，。/ hi。
I can look at location 400, recompile my code, make hi, ./hi.
现在又是0。
And now it's 0 again.
因此，这对于C语言来说既强大又危险。
So this is what's both powerful and also dangerous about C.
您可以触摸，查看或更改所需的任何内存。
You can touch, look at, change any memory you want.
您实际上只是在荣誉系统上
You're essentially just on the honor system
不要触摸属于您的记忆。
not to touch memory that does it belong to you.
而且总是，尤其是下周，
And invariably, especially next week, are
我们将开始不小心触摸不属于您的记忆。
we going to start accidentally touching memory that doesn't belong to you.
您会发现它实际上可能导致计算机程序崩溃，
And you'll see that it actually can cause computer programs to crash,
包括您自己的Mac和PC上的程序，这是另一个常见错误的来源。
including programs on your own Mac and PC, yet another source of common bugs.
但是现在我们有了存储不同字符串的能力
But now that we have this ability to store different strings
或将字符串视为数组，
or to think about strings as arrays, well,
让我们继续考虑如何
let's go ahead and consider how you might
一个程序中有多个字符串。
have multiple strings in a program.
举例来说，如果您要在程序中存储两个字符串，我们可以调用
So for instance, if you were to store two strings in a program-- let's call
它们分别是s和t。
them s and t respectively.
另一个程序员惯例-如果您需要两个字符串，
Another programmer convention-- if you need two strings,
称第一个为s，第二个为t。
call the first one s then the second one t.
也许我正在存储“嗨！”
Maybe I'm storing "HI!"
那么，再见！”
then "BYE!"
那么，计算机的内存将是什么样的？
Well, what's the computer's memory going to look like?
好吧，让我们做一些挖掘。
Well, let's do some digging.
和以前一样，“ HI！”将存储在此处。
"HI!", as before, is going to be stored here.
所以整个事情都指s，它是
So this whole thing refers to s, and it's
占用4个字节，因为最后一个是那个特殊的空字符
taking 4 bytes because the last one is that special null character that
只是划定字符串结尾的停止符号。
just is the stop sign that demarcates the end of the string.
同时，“再见！”将占据另一个B，Y，E感叹号，
"BYE!", meanwhile, is going to take up another B, Y, E, exclamation point,
五个字节，因为我需要第五个字节代表另一个空字符。
five bytes because I need a fifth byte to represent another null character.
而这是故意环绕。
And this one deliberately wraps around.
再说一次，这只是艺术家的作品。
Though again, this is just an artist's rendition.
现实中不一定有网格。
There's not necessarily a grid in reality.
B，Y，E，感叹号，反斜杠0现在表示t。
B, Y, E, exclamation point, backslash 0 now represents t.
这就是说，如果我有一个像这样的程序，那么我在这里有“ HI！”。
So this is to say, if I had a program like this, where I had "HI!"
然后是“再见！”，然后我开始在计算机的内存中戳戳
and then "BYE!", and I started poking around the computer's memory
只是使用方括号符号，我
just using the square bracket notation, I
打赌我可以开始访问B或Y的值
bet I could start accessing the value of B or Y
或E，只要稍微看一下字符串s即可。
or E just by looking a little past the string s.
再说一次，随着我们程序的复杂化，
So again, as complicated as our programs get,
引擎盖下面发生的所有事情就是您放下东西
all that's going on underneath the hood is you just plop things down
在这些位置的内存中。
in memory in locations like these.
因此，现在我们有了这种能力或这种思维模式
And so now that we have this ability or maybe this mental model
对于计算机内部发生的事情，
for what's going on inside of a computer,
我们可以考虑您可能需要的一些功能
we can consider some of the features that you might want
现在可以在您编写的程序中使用。
to now use in programs that you write.
所以，让我继续这里，快速编写程序，
So let me go ahead here and whip up a quick program,
例如，这可以继续进行下去，比方说，
for instance, that goes ahead and, let's say,
打印出字符串的总长度。
prints out the total length of a string.
让我继续执行此操作。
Let me go ahead and do this.
我将继续在CS50的IDE中创建一个新程序。
I'm going to go ahead and create a new program here in CS50's IDE.
我将其称为一个字符串。c。
And I'm going to call this one string.c.
而且我将像往常一样快速进入顶部cs50.h。
And I'm going to very quickly at the top include as usual cs50.h.
我将继续并#include stdio.h。
And I'm going to go ahead and #include stdio.h.
而且我要给自己int main（void）。
And I'm going to give myself int main(void).
然后在这里，我要给自己一个字符串。
And then in here, I'm going to get myself a string.
所以string s等于get_string。
So string s equals get_string.
让我问一下人类，无论它是什么。
Let me just ask the human for some input, whatever it is.
然后，让我继续并逐字打印“输出”一词
Then let me go ahead and print out literally the word "Output"
以便我可以实际看到结果。
just so that I can actually see the result.
然后在这里，让我继续打印该字符串，因为我得到0，
And then down here, let me go ahead and print out that string, for int i get 0,
我小于-
i is less than--
呵呵，我还不知道字符串的长度是多少。
huh, I don't know what the length of the string is yet.
因此，让我在此处输入一个问号，它不是有效的代码，
So let me just put a question mark there, which is not valid code,
但我们将回到这个问题-i ++。
but we'll come back to this-- i++.
然后在循环内部，我想继续打印
And then inside of the loop, I want to go ahead and print out
通过使用我的新数组符号，每个字符每次一次。
every character one at a time by using my new array notation.
然后在该程序的最后，
And then at the very end of this program,
我要打印一条新行以使
I'm going to print a new line just to make
确保光标在自己的行上。
sure the cursor is on its own line.
这是一个完整的程序，现在，
So this is a complete program that is now,
从本周开始，将字符串视为数组，所以，第10行中的我的语法
as of this week, going to treat a string as an array, ergo, my syntax in line 10
那是使用我的新花式方括号表示法。
that's using my new fancy square bracket notation.
但是我还没有回答的唯一问题是
But the only question I haven't answered yet is this--
我怎么知道什么时候停止打印字符串？
how do I know when to stop printing the string?
我怎么知道什么时候停止？
How do I know when to stop?
好吧，到目前为止，当我们使用for循环时，
Well, it turns out, thus far, when we're using for loops,
我们通常所做的只是从0开始计数直到某个数字。
we've typically done something like just count from 0 on up to some number.
但是，此条件是任何布尔表达式。
This condition, though, is any Boolean expression.
我只需要有一个是/否或一个正确/错误的答案。
I just need to have a yes/no or a true/false answer.
所以你知道我能做什么？
So you know what I could do?
只要角色i在位置i上就一直循环播放
Keep looping so long as character at location i
和s不等于反斜杠0。
and s does not equal backslash 0.
因此，现在绝对是一些新语法。
So this is now definitely some new syntax.
让我在这里放大。
Let me zoom in here.
但是s [i]仅表示s中的第i个字符，或更具体地说，
But s[i] just means the i-th character in s, or more specifically,
s中位置i处的字符。
the character at position i in s.
爆炸等于-因此爆炸是程序员的发音
Bang equals-- so bang is how a programmer pronounces
感叹号，因为它快一点了-砰等于
exclamation point because it's a little faster-- bang equals
均值不相等。
means does not equal.
因此，这是在数学中用斜杠将等号切成等号的方式。
So this is how you would do an equal sign with a slash through it in math.
在代码中，感叹号等于符号。
It's, in code, exclamation point, equals sign.
然后注意这种时髦-反斜杠
And then notice this funkiness-- backslash
再次为0，即“空字符”，但用单引号引起来
0 is again, the "null character," but it's in single quotes
因为根据定义它又是一个字符。
because, again, it is by definition a character.
由于种种原因，我们将进入另一个时代，
And for reasons we'll get into another time,
反斜杠0是表达方式。
backslash 0 is how you express it.
就像反斜杠n在新行中有点怪异的转义字符一样，
Just like backslash n is kind of a weird escape character for the new line,
反斜杠0是全0的字符。
backslash 0 is the character that is all 0's.
因此，这是一种不同的for循环。
So this is kind of a different for loop.
我仍然从0开始。
I'm still starting at 0 for i.
我仍然像往常一样增加我。
I'm still incrementing i as always.
但我现在不检查预定长度
But I'm now not checking for some preordained length
因为就像计算机一样，我不知道这些字符串的结尾是先验的。
because just like a computer, I do not know a priori where these strings end.
我只知道一旦看到反斜杠0，它们就会结束。
I only know that they end once I see backslash 0.
所以当我现在下来这里做弦时
So when I now go down here and do make string--
它会编译OK-- ./string，让我在所有大写字母中输入“ HELLO”之类的内容。
it compiles OK-- ./string, let me type in something like "HELLO" in all caps.
瞧，输出再次是“ HELLO”。
Voila, the output is "HELLO" again.
让我再做一次
Let me do it again--
大写字母为“ BYE”，输出为“ BYE”。
"BYE" in all caps, and the output is "BYE."
所以这是一个无用的程序，因为它只是打印
So it's kind of a useless program in that it's just printing
我输入的内容相同。
the same thing that I typed in.
但是我有条件地使用这个布尔表达式
But I'm conditionally using this Boolean expression
决定是否继续打印字符。
to decide whether or not to keep printing characters.
现在，值得庆幸的是，C附带了一个可以为我解答的函数。
Now thankfully, C comes with a function that can answer this for me.
原来有一个叫做strlen的函数
It turns out there is a function called strlen
所以我可以从字面上说，好吧，找出来
so I can literally just say, well, figure out
字符串的长度是多少。
what the length of the string is.
该函数称为字符串长度的strlen。
The function is called strlen for string length.
它存在于一个叫做的文件中，也许并不奇怪，
And it exists in a file called, not surprisingly, perhaps,
string.h，string.h。
string.h, string.h.
所以现在让我继续在这里做弦-
So now let me go ahead down here and do make string--
编译OK-- ./string。
compiles OK-- ./string.
输入“ HELLO”，它仍然有效。
Type in "HELLO," and it still works.
所以这个函数很奇怪，它确实通过头文件存在于库中
So this function strlen that does exist in a library via the header file
string.h已经存在。
string.h already exists.
有人写的。
Someone else wrote it.
但是他们是怎么写的呢？
But how did they write it?
奇怪的是他们写了我的第一个版本
Odds are they wrote the first version that I
通过检查该反斜杠0来完成。
did by checking for that backslash 0.
但是，让我在这里问一个微妙的问题。
But let me ask a subtle question here.
这个程序是正确的。
This program is correct.
遍历字符串的整个长度，
It iterates over the whole length of the string,
并打印出其中的每个字符。
and it prints out every character therein.
任何人都可以在此功能中观察到较差的设计决策吗？
Can anyone observe a poor design decision in this function?
这个人很微妙，但我有一些不喜欢的东西
This one's subtle, but there's something I don't
特别是关于我的for循环。
like about my for loop in particular.
我将其隔离到第9行。
And I'll isolate it to line 9.
我没有在9号线上做一些优化的事情。
I've not done something optimally on line 9.
有机会进行更好的设计。
There's an opportunity for better design.
关于我可能会做得更好的任何想法？
Any thoughts here on what I might do better?
是的，乔纳森？
Yeah, Jonathan?
JONATHAN：是的，基本上是为字符串长度创建另一个变量
JONATHAN: Yeah, to create basically another variable for the string length
并记住它。
and to remember it.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，为什么要这样建议呢？
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, and why are you suggesting that?
JONATHAN：如果您要为字符串长度使用其他值，
JONATHAN: If you want to use a different value for the string length,
或者如果它可能波动或变化，您想要
or if it might fluctuate or change, you want
只是拥有一个不同的变量作为它的占位符值。
to just have a different variable as a sort of placeholder value for it.
DAVID MALAN：好的，可能。
DAVID MALAN: OK, potentially.
但在这种情况下，我会宣称，因为人类
But I will claim in this case that because the human has
输入单词，一旦输入单词，它就不会改变。
typed in the word, once you type in the word, it's not going to change.
但我认为您的方向是正确的，因为
But I think you're going down the right direction because
在这里的布尔表达式中，我小于s的字符串长度，
in this Boolean expression here, i less than the string length of s,
回想一下，该表达式一次又一次地被求值。
recall that this expression gets evaluated again and again and again.
每次通过for循环时，请记住您一直在
Every time through a for loop, recall that you're constantly
检查条件。
checking the condition.
在这种情况下，条件i小于s的长度。
The condition in this case is i less than the length of s.
问题是在这种情况下strlen是一个函数，
The problem is that strlen in this case is a function, which
意味着有人写了一些代码，
means there's some piece of code someone wrote,
可能与我几分钟前写的内容相似，
probably similar to what I wrote a few minutes ago, that you're constantly
问，字符串的长度是多少？
asking, what's the length of the string?
字符串的长度是多少？
What's the length of the string?
并从我们的图片中回想起您计算字符串长度的方式
And recall from our picture, the way you figure out the length of a string
是从字符串的开头开始，然后继续检查，
is you start at the beginning of the string, and you keep checking,
我在反斜杠0处吗？
am I at backslash 0?
好的。
OK.
我在反斜杠0处吗？
Am I at backslash 0?
好的。
OK.
因此，要弄清楚“ HI！”的长度，我需要1、2、3、4步，
So to figure out the length of "HI!", it's going to take me 1, 2, 3, 4 steps,
是的，因为我必须从头开始。
right, because I have to start at the beginning.
我从位置0一直循环到结束。
And I iterate from location 0 on to the end.
为了找出“再见！”的长度，
To find out the length of "BYE!", it's going
我走了五个步骤，因为那是多长时间
to take me five steps because that's how long it's
从左到右带我找到反斜杠0。
going to take me from left to right to find that backslash 0.
所以我不喜欢这行代码，
So what I don't like about this line of code is,
你为什么一次又一次地要求s的字符串长度
why are you asking for the string length of s again and again
一遍又一遍？
and again and again?
在这种情况下，它不会改变。
It's not going to change in this context.
因此，如果我们继续要求用户提供更多输入，就会得出乔纳森的观点。
So Jonathan's point is taken if we keep asking the user for more input.
但是在这种情况下，我们只问了一次人类。
But in this case, we've only asked the human once.
那你知道吗？
So you know what?
让我们听乔纳森（Jonathan）的建议，将int n等于s的字符串长度。
Let's take Jonathan's advice and do int n equals the string length of s.
然后，也许您知道我们能做什么？
And then maybe you know what we could do?
相反，将n置于此条件下。
Put n in this condition instead.
所以现在我问的是同样的问题，但我不是愚蠢的，
So now I'm asking the same question, but I'm not foolishly,
一遍又一遍地低效率地问同样的问题，
inefficiently asking the same question again and again,
因此，相同的问题需要大量的工作
whereby the same question requires a good amount of work
一次又一次地找到反斜杠0。
to find the backslash 0 again and again and again.
现在，我们也可以在此处进行一些清理。
Now, there's some cleaning up we can do here too.
事实证明，for循环还有另一个微妙的功能。
It turns out there's this other subtle feature of for loops.
如果您想将另一个变量初始化为一个值，
If you want to initialize another variable to a value,
您实际上可以一次完成所有操作。
you can actually do this all at once.
您可以在分号之前执行此操作。
And you can do so before the semicolon.
您可以将逗号n等于s的strlen。
You can do comma n equals strlen of s.
然后就可以像我在这里一样使用n了。
And then you can use n, just as I have here.
所以这并没有那么好，但是
So it's not all that much better, but it's
稍微干净一点，现在我已经写了两行代码
a little cleaner in that now I've taken two lines of code
并将它们合而为一。
and collapsed them into one.
它们都必须是相同的数据类型，
They both have to be of the same data types,
但这没关系，因为i和n都可以。
but that's OK here because both i and n are.
再一次，这里的低效率是愚蠢的
So again, the inefficiency here is that it was foolish
在此之前，我一直一次又一次地问同样的问题。
before that I kept asking the same question again and again and again.
但是现在我问了一个问题，在一个叫做n的变量中记住了这个问题，
But now I'm asking the question once, remembering it in a variable called n,
并且仅将i与实际上没有变化的整数进行比较。
and only comparing i against that integer which does not actually change.
好吧，我知道很多。
All right, I know that too was a lot.
让我们继续在这里休息3分钟，只是为了伸展腿和其他东西。
Let's go ahead here and take a 3-minute break just to stretch legs and whatnot.
3分钟后，我们将返回并开始查看应用程序
In 3 minutes, we'll come back and start to see applications
现在所有这些功能最终都会导致一些问题，
now of all of these features ultimately to some problems that
在语言的可读性方面，本周将领先
are going to lie ahead this week on the readability of language
以及密码学。
and also on cryptography.
因此，我们将在3分钟后见到您。
So we'll see you in 3 minutes.
好吧，我们回来了。
All right, so we're back.
诚然，这是一堆低级的细节。
And this has been a whole bunch of low-level details, admittedly.
最终，本周及以后我们将如何处理此问题
And where we're going with this ultimately this week and beyond
是其中一些构建基块的应用。
is applications of some of these building blocks.
而下周和下一个问题集中的应用程序之一
And one of those applications this coming week and the next problem set
将会是加密技术，即加扰或加密的艺术
is going to be that of cryptography, the art of scrambling or encrypting
信息。
information.
如果您要加密信息，
And if you're trying to encrypt information,
像消息一样，这些消息可能很好
like messages, well, those messages might very well
如果可以的话，可以用英文或ASCII书写。
be written in English or in ASCII, if you will.
您可能想从一件事转换某些ASCII字符
And you might want to convert some of those ASCII characters from one thing
传递给另一个人，以便如果您的消息被某个第三方截获，
to another so that if your message is intercepted by some third party,
他们实际上无法破译或弄清楚您发送的邮件是什么。
they can't actually decipher or figure out what it is that you've sent.
所以我觉得我们几乎要-
So I feel like we're almost toward--
我们几乎有能力在代码中
we're almost at the ability where, in code, we
可以开始将一个单词转换为另一个单词或扰乱我们的文本。
can start to convert one word to another or to scramble our text.
但是我们确实需要更多的构建块。
But we do need a couple of more building blocks.
所以回想一下，我们放弃了这张照片
So recall that we left off with this picture
在这里，我们在计算机的内存中有两个单词：“嗨！”和“再见！”，
here, where we had two words in the computer's memory, "HI!" and "BYE!",
既带有感叹号，也带有反斜杠0
both with exclamation points, but also both with these backslash 0's
您和我没有明确地放在那儿。
that you and I do not put there explicitly.
只要您使用双引号和任何时间，它们就会为您发生
They just happen for you any time you use the double quotes and any time
您使用get_string函数。
you use the get_string function.
因此，一旦我们将它们存储在内存中，就可以将它们分别视为s和t。
So once we have those in memory, you can think of them as s and t respectively.
但是字符串s或t只是一个数组。
But a string, s or t, is just an array.
同样，您也可以引用所有这些单独的字符或字符
So again, you can also refer to all of these individual characters or chars
通过今天的新方括号符号s [0]，s [1]，s [2]，s [3]，
via the new square bracket notation of today, s[0], s[1], s[2], s[3],
然后是t [0]，t [1]，[2]，[3]和[4]，然后是其他任何东西
and then t[0], t[1], [2], [3], and [4], and then whatever else is
在计算机的内存中。
in the computer's memory.
但是您知道您什至可以做这件事-假设相反，我们
But you know what you can even do is this-- suppose that instead we
想要有一个单词数组。
wanted to have an array of words.
所以之前，我们有一个分数数组，一个整数数组。
So before, we had an array of scores, an array of integers.
但是现在假设我们想要在其他程序的上下文中
But now suppose we wanted in the context of some other program
有一系列的单词。
to have an array of words.
您完全可以做到这一点。
You can totally do that.
没有什么可以阻止您拥有一系列单词。
There's nothing stopping you from having an array of words.
而且语法将是相同的。
And the syntax is going to be identical.
请注意，如果我想要一个名为word的数组，该数组可以容纳两个字符串，
Notice, if I want an array called words that has room for two strings,
我只是说字符串字[2]。
I literally just say, string words[2].
嘿，这意味着计算机给我一个大小为2的数组，每个成员
This means, hey, computer, give me an array of size 2, each of whose members
将是一个字符串。
is going to be a string.
如何填充该数组？
How do I populate that array?
与以前相同的分数-
Same as before with the scores--
单词[0]得到，引用不加引号，“嗨！”
words[0] gets, quote unquote, "HI!"
Words [1]得到，引用不带引号的“再见！”
Words[1] gets, quote unquote, "BYE!"
这就是说，使用此代码，我们可以创建类似于该图片的图片吗？
So that is to say with this code, could we create a picture similar to the one
之前？
previously?
但是我没有将这些字符串称为s和t。
But I'm not calling these strings s and t.
现在，我在两个不同的位置分别将它们称为“单词”，分别为0和1
Now I'm calling them both "words" at two different locations, 0 and 1
分别。
respectively.
因此，我们可以像这样重绘同一张图片。
So we could redraw that same picture like this.
现在，该词在技术上被命名为words [0]。
Now this word is technically named words[0].
而这个用词[1]来指代。
And this one is referred to by words[1].
但是，字符串又是什么呢？
But again, what is a string?
字符串是一个数组。
A string is an array.
但是，这里我们有一个字符串数组。
And yet, here we have an array of strings.
因此，我们有点拥有数组数组。
So we kind of sort of have an array of arrays.
所以我们有一个单词数组，但是一个单词只是一个字符串。
So we've got an array of words, but a word is just a string.
字符串是字符数组。
And a string is an array of characters.
所以我在黑板上真正拥有的是一个数组阵列。
So what I really have on the board is an array of arrays.
所以在这里-这将是今天的最后一个怪异的语法-
And so here-- and this will be the last weird syntax for today--
您实际上可以背对背使用多个方括号。
you can actually have multiple square brackets back to back.
因此，如果您的变量被称为单词，而该变量是一个数组，
So if your variable's called words, and that variable's an array,
如果要获取数组中的第一个单词，则执行words [0]。
if you want to get the first word in the array, you do words[0].
一旦你说了这个“ HI！”，你就想要
Once you're at that word, "HI!", and you want
要获得该单词的第一个字符，您可以类似地执行[0]。
to get the first character in that word, you can similarly do [0].
因此，第一个括号指的是您要在数组中使用的单词。
So the first bracket refers to what word do you want in the array.
第二个括号指的是您要在该单词中使用什么字符。
The second bracket refers to what character do you want in that word.
所以现在我就是那个单词[0] [1]。
So now the I is that words[0][1].
感叹号是单词[0] [2]。
The exclamation point is that words[0][2].
空字符位于单词[0] [3]处。
And the null character's at words[0][3].
同时，B是单词[1] [0]，[1] [1]，[1] [2]，[1] [3]，[1] [4]。
Meanwhile, the B is that words[1][0], [1][1], [1][2], [1][3], [1][4].
因此，如果可以的话，它几乎有点像坐标系。
So it's almost kind of like a coordinate system, if you will.
它是二维数组或数组数组。
It's a two-dimensional array, or an array of arrays.
所以这只是说，如果我们想考虑字符串数组
So this is only to say that if we wanted to think of arrays of strings
作为个人角色，我们可以。
as individual characters, we can.
我们现在具有编码的表达能力。
We have that expressiveness now to encode.
那么，现在我可以在此级别上进行操作了，该怎么办？
So what more can I do now that I can manipulate things at this level?
让我做一个非常适用的程序，
Let me do a program that'll be pretty applicable,
我认为，还有一些我们即将推出的计划。
I think, with some of our upcoming programs as well.
让我将此称为大写。
Let me call this one uppercase.
让我快速写出一个以生活为目的的程序
Let me quickly write a program whose purpose in life
只是将输入的单词转换为大写。
is just to convert an input word to uppercase.
让我们看看我们如何做到这一点。
And let's see how we can do this.
因此，让我继续并#includecs50.h。
So let me go ahead and #include cs50.h.
让我继续并#include stdio.h。
Let me go ahead and #include stdio.h.
让我也包括这个时间string.h，这是
Let me also include this time string.h, which is
给我们像strlen这样的功能。
going to give us functions like strlen.
然后让我做int main（void）。
And then let me do int main(void).
然后让我继续前进，像以前一样从用户那里获取一个字符串。
And then let me go ahead here and get a string from the user like before.
所以我只想问用户一个字符串。
So I'm just going to ask the user for a string.
我希望他们给我任何弦乐
And I want them to give me whatever the string should
在我将所有内容都大写之前。
be before I uppercase everything.
然后，我将继续打印字面意思为“之后”，
Then I'm just going to go ahead and print out literally "After,"
只是为了让我看到将字符串中的所有内容都大写之后会发生什么。
just so I can see what happens after I capitalize everything in the string.
现在让我继续执行此操作-因为我得到0，
And now let me go ahead and do this-- for int i get 0,
我小于s的字符串长度，i ++。
i less than string length of s, i++.
等一下，我之前犯了那个错误。
Wait a minute, I made that mistake before.
让我们不再重复这个问题。
Let's not repeat this question.
让我们给自己一个第二个变量-n的字符串长度为s，i小于n，
Let's give myself a second variable-- n gets string length of s, i less than n,
我++。
i++.
如此一来，现在这已成为样板。
So again, this is now becoming boilerplate.
每当您要遍历字符串中的所有字符时，
Any time you want to iterate over all of the characters in the string,
这可能是一个合理的起点。
this probably is a reasonable place to start.
然后让我问一个问题
And then let me ask the question--
我想遍历字符串中的每个字符
I want to iterate over every character in the string
人类输入的内容。
that the human has typed in.
我想问自己一个问题，就像我们对任何算法所做的一样。
And I want to ask myself a question, just as we've done with any algorithm.
具体来说，我想问一下当前字母是否为小写，
Specifically, I want to ask if the current letter is lowercase,
让我以某种方式将其转换为大写。
let me somehow convert it to uppercase.
否则，让我直接将其打印出来。
Else, let me just print it out unchanged.
那么，我如何使用上周和本周的构建基块来表达这一点？
So how can I express that using last week and this week's building blocks?
好吧，让我说这样的话-
Well, let me say something like this--
如果位于s中第i个位置的字符，或者位于s中第i个字符
if the character at location i in s, or if the i-th character in s
大于或等于小写字母a，且s中的第i个字符
is greater than or equal to a lowercase a, and the i-th character in s
小于或等于小写字母z，我想怎么办？
is less than or equal to a lower case z, what do I want to do?
让我继续打印一个字符。
Let me go ahead and print out a character.
但是那个角色应该是什么？的括号我，
But that character should be what? s bracket i,
但我不知道该怎么办。
but I'm not sure what to do here yet.
但是，让我回到这一点。
But let me come back to that.
否则，让我继续，只打印不变的字符s [i]。
Else, let me go ahead and just print out that character unchanged, s[i].
所以减去占位符，我问过的问号，我一直都挺好的
So minus the placeholder, the question marks I've put, I'm kind of all the way
那里。
there.
第10行将i初始化为0。
Line 10 initializes i to 0.
它将一直计数到n，其中n是字符串的长度。
It's going to count all the way up to n, where n is the length of the string.
而且它将继续增加i。
And it's going to keep incrementing i.
因此，我们之前已经看到过。
So we've seen that before.
再一次，那将很快成为肌肉记忆。
And again, that's going to become muscle memory before long.
第12行有点新，但是使用了构建块
Line 12 is a little new, but it uses building blocks
从上周开始。
from last week and this.
这周，我们有了新的方括号
This week, we have the new square bracket
表示法，以获取字符串s中的第i个字符。
notation to get the i-th character in the string s.
大于或等于，小于或等于-我们看到至少一个
Greater than or equal to, less than or equal to-- we saw at least one
上周的那些。
of those last week.
那只是意味着大于或等于，小于或等于。
That just means greater than or equal to, less than or equal to.
我上周提到了&amp;&amp;，这是逻辑AND运算符，
I mentioned &amp;&amp; last week, which is the logical AND operator,
这意味着您可以检查一种情况，而另一种情况。
which means you can check one condition and another.
如果这两个都是正确的，那么整个事情就是正确的。
And the whole thing is true if both of those are true.
今天有点奇怪。
This is a bit weird today.
但是如果要表达，是当前字符
But if you want to express, is the current character
在小写字母a和小写字母z之间，完全可以
between lowercase a and lowercase z, totally fine
将a和z隐式地视为数字，它们实际上是数字。
to implicitly treat a and z as numbers, which they really are.
因为同样，如果回到最喜欢的ASCII图表，
Because again, if we come back to our favorite ASCII chart,
您会再次看到小写字母a有一个与之相关的数字97。
you'll see again that lowercase a has a number associated with it, 97.
小写字母z有一个与之关联的数字122。
Lowercase z has a number associated with it, 122.
因此，如果我真的想成为一个学究的人，可以回到我的代码中
So if I really wanted to be pedantic, I could go back into my code
并执行类似的操作，如果大于或等于97，
and do something like, well, if this is greater than or equal to 97,
小于或等于122，但设计不佳。
and it's less than or equal to 122, but bad design.
就像，我永远不会记住小写字母z是122。
Like, I'm never going to remember that lowercase z is 122.
就像，没有人会知道这一点。
Like, no one is going to know that.
它使代码不那么明显。
It makes the code less obvious.
继续以一种更多的方式编写它
Go ahead and write it in a way that's a little more
这样对人类友好。
friendly to humans like this.
但是请注意这个问号。
But notice this question mark.
如何填写此空白？
How do I fill in this blank?
好，让我回到ASCII图表。
Well, let me go back to the ASCII chart.
这很微妙，但这很酷。
This is subtle, but this is kind of cool.
人类肯定在向前思考。
And humans were definitely thinking ahead.
请注意，小写字母a为97。
Notice that lowercase a is 97.
大写字母A为65。
Capital A is 65.
小写字母b为98。
Lowercase b is 98.
大写B为66。
Capital B is 66.
并注意这两个数字-
And notice these two numbers--
65至97、66至98、67至99。
65 to 97, 66 to 98, 67 to 99.
似乎无论我们比较什么字母，小写
It would seem that no matter what letters we compare, lowercase
和大写字母，它们始终相距32。
and uppercase, they're always 32 apart.
这是一致的。
And that's consistent.
我们可以为所有26个英文字母做到这一点。
We could do it for all 26 English letters.
因此，如果他们总是相隔32岁，您知道我能做些什么-
So if they're always 32 apart, you know what I could do--
如果我想用小写字母，
if I want to take a lowercase letter, which
这就是我在第14行中所考虑的
is what I'm thinking about in line 14, I could just
在这种情况下，请减去32。
subtract off 32 in this case.
这不是最干净的，因为我再次
It's not the cleanest, because again, I'm
在某个时候可能会忘记那个数学。
probably going to forget that math at some point.
但至少在数学上，我认为这样做
But at least mathematically, I think that'll do
诀窍，因为97会变成65。
the trick because 97 will become 65.
98将变为66，这将迫使这些字符转换为小写。
98 will become 66, which is forcing those characters to lowercase.
但是它们并没有被打印为数字。
But they're not being printed as numbers.
我仍在使用％c强制将其作为字符。
I'm still using %c to coerce it to be a char.
因此，如果我在这里没有弄乱任何语法，请让我大写。
So if I didn't mess any syntax up here, let me make uppercase.
好的，。/大写。
OK, ./uppercase.
让我继续输入，例如，用小写形式输入我的名字。
And let me go ahead and type in, for instance, my name in all lowercase.
瞧，大写。
And voila, uppercase.
现在，这有点丑陋。
Now, it's a little ugly.
我忘了反斜线n，所以让我继续
I forgot my backslash n, so let me go ahead
并添加其中一种真正的快速工具来修复光标。
and add one of those real quick just to fix the cursor.
让我用make大写重新编译代码。
Let me recompile the code with make uppercase.
让我用./uppercase重新运行程序，然后输入我的名字，
Let me rerun the program with ./uppercase and now type in my name,
大卫。
David.
让我再和Brian一起做一次。
Let me do it again with Brian.
并注意，每个字符都在大写
And notice that it's capitalizing everything character by character
仅使用今天的构件。
using only today's building blocks.
这是对的。
This is correct.
它的样式非常好，因为所有东西都缩进了。
It's pretty well styled because everything's nicely indented.
即使乍一看它看起来有点神秘，它还是非常易读的。
It's very readable even though it might look a little cryptic at first glance.
但我认为我可以做得更好。
But I think I can do better.
通过使用另一个库，我可以做得更好。
And I can do better by using yet another library.
这就是C（实际上是一般的编程）变得强大的地方。
And here's where C, and really programming in general, gets powerful.
使用流行语言的重点
The whole point of using popular languages
是因为在解决问题之前还有很多其他人
is because so many other people before you have solved problems
您无需再次解决。
that you don't need to solve again.
我敢肯定，在过去的50年中，有人可能
And I'm sure over the past, like, 50 years, someone has probably
编写了一个为我大写字母的函数。
written a function that capitalizes letters for me.
我不必自己做。
I don't have to do this myself.
确实，还有一个我要去的图书馆
And indeed, there is another library that I'm going
通过其头文件包括在内。
to include by way of its header file.
在ctype.h中，type是语言C和一堆与类型相关的东西。
In ctype.h, type which is the language C and a bunch of type-related things.
在ctype.h中，结果是有一个函数调用-
And in ctype.h, it turns out there's a function call--
有几个功能。
there's a couple of functions.
具体来说，让我摆脱所有这些代码。
Specifically, let me get rid of all of this code.
让我调用一个称为islower的函数并将其传递给islower s [i]。
And let me call a function called islower and pass to islower s[i].
正如您可能猜到的，它的生命目标更低
And islower, as you might guess, its purpose in life
实质上是返回布尔值true或false，
is to return essentially a Boolean value, true or false,
如果该字符较低。
if that character is lower.
如果是这样，那么，让我继续并打印出一个占位符
And if so, well, let me go ahead and print out a placeholder
然后是那封信的大写。
followed by the capitalization of that letter.
现在，在我不得不用负32进行烦人的数学运算并弄清楚之前，
Now, before I had to do that annoying math with minus 32 and figure it out,
嗯，括号s [i]的上半部分。
uh-uh, toupper of parentheses s[i].
现在，我可以原样打印该字符，
And now I can otherwise just print out that character unchanged,
和以前一样，s [i]。
just as before, s[i].
但是现在请注意我的程序-
But now notice my program--
老实说，它肯定要短一点。
honestly, it's definitely a little shorter.
这有点简单，因为代码更少。
It's a little simpler in that there's just less code.
希望如果写得较低和较高的人做得很好，
And hopefully, if the person that wrote islower and toupper did a good job,
我知道是对的。
I know it's correct.
我只是站在他们的肩膀上。
I'm just standing on their shoulders.
坦率地说，我的代码更具可读性，因为我了解更低的代码
And frankly, my code's more readable because I understand what islower
意味着，而疯狂的&amp;&amp;语法和所有其他代码-
means, whereas that crazy &amp;&amp; syntax and all of the additional code--
可以说，这很难使您的想法四处走动。
that was just a lot harder to wrap your mind around, arguably.
因此，现在如果我继续进行编译，请大写。
So now if I go ahead and compile this-- make uppercase.
好的，这似乎很好。
OK, that seemed to work well.
现在我要继续进行操作。/大写并在所有输入我的名字
And now I'm going to go ahead and do ./uppercase and type in my name in all
再次小写。
lowercase again.
大卫似乎在工作。
David seems to work.
布赖恩似乎在工作。
Brian seems to work.
我可以整日做到这一点。
And I could do this all day long.
它似乎仍然有效。
It seems to still work.
但是你知道吗？
But you know what?
我认为我不必这么明确。
I don't think I have to be even this explicit.
你知道吗？
You know what?
我敢打赌，写to的人很聪明，
I bet if the human who wrote toupper was smart,
我敢打赌，我可以盲目地将任何字符传递给toupper，
I bet I can just blindly pass in any character to toupper,
如果可以将其转换为大写字母，则只会使用大写字母。
and it's only going to uppercase it if it can be converted to uppercase.
否则，它将原样传递。
Otherwise, it'll pass it through unchanged.
那你知道吗？
So you know what?
让我摆脱所有这些东西，真正加强这个程序
Let me get rid of all of this stuff and really tighten this program up
并打印出c的占位符，然后打印s [i]的占位符。
and print out a placeholder for c and then toupper of s[i].
确实，如果您阅读了此功能的文档，
And sure enough, if you read the documentation for this function,
它可以处理小写或不小写的情况。
it will handle the case where it's either lowercase or not lowercase.
它将做正确的事。
And it will do the right thing.
因此，现在，如果我重新编译我的代码，请大写，到目前为止效果很好。
So now if I recompile my code, make uppercase, so far so good.
./大写，David又来了。
./uppercase, David again.
瞧，它仍然有效。
Voila, it still works.
并请注意，实际上更紧密，更清洁，
And notice truly just how much tighter, how much cleaner,
我的代码短了多少。
how much shorter my code is.
从某种意义上来说，此函数的可读性更高。
And it's more readable in the sense that this function is pretty well named.
Toupper确实是所谓的。
Toupper is what it's indeed called.
但是这里有一个重要的细节。
But there is an important detail here.
Toupper希望输入一个字符。
Toupper expects as input a character.
您无法将整个单词传递给它。
You cannot pass a whole word to it.
在这一点上，我仍然有必要使用此循环
It is still necessary at this point for me to be using this loop
并逐个字符地进行。
and doing it character by character.
现在，您怎么知道呢？
Now, how would you know this?
好吧，在接下来的几周中，您将看到多个示例。
Well, you'll see multiple examples of this over the weeks to come.
但是如果我转到语言C的手册页，
But if I go to what's called the manual pages for the language C,
我们有他们自己的基于Web的版本。
we have our own web-based version of them.
我们将在本课程的实验室中为您链接
And we'll link this for you in the course's labs
并根据需要设置问题。
and problem sets as needed.
您可以在C中看到所有可用功能的列表
You can see a list of all of the available functions in C
至少在CS50中经常使用。
at least that are frequently used in CS50.
如果取消选中顶部的框，则可以看到更多功能。
And if we uncheck a box at the top, we can see even more functions.
有数十种，也许数百种功能，其中大多数
There's dozens, maybe hundreds of functions, most of which
我们将不需要或不使用CS50。
we will not need or use in CS50.
但这在任何语言中都是正确的。
But this is going to be true in any language.
您可以逐渐选择所需的构建基块。
You sort of pick up the building blocks that you need over time.
因此，我们将为您推荐这些资源
So we'll refer you to these kinds of resources
这样您就不会仅依靠我们在本节和讲座中展示的内容，
so that you don't rely only on what we show in section and lecture,
但是您还可以使用这些其他功能和工具包。
but you have at your disposal these other functions and toolkits as well.
我们还将对Python和SQL以及其他语言进行相同的处理。
And we'll do the same with Python and SQL and other languages as well.
这些就是我们再次称为手册页的内容。
So those are what we call, again, manual pages.
好吧，这是我们什至没有的最后功能
All right, a final feature before we even
考虑习题集2的加密和加扰信息。
think about cryptography and scrambling information as for problem set 2.
因此，我之前在名称中提到了一个命令行参数-
So a command-line argument I mentioned by name before--
就像一个单词，您可以在程序名称后面输入
it's like a word you can type after a program's name
为了在命令行提供输入。
in order to provide it input at the command line.
因此，打个招呼-hello是程序的命令行参数，打招呼。
So make hello-- hello is a command-line argument to the program, hello.
rm space a.out-a.out是参数，是程序的命令行参数
Rm space a.out-- a.out was an argument, a command-line argument to the program
rm，当我想将其删除时。
rm when I wanted to remove it.
因此，我们已经看到了命令行参数的实际作用。
So we've already seen command-line arguments in action.
但是我们实际上还没有编写任何程序
But we haven't actually written any programs
允许您从所谓的命令行接受单词或其他输入。
that allow you to accept words or other inputs from the so-called command line.
到目前为止，您和我的所有输入都已包含在我们的程序中
Up until now, all of the input you and I have gotten in our programs
来自get_string，get_int等。
comes from get_string, get_int, and so forth.
我们从来没有看过人类很可能拥有的单词
We have never been able to look at words that the human might very well have
在运行程序时在提示符下键入。
typed at the prompt when running your program.
但这一切现在都将改变。
But that's all about to change now.
让我继续创建一个名为argv.c的程序，
Let me go ahead and create a program called argv.c,
很快就会明白为什么。
and it'll become clear why in just a moment.
我要继续，包括stdio.h。
I'm going to go ahead and include, shall we say, stdio.h.
然后我要给自己int main（void）。
And then I'm going to give myself int main(void).
然后，我将非常简单地返回并更改空白。
And then I'm just going to very simply go back and change the void.
因此，就像我们自己的自定义函数可以接受输入一样，
So just as our own custom functions can take inputs--
我们通过get_negative_int看到了这一点。
and we saw that with get_negative_int.
我们今天平均看到了
We saw that with average today--
main也可能会接受输入。
so does main potentially take inputs.
到目前为止，我们一直在说无效。
Up till now though, we've been saying void.
我们告诉你上周说无效。
And we told you to say void last week.
我们告诉您说问题1中的内容无效。
And we told you to say void in problem set 1.
但是现在事实证明，C确实允许您将其他输入放入main。
But now it turns out that C does allow you to put other inputs into main.
您可以说，不，main不接受任何命令行参数。
You can either say, nope, main does not take any command-line arguments.
但是，如果确实如此，您可以按字面意思说int argc
But if it does, you can say literally, int argc
和带有方括号的字符串argv。
and string argv with square brackets.
因此有点神秘。
So it's a little cryptic.
从技术上讲，您不必完全以这种方式键入它。
And technically, you don't have to type it precisely this way.
但是人类的惯例至少在现在是这样让你这样做的。
But human convention would have you do it, at least for now, in this way.
这表示main，您的function，main，
This says that main, your function, main,
将整数作为一个输入而不是字符串
takes an integer as one input and not a string
而是一个字符串数组作为输入。
but an array of strings as input.
argc是参数计数的简写形式。
And argc is shorthand notation for argument count.
参数计数是一个整数，它将表示单词的数量
Argument count is an integer that's going to represent the number of words
您的用户在提示符下键入。
that your users type at the prompt.
Argv是自变量向量的缩写。
Argv is short for argument vector.
向量是说表的一种奇特的方式。
Vector is a fancy way of saying list.
这是一个变量，它将所有字符串存储在数组中
It is a variable that's going to store in an array all of the strings
有人在您自己的程序名称后的提示符下键入。
that a human types at the prompt after your own program's name.
因此，例如，我们可以如下使用它。
So we can use this, for instance, as follows.
假设我想让用户在命令提示符下键入自己的名称。
Suppose that I want to let the user type their own name at the command prompt.
我不想使用get_string。
I don't want to use get_string.
我不想稍后再提示该人的名字。
I don't want to have to prompt the human later for their name.
我希望他们能够运行我的程序并一次给我他们的名字，
I want them to be able to run my program and give me their name all at once,
就像make一样，就像rm和Clang以及我们看到的其他程序一样。
just like make, just like rm, and Clang, and other programs we've seen.
因此，我将执行此操作-如果argc == 2--
So I'm going to do this-- if argc == 2--
因此，如果我程序的参数个数是2-
so if the number of arguments to my program is 2--
继续并打印出“ hello，％s”，然后插入任何argv [1]。
go ahead and print out, "hello, %s", and plug in whatever is that argv[1].
稍后，将对此进行更多介绍。
So more on this in just a moment.
否则，如果argc不等于2，我们就使用上周的默认值，
Else, if argc is not equal to 2, let's just go with last week's default,
“你好，世界。”
"hello, world."
那么这个程序的目的是什么？
So what is this program's purpose in life?
如果人类在提示符下键入两个单词，
If the human types two words at the prompt,
我想说，“你好，大卫”，“你好，布莱恩”，“你好，某某”。
I want to say, "hello, David," "hello, Brian," "hello, so-and-so."
否则，如果他们没有在提示符下键入两个单词，
Otherwise, if they don't type two words at the prompt,
我只想说默认的“你好，世界”。
I'm just going to say the default "hello, world."
因此，让我编译一下，制作argv。
So let me compile this, make argv.
而且，嗯，我在这里没搞清楚-未知类型字符串，未知类型
And, hm, I didn't get it right here-- unknown type string, unknown type
细绳。
string.
好吧，我很无聊。
All right, I goofed.
如果我使用的是字符串，请回想一下，现在我需要开始使用CS50库。
If I'm using string, recall that now I need to start using the CS50 library.
再一次，我们将在接下来的几周内进一步了解为什么
And again, we'll see all the more why in the coming weeks as
我们将那些训练轮取下来。
we take those training wheels off.
但是现在我要再做一次，制作argv。
But now I'm going to do this again, make argv.
好了
There we go.
现在它可以工作了-./argv，输入“ hello world”。
Now it works-- ./argv, Enter, "hello, world."
这几乎等于我们上周所做的。
That's pretty much equivalent to what we did last week.
但是请注意，如果我输入了例如argv [1] David，请回车，它说：“你好，
But notice if I type in, for instance, argv[1] David, Enter, it says, "hello,
大卫。”
David."
如果我输入argv Brian，它会说。
If I type in argv Brian, it says that.
如果我输入Brian Yu，它会说“你好，世界”。
If I type in Brian Yu, it says "hello, world."
发生什么了？
So what's going on?
好吧，用C编写接受零个或多个命令行的程序的方式
Well, the way you write programs in C that accept zero or more command-line
参数-即程序名称后的提示符下的单词-
arguments-- that is, words at the prompt after your program's name--
你改变了我们一直以来所做的事情吗？
is you change what we have been doing all this time from void
将其放入带有方括号的argc字符串argv中。
to be this into argc string argv with square brackets.
电脑会自动为您做什么
And what the computer is going to do for you automatically
它会在argc中存储一定数量的单词吗？
is it's going to store in argc a number of the total number of words
从技术上讲，人类输入的不仅是论据
that the human typed in, not just the arguments, technically
所有的单词，包括您自己的程序的名称。
all of the words, including your own program's name.
然后它将填充此字符串数组，也就是argv，
It's then going to fill this array of strings, a.k.a. argv,
并在提示下输入了所有人类键入的字词，而不仅仅是
with all of the words the human typed at the prompt, so not just
像Brian或David这样的参数，还有程序的名称。
the arguments like Brian or David, but also the name of your program.
因此，如果人类输入了两个字，argv Brian，
So if the human typed in two total words, which they did, argv Brian,
argv David，那么我想打印出来，“你好”
argv David, then I want to print out, "hello"
然后是一个占位符，然后是argv [1]处的任何值。
followed by a placeholder and then whatever value is at argv[1].
我故意不做0。
And I'm deliberately not doing 0.
如果我的口头定义是0，
If I did 0, based on the verbal definition I just gave,
如果我重新编译该程序，我不想看到这个，。/ argv。
if I recompile this program, I don't want to see this, hello, ./argv.
因此，程序本身的名称会自动始终为您存储
So the program's own name is automatically always stored for you
在该数组的第一个位置。
at the first location in that array.
但是，如果您想获得第一个有用的信息，
But if you want the first useful piece of information,
在这里重新编译代码后，您实际上可以在[1]处对其进行访问。
you actually would, after recompiling the code here, access it at [1].
这样我们就可以在argv中看到我们实际上可以
And so in this way do we see in argv that we can actually
访问单个单词。
access individual words.
但也要注意这一点-
But notice this too--
假设我要打印出某人的所有单个字符
suppose I want to print out all of the individual characters in someone's
输入。
input.
你知道吗？
You know what?
我敢打赌我什至可以做到这一点。
I bet I could even do this.
让我继续执行此操作。
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我不仅仅打印出“ hello”，还因为我得到0，
Instead of just printing out "hello," let me do for int i get 0,
n等于argv [1]的字符串长度。
n equals the string length of argv[1].
然后在这里，我要做的是我小于n，即i ++。
And then over here, I'm going to do i is less than n, i++.
好吧，所以我要遍历所有字符
All right, so I'm going to iterate over all of the characters
在argv中的第一个实词中。
in the first real word in argv.
我该怎么办？
And what am I going to do?
好吧，让我继续打印出argv [1]处的字符
Well, let me go ahead and print out a character that's at argv[1]
但在位置我。
but at location i.
所以我刚才在图片中说
So I said a moment ago with our picture that we
可以认为一个字符串数组实际上只是一个数组数组。
could think of an array of strings as really just being an array of arrays.
因此，我可以通过进入argv [1]来理解这个词，从而在此处采用该语法
And so I can employ that syntax here by going into argv[1] to get me the word
例如“ David”或“ Brian”等，然后使用更多
like "David" or "Brian" or so forth, and then further index into it with more
方括号使我得到D，A，V，I，D等。
square brackets that get me the D, the A, the V, the I, the D, and so forth.
为了更加清晰，让我在其中放置一个换行符
And just to be super clear, let me put a new line character there
以便我们可以清楚地看到发生了什么。
just so we can see explicitly what's going on.
现在让我继续，删除这个“你好，世界”
And let me go ahead now and just delete this "hello, world"
因为我不想看到任何问候。
because I don't want to see any hellos.
我只想看看人类输入的单词。
I just want to see the word the human typed in.
制作argv-糟糕，我做错了什么？
Make argv-- whoops, what did I do wrong?
哦，我不应该使用strlen，因为我没有包含string.h
Oh, I used strlen when I shouldn't have because I haven't included string.h
在顶部。
at the top.
好吧，现在，如果我重新编译此代码并重新编译make argv--
OK, now if I recompile this code and recompile make argv--
我们去了-./argv David，您将看到每行一个字符。
there we go-- ./argv David, you'll see one character per line.
如果我也用Brian的名字或任何人的名字做同样的事情
And if I do the same with Brian's name or anyone's name
并将其更改为Brian，我一次打印一个字符。
and change it to Brian, I'm printing one character at a time.
再次重申，我不确定您为什么要这么做。
So again, I'm not sure why you would want to do that.
但是在这种情况下，我的目标仅仅是不仅仅迭代
But in this case, my goal simply was to not only iterate over
第一个单词中的字符，但将其打印出来。
the characters in that first word, but print them out.
再说一次，只需在这段时间内应用两次，
So again, just by applying twice over this time this principle,
我们可以实际看到一个程序可以访问吗
can we actually see that a program has access
到每个字符串中的单个字符。
to the individual characters in each of these strings.
好吧，我们面前的最后一个解释
All right, and one last explanation before we
介绍加密货币及其应用。
introduce the crypto and application thereof.
这里的东西这里的东西-任何人都可以做
This thing here, this thing here-- does anyone
对于上周和本周为何主要的情况有任何想法，
have any idea as to why main, last week and this week,
即使它不是一般函数，似乎也返回一个int？
seems to return an int even though it's not an average function?
这不是get_positive_int函数。
It's not a get_positive_int function.
不是get_negative_int。
It's not get_negative_int.
出于某种原因，即使我们不满意，main仍会返回int
Somehow, for some reason, main keeps returning an int even though we
从未见过这种int的作用。
have never seen this int in action.
这可能是什么意思？
What might this mean?
这是我们承诺的最后一块
This is the one last piece that we promised
上周我们将最终进行解释。
last week we would eventually explain.
这可能是什么意思？
What might this mean?
这是一个艰难的过程。
And this one's a tough one.
布莱恩，我们有谁？
Brian, who do we have?
怎么样 [？贪婪，？]是吗？
How about [? Gred, ?] is it?
[？ GRED：？]通常，最后的函数返回0。
[? GRED: ?] Usually, the functions in the end have returned 0.
这意味着该功能停止。
And that means that the function stops.
0是从主函数中弹出的整数。
And the 0 is the integer that pops out of the main function.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，这很妙，如果您之前曾编程过，
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, and this one's subtle in that if you had programmed before,
赔率是-我猜你有，[？ Gred--？]您已经看到了这个用法
odds are-- and I'm guessing you have, [? Gred-- ?] you've seen this in use
前。
before.
但是，我们人类在使用Mac和PC的现实世界中-
We humans, though, in the real world of using Macs and PCs--
您实际上已经在奇怪的地方看到了数字和整数。
you've actually seen numbers, integers in weird places.
坦白说，几乎在您的计算机死机或看到错误消息时，
Frankly, almost any time your computer freezes or you see an error message,
您很可能会在错误消息中看到英语或某种口头语言。
odds are you see an English or some spoken language in the error message.
但是，您经常会看到一个数字代码。
But you very often see a numeric code.
例如，如果您遇到缩放问题，
For instance, if you're having Zoom trouble,
您经常会在Zoom程序的错误窗口中看到数字5。
you'll often see the number 5 in the error window in Zoom's program.
5仅表示您遇到网络问题。
And 5 just means you're having network issues.
因此程序员经常将整数与事物相关联
So programmers often associate integers with things
在程序中可能会出错。
that can go wrong in a program.
并作为 [？ Gred？]注释，它们使用0表示没有任何问题，
And as [? Gred ?] notes, they use 0 to connote that nothing has gone wrong,
那也一样。
that all as well.
所以让我在这里写一个最终的程序，叫做exit.c
So let me write one final program here just called exit.c
对此进行了测试。
that puts this to the test.
让我继续并在名为exit.c的文件中编写程序
Let me go ahead and write a program in a file called exit.c
这将介绍我们称之为退出状态的信息。
that's going to introduce what we're going to call an exit status.
这是一个微妙之处，因为我们的程序会变得有用
This is a subtlety that will be useful as our programs get
稍微复杂一点。
a little more complicated.
我要去这里做#includecs50.h。
I'm going to go in here and do #include cs50.h.
我将继续并#include stdio.h。
And I'm going to go ahead and #include stdio.h.
而且我要给自己更长的main版本，例如int argc，string
And I'm going to give myself the longer version of main, so int argc, string
带有方括号的argv。
argv with the square brackets.
在这里，我要说的是，如果argc不等于2，
And in here, I'm going to say, if argc does not equal 2,
呃，人类没有做我想要他们做的事，
uh-uh, the human is not doing what I want them to,
我会以某种方式对他们大喊大叫。
and I'm going to yell at them in some way.
我要说的是缺少命令行参数。
I'm going to say missing command-line arguments.
因此，我希望人类在屏幕上看到的任何类型的错误消息，
So any kind of error message that I want the human to see on the screen,
我只想用这些信息告诉他们。
I'm just going to tell them with that message.
但是我将非常巧妙地返回数字1。
But I'm going to very subtly return the number 1.
我将返回一个错误代码。
I'm going to return an error code.
而且人类不一定会看到此代码。
And the human is not necessarily going to see this code.
但是如果我们要使用图形用户界面或其他功能
But if we were to have a graphical user interface or some other feature
这个程序就是那个数字
to this program, that would be the number
他们在弹出的错误窗口中看到，
they see in the error window that pops up,
就像Zoom可能在出现问题时向您显示数字5一样。
just like Zoom might show you the number 5 if something has gone wrong.
同样，坦率地说，如果您曾经访问过某个页面，
Similarly, if you've ever visited a page, frankly,
并且网页不存在，您会看到整数404。
and the web page doesn't exist, you see the integer 404.
从技术上讲，这并不是完全相同的化身，
That's not technically the exact same incarnation of this,
但是它代表程序员使用数字表示错误。
but it is representative of programmers using numbers to represent errors.
因此，您可能已经看到了。
So that one, you probably have seen.
不过，在这里，我将继续进行操作，默认情况下，说“你好，％s”
Here, I'm going to go ahead, though, and by default, say, "hello, %s,"
就像以前一样，传入argv [1]中的所有内容。
just like before, passing in whatever's in argv[1].
程序与以前一样，但是我不会做任何这样的la脚，“你好，
So same program as before, but I'm not going to do any of this lame, "hello,
世界”，如果人类没有按我的期望输入他们的名字。
world" if the human doesn't type in their name as I expect.
相反，我要检查一下，人类
Instead, I am going to check, did the human
在命令行给我两个词？
give me two words at the command line?
如果没有，我将打印“缺少命令行参数”
If not, I'm going to print, "missing command-line argument,"
然后返回此退出代码。
and then return this exit code.
否则，如果一切正常，我将继续并显式返回0。
Otherwise, if all is well, I'm going to go ahead and return explicitly 0.
这是您我本人永远都不会看到的另一个数字，
This is another number that the human, you and I, are never going to see,
但我们可以使用它。
but we could have access to it.
坦率地说，出于课程目的，check50可以访问此文件。
And frankly, for course purposes, check50 can have access to this.
还有图形用户界面，当我们进入这些界面时，
And graphical user interfaces, when we get to those,
可以访问这些值。
can have access to these values.
所以0，如[？ Gred？]笔记也一样。
So 0, as [? Gred ?] notes, is just all as well.
但是1表示出了点问题。
But 1 would mean that something goes wrong.
因此，让我继续并退出，这是适当的，
So let me go ahead and make exit, which is kind of appropriate,
当我们在这里结束时。
as we're wrapping up here.
让我继续做./exit。
And let me go ahead and do ./exit.
显示“缺少命令行参数”。
"Missing command-line argument" is what's displayed.
如果我继续说，退出大卫，现在我看到“你好，大卫”。
If I go ahead and say, exit David, now I see "hello, David."
或退出Brian，我将看到“退出Brian”。
Or exit Brian, I'll see "exit Brian."
现在，这不是您经常需要使用的技术，
Now, this is not a technique you'll need to use often,
但是如果需要，您实际上可以看到这些返回值。
but you can actually see these return values if you want.
如果我运行出口，并且看到此错误消息，我可以很奇怪地说，
If I run exit, and I see this error message, I can very weirdly say,
echo $ ?，这是一个非常隐蔽的说法，
echo $?, which is a very admittedly cryptic way of saying,
我的退出状态是什么？
what was my exit status?
如果您按Enter键，则会看到1。
And if you hit Enter, you'll see 1.
相比之下，如果我逃离大卫，我实际上
By contrast, if I run exit of David, and I actually
看到“你好，大卫”，我回显$ ?，现在我将看到0。
see "hello, David," and I do echo $?, now I will see 0.
同样，这不是您我会经常使用的技术。
So again, this is not a technique you and I will use very frequently.
但这是程序的能力，是C的能力，
But it's a capability of a program, and it's a capability of C,
您现在可以访问的。
that you do now have access to.
因此，在编写向前发展的程序时，
And so in writing programs moving forward,
我们在实验室，问题集等中经常要做的事情
what we will often do in labs and in problem sets and the like
要求您从主站返回0或1或2或3或4
is ask you to return from main either 0 or 1 or maybe 2 or 3 or 4
根据程序中可能出问题的问题
based on the problems that might have gone wrong in your program
您已经检测到并做出了适当的回应。
that you have detected and responded to appropriately.
因此，这是一种以标准方式处理错误的非常有效的方法
So it's a very effective way of handling errors in a standard way
以便您知道自己正在主动发现错误。
so that you know that you are being proactive about detecting mistakes.
那么，本周我们可能会处理哪些类型的错误？
So what kinds of mistakes might we handle this week?
我们可以解决哪些问题？
And what kinds of problems might we solve?
好吧，今天完全是关于解构字符串是什么。
Well, today was entirely about deconstructing what a string is.
上周，这只是一段文本，一段文本。
Last week, it was just a sequence of text, a chunk of text.
今天，它现在是字符数组。
Today, it's now an array of characters.
而且我们在C语言中提供了用于访问这些字符的新语法。
And we have new syntax in C for accessing those characters.
今天，我们还可以访问更多的库，更多的头文件，
We also today have access to more libraries, more header files,
因此，文档，以便我们可以实际解决问题
the documentation, therefore, so that we can actually solve problems
无需自己编写太多代码。
without writing as much code ourselves.
我们可以以这些库的形式使用其他人的代码。
We can use other people's code in the form of these libraries.
因此，我们将通过问题集2解决下个星期的一个问题
So one problem we will solve this coming week by way of problems set 2
是可读性。
is that of readability.
例如，当您阅读书籍，论文，论文或其他任何内容时，
Like, when you're reading a book or an essay or a paper or anything,
是什么使它像三年级的阅读
what is it that makes it like a 3rd-grade reading
或12年级的阅读水平或大学的阅读水平？
level or a 12th-grade reading level or university reading level?
好吧，我们所有人都可能具有直觉，对吗？
Well, all of us probably have an intuitive sense, right?
例如，如果它是大字体和短词，则可能是针对年幼的孩子的。
Like, if it's big font and short words, it's probably for younger kids.
如果真的是很复杂的单词，而且词汇量很大
And if it's really complicated words with big vocabulary and things
我们不知道，也许这是针对大学观众的。
we don't know, maybe it's meant for university audiences.
但是我们可以更加公式化地量化这一点，
But we can quantify this a little more formulaically,
不一定是唯一的方法，但是我们会给您一些定义。
not necessarily the only way, but we'll give you a few definitions.
例如，这是一个著名的句子
So for instance, here's a famous sentence--
“女贞路四号先生和达斯利夫人，
"Mr. And Mrs. Dursley, of number four, Privet Drive,
我们很自豪地说他们很正常，非常感谢，”
we're proud to say that they were perfectly normal, thank you very much,"
等等。
and so forth.
好吧，这本书的内容是什么，使哈利·波特升入了七年级
Well, what is it about this text that puts Harry Potter at grade seven
阅读水平？
reading level?
好吧，这可能与词汇单词有关。
Well, it probably has to do with the vocabulary words.
但这可能与句子的长度，数量有关
But it probably has to do with the lengths of the sentences, the amount
标点符号，也许是您可能要计算的字符总数。
of punctuation perhaps, the total number of characters that you might count up.
您可以想象仅基于外观对其进行量化
You can imagine quantifying it just based generically on the look
以及文字的美感。
and the aesthetics of the text.
那这个呢？
What about this?
“在计算语言学中，作者身份归属
"In computational linguistics, authorship attribution
是预测作者身份不明的文档的作者的任务。
is the task of predicting the author of document of unknown authorship.
通常通过分析测音特征来执行此任务-
This task is generally performed by the analysis of stylometric features--
特别”-这是Brian的高级论文。
particular"-- this is Brian's senior thesis.
因此，这不是七年级的阅读水平。
So this is not a seventh-grade reading level.
这实际上被评为16年级。
This was actually rated at grade 16.
因此，在撰写论文时，布莱恩相当精明。
So Brian's pretty sophisticated when it comes to writing theses.
但是在那儿，您也许也可以从老练中汲取灵感
But there too, you could perhaps glean from the sophistication
句子，句子的长度和其中的单词-
of the sentences, the length thereof, and the words therein--
我们也许可以量化一些东西以应用数字。
there's something we could perhaps quantify so as to apply numbers.
实际上，这是评估文本可读性的一种方式
And indeed, that's one way you could assess the readability of a text
即使您无权访问与之相关的字典
even if you don't have access to a dictionary with which
找出哪些是实际的大字或小字。
to figure out which are the actual big or small words.
密码学又如何呢？
And what about cryptography?
所以这几天真是太普遍了，所以很重要
So it's incredibly common these days and so important
这些天，您和我都使用加密技术，而不必使用
these days for you and I to use cryptography, not necessarily using
我们自己想出的算法，而是使用
algorithms we ourselves come up with, but rather using
WhatsApp，Signal and Telegram和Messenger等软件，
software, like WhatsApp and Signal and Telegram and Messenger and others,
支持您与第三方，朋友或家人之间的加密，
that support encryption between you and the third party or friend or family,
或至少是与您互动的网站。
or at least minimally the website with which you're interacting.
因此，密码学是加扰信息或隐藏信息的艺术。
So cryptography is the art of scrambling information, or hiding information.
坦率地说，如果是文字信息，那么从CS50的第三周开始，
And if that information is text, well, frankly, as of this third week of CS50,
我们已经有了必要的构件，不仅可以代表文本，
we already have the requisite building blocks for not only representing text,
但是我们今天看到了它。
but we saw today manipulating it.
即使只是大写字符也可以使我们开始对文本进行变异。
Even just uppercasing characters allows us to start mutating text.
那么，加密信息意味着什么？
Well, what does it mean to encrypt information?
好吧，就像上周我们的黑匣子一样。
Well, it's like our black box from last week.
您有一些意见。
You have some input.
您需要一些输出。
You want some output.
输入之后，我们将开始调用纯文本。
The input, we're going to start calling plaintext.
您要从自己发送给其他人的消息。
The message, you want to send from yourself to someone else.
密文是所需的输出。
Ciphertext is the output that you want.
因此，在这两者之间
And so in between there, there's going to be
我们将其称为密码。
what we're going to call a cipher.
密码是一种加密或加扰的算法
A cipher is an algorithm that encrypts or scrambles
它的输入，以便产生第三方无法理解的输出。
its input so as to produce output that a third party can't understand.
希望该密码，该算法，
And hopefully, that cipher, that algorithm,
是一个可逆的过程，因此当您收到加扰的密文时，
is a reversible process so that when you receive the scrambled ciphertext,
您可以弄清楚此人发送给您的邮件是什么。
you can figure out what it was that the person sent to you.
但是双关语意是使用加密技术的关键-
But the key to using cryptography-- pun intended--
也要有一个秘密钥匙。
is to also have a secret key.
所以，如果您回想小学，也许您
So if you think back to grade school, maybe you
在和一个班上的某人调情，而你发给他们
were flirting with someone in class, and you sent them
在一张纸上的笔记。
a note on a piece of paper.
好吧，希望你不只是在纸上说，例如，我爱你
Well, hopefully, you didn't just say, like, I love you, on the piece of paper
然后将其传递给您所有的朋友，
and then pass it through all of your friends,
或者更不用说老师了，最终的接受者。
or let alone the teacher, to the ultimate recipient.
也许您做了类似的事情，A变成了
Maybe you did something like, an A becomes
B. AB变成C. AC变成D.像，
a B. A B becomes a C. A C becomes a D. Like,
您有点应用一种算法将所有字母加1
you kind of apply an algorithm to add 1 to all of the letters
这样，如果老师确实拦截并看着它，
so that if the teacher does intercept it and look at it,
他们可能在世界上没有足够的心态去弄清楚这是什么。
they probably don't have enough care in the world to figure out what this is.
这看起来像是胡说八道。
It's just going to look like nonsense.
但是如果您的朋友知道您将A更改为B，则B
But if your friend knows that you changed A to B, B
在C上加上每个字母1，他们可以逆转该过程
to C by adding 1 to every letter, they could reverse that process
并解密。
and decrypt it.
因此，例如，该密钥实际上可能是数字1。
So the key, for instance, might be literally the number 1.
该消息的字面意思可能是“我爱你”。
The message literally might be, "I LOVE YOU."
但是密文是什么，或者是输出？
But what would the ciphertext be, or the output?
好吧，让我们考虑一下“ I LOVE YOU”是一个字符串，从今天开始，
Well, let's consider "I LOVE YOU" is a string which, as of today,
是一个字符数组。
is an array of characters.
那有什么用呢？
So what use is that?
好吧，让我们仔细考虑一下该短语，就好像它是一个数组一样。
Well, let's consider exactly that phrase as though it's an array.
它是一个字符数组。
It's an array of characters.
从上周我们知道，字符只是整数，十进制整数，
We know from last week, characters are just integers, decimal integers,
多亏了ASCII，以及Unicode。
thanks to ASCII, and in turn, Unicode.
事实证明，我已经是73岁了。
So it turns out I, we already know, is 73.
如果我们在图表上查找所有其他图表，则L为76、79、86、69、89、79、85。
And if we looked up all the others on a chart, L is 76, 79, 86, 69, 89, 79, 85.
这样我们就可以相对轻松地看到-您可能必须检查一下笔记
So we could relatively easily and see-- you might have to check your notes
并检查我的示例代码，依此类推-
and check my sample code and so forth--
但在C中相对容易地将“ I LOVE YOU”转换为相应的整数
but relatively easily in C convert "I LOVE YOU" to the corresponding integers
通过仅将字符转换为整数就可以了。
by just casting, so to speak, chars to integers.
我可以很容易地在数学上使用C语言中的plus运算符，
I could very easily mathematically, using the plus operator in C,
开始向这些字符中的每个字符加1，
start to add 1 to every one of these characters,
从而加密我的信息。
thereby encrypting my message.
但是我可以把这些号码发给我的朋友。
But I could send my friend these numbers.
但我也可以使它更加人性化
But I might as well make it a little more user friendly
并将其从整数转换回char。
and cast it back from integers to chars.
因此，现在看来，如果我使用1的密钥，则“ I LOVE YOU”的密文-
So now it would seem that the ciphertext for "I LOVE YOU," if using a key of 1--
而1只是意味着将A更改为B，而不是将A更改为C，只需将其移动一个位置-
and 1 just means change A to B, not A to C, just move it by one place--
这是“我爱你”的加密消息的密文。
this is the ciphertext for an encrypted message of, "I LOVE YOU."
因此整个过程变为1就是输入作为键。
And so the whole process becomes 1 is the input as the key.
输入的内容为“ I LOVE YOU”（纯文字）。
"I LOVE YOU" is the input as the plaintext.
输出最终就是这个不可发音的短语
And the output ultimately is this unpronounceable phrase
再说一次，如果老师或一些朋友拦截，
that, again, if the teacher or some friend intercepts,
他们可能不知道发生了什么。
they probably don't know what's going on.
确实，这是密码学的本质。
And indeed, this is the essence of cryptography.
保护我们的电子邮件，文本和财务信息的算法
The algorithms that protect our emails and texts and financial information
和健康信息有望更多
and health information is hopefully way more
比该特定算法更复杂。
sophisticated than that particular algorithm as it is.
但这归结为相同的过程-
But it reduces to the same process--
一个输入键和一个输入文本，后跟一些输出，
an input key and an input text followed by some output,
所谓的密文。
the so-called ciphertext.
数十年来，这种形式一直伴随着我们，有时甚至
And this has been with us for decades now in some form, sometimes even
机械形式。
mechanical form.
过去，您实际上可以得到这些小的圆形装置
Back in the day, you could actually get these little circular devices
在一侧的字母上有字母的字母，在其他字母上
that have letters on the alphabet on one side, other letters
在另一边的字母上。
on the alphabet on the other side.
如果您旋转一个或另一个，A可能会排成一行
And if you rotate one or the other, A might line up
与B，B可能会与C对齐。
with B, B might line up with C.
因此，您甚至可以拥有加密的物理化身，
So you can have even a physical incarnation of cryptography,
就像在电视上无休止地播放电影一样，
just as was popular in a movie that seems to play endlessly on TV,
至少在圣诞节期间在美国这里。
at least here in the US around Christmas time.
而且您可能会认识到，如果您看过《圣诞节故事》就是这样一个样子。
And you might recognize if you've seen A Christmas Story one such look.
所以我们只用了几分钟的最后一刻
So we'll use just a couple of minutes of our final moments
一起来看一下这种加密技术的真实世界
together to take a look at this real-world incarnation of cryptography
毫无疑问，您可能会在今年秋天在电视上看到它。
that undoubtedly you can probably see on TV this fall.
[视频回放]
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
-“众所周知，拉尔夫·帕克（Ralph Parker）特此登场
- "Be it known to all and sundry that Ralph Parker is hereby
任命小孤儿安妮秘密圈子的成员
appointed a member of the Little Orphan Annie secret circle
并有权享有由此产生的所有荣誉和利益。”
and is entitled to all the honors and benefits occurring thereto."
-《小孤儿安妮签名》。
- "Signed, Little Orphan Annie."
墨水中的“皮埃尔·安德烈（Countersigned）”
"Countersigned, Pierre Andre," in ink.
荣誉和福利已经九岁了。
Honors and benefits already at the age of nine.
[无线电聊天]
[RADIO CHATTER]
-（广播）注意！
- (ON RADIO) Attention!
[听不清]落水！
[INAUDIBLE] overboard!
[更改中]
[CLANGING]
-（广播）来[听不清]落水了！
- (ON RADIO) Come [INAUDIBLE] Gone overboard!
-（在收音机上）[听不清]
- (ON RADIO) [INAUDIBLE]
-来吧，让我们继续吧。
- Come on, let's get on with it.
我不需要关于走私者和海盗的爵士乐。
I don't need all that jazz about smugglers and pirates.
[叫声]
[BARKING]
-（广播）明天晚上听结局冒险
- (ON RADIO) Listen tomorrow night for the concluding adventure
黑色海盗船。
of the Black Pirate Ship.
现在是时候向您的秘密圈子成员发送安妮的秘密消息了。
Now it's time for Annie's secret message for you members of the secret circle.
记住孩子，只有任何秘密圈子的成员
Remember kids, only members of any secret circle
可以解码任何秘密消息。
can decode any secret message.
记住，安妮取决于你。
Remember, Annie is depending on you.
将引脚设置为B-2。
Set your pins to B-2.
这是消息。
Here is the message.
12、11、2、8-
12, 11, 2, 8--
-我正在第一次秘密聚会。
- I am in my first secret meeting.
-（广播）--25、14、11、18、16、23--
- (ON RADIO) --25, 14, 11, 18, 16, 23--
-今晚老皮埃尔大声疾呼。
- Old Pierre was in great voice tonight.
-（收音机）--12，23--
- (ON RADIO) --12, 23--
-我可以说今晚的信息非常重要
- I could tell that tonight's message was really important
-（广播）--21，3，25。
- (ON RADIO) --21, 3, 25.
那是安妮本人的信息。
That's a message from Annie herself.
记住，不要告诉任何人。
Remember, don't tell anyone.
[脚步声和气喘吁吁]
[FOOTSTEPS AND PANTING]
-90秒后，我在房子里唯一一个有9个男孩的房间里
- 90 seconds later, I'm in the only room in the house where a boy of nine
可以私下里坐下并解码。
could sit in privacy and decode.
[笑声] Aha，B. [笑声]我去了下一个，E。第一个单词是“ be”。
[CHUCKLES] Aha, B. [CHUCKLES] I went to the next, E. The first word is "be."
S，现在变得更容易了。
S, it was coming easier now.
U. [笑脸] 25，是R。
U. [CHUCKLES] 25, that's R.
-噢，来吧，拉尔菲，我得走了。
- Aw, come on, Ralphie, I gotta go.
- 快点。
- Come on.
-我马上下来，妈！
- I'll be right down, Ma!
-哎呀
- Gee whiz.
-T，O。“一定要。”
- T, O. "Be sure to."
确定要做什么？
Be sure to what?
小孤儿安妮想说什么？
What was Little Orphan Annie trying to say?
确定要做什么？
Be sure to what?
-Ralphie，Randy得走了。
- Ralphie, Randy has got to go.
你能出来吗？
Will you please come out?
-好的，妈！
- All right, Ma!
我马上出去！
I'll be right out!
-我现在越来越近了。
- I was getting closer now.
紧张局势非常糟糕。
The tension was terrible.
它以前如何？
What was it?
行星的命运可能悬而未决。
The fate of the planet may hang in the balance.
[敲门声]
[KNOCKING]
-拉尔夫！
- Ralphie!
兰迪要走了！
Randy's got to go!
-我马上就出来，大声喊出来！
- I'll be right out, for crying out loud!
-[笑声]快到了。
- [CHUCKLES] Almost there.
我的手指飞舞。
My fingers flew.
我的心是一个钢陷阱，每个毛孔都在振动。
My mind was a steel trap, every pore vibrated.
这几乎是清楚的。
It was almost clear.
是的，是的，是的，是的。
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
-“一定要喝你的椭圆形药。”
- "Be sure to drink your Ovaltine."
椭圆形的？
Ovaltine?
笨拙的广告？
A crummy commercial?
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
桦木的儿子。
Son of a bi*ch.
[结束播放]
[END PLAYBACK]
DAVID MALAN：好的，就是CS50。
DAVID MALAN: All right, that's it for CS50.
下次见。
We will see you next time.
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]